[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "_____ programming language is a dialect of S.",
        "Options": [
            "a) B",
            "b) C",
            "c) R",
            "d) K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: S was initiated in 1976⁷ as an internal statistical analysis environment—originally implemented as Fortran libraries."
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "Point out the WRONG statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Early versions of the S language contain functions for statistical modeling",
            "b) The book Programming with Data by John Chambers documents S version of the language",
            "c) In 1993 Bell Labs gave StatSci (later Insightful Corp.) an exclusive license to develop and sell the S language",
            "d) The book Programming with Data by IBM documents S version of the language"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Insightful sold its implementation of the S language under the product name S-PLUS."
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "In 2004, ________ purchased the S language from Lucent for $2 million.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Insightful",
            "b) Amazon",
            "c) IBM",
            "d) TCS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TIBCO is the current owner of the S language and is its exclusive developer."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "In 1991, R was created by Ross Ihaka and Robert Gentleman in the Department of Statistics at the University of _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) John Hopkins",
            "b) California",
            "c) Harvard",
            "d) Auckland"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In 1993 the first announcement of R was made to the public. Ross’s and Robert’s experience developing R is documented in a 1996 paper in the Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics."
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) R is a language for data analysis and graphics",
            "b) K is language for statistical modelling and graphics",
            "c) One key limitation of the S language was that it was only available in a commercial package, S-PLUS",
            "d) C is a language for data and graphics"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In 1996, a public mailing list was created (the R-help and R-devel lists) and in 1997 the R Core Group was formed, containing some people associated with S and S-PLUS."
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "Finally, in _________ R version 1.0.0 was released to the public.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2000",
            "b) 2005",
            "c) 2010",
            "d) 2012"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Source code for the entire R system is accessible to anyone who wanted to tinker with it."
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "R is technically much closer to the Scheme language than it is to the original _____ language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) B",
            "b) C",
            "c) C++",
            "d) S"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: R’s semantics, while superficially similar to S, are quite different."
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "The R-help and _____ mailing lists have been highly active for over a decade now.",
        "Options": [
            "a) R-mail",
            "b) R-devel",
            "c) R-dev",
            "d) R-del"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There is considerable activity on web sites like Stack Overflow as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "Which of the following describes R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Free",
            "b) Paid",
            "c) Available for free trial only",
            "d) Testing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A major advantage that R has over many other statistical packages and is that it’s free."
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "The copyright for the primary source code for R is held by the ______ Foundation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A",
            "b) S",
            "c) C",
            "d) R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It is published under the GNU General Public License version."
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "In which year R-Core group was formed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1993",
            "b) 1996",
            "c) 1997",
            "d) 1998"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In 1996, a public mailing list was created. In 1997, the R Core Group was formed. R is for statistical computing and graphics. It compiles and runs on any operating system. It is free software which can easy to install and configure."
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "Version of R released to the public in 2000 was_________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.0.0",
            "b) 1.0.3",
            "c) 2.0.1",
            "d) 1.1.0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In 2000 version 1.0.0 was released to the public. The other versions are released successively. R is a free software environment for statistical computing and graphics. There is no specified operating system for R."
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "R runs on the ____________ operating system.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linux",
            "b) Windows",
            "c) Ubuntu",
            "d) Any operating system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: R language runs on any standard computing platform and operating platform. So R can run in any operating system. It compiles and runs on a wide variety of UNIX platforms, Windows and MacOS."
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "The primary source code copyright for R is held by the ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) R Foundation",
            "b) S Foundation",
            "c) R and S foundation",
            "d) C Foundation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The copyright for the primary source code for R is held by the R Foundation. The S foundation could not have R primary source code. R is a free software environment for statistical computing and graphics."
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "R is published under the __________ General Public License version.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A",
            "b) B",
            "c) C",
            "d) GNU"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: R language is published under the GNU General Public License version. It includes compilers for C, C++, Objective-C and a host of other languages. The following licenses are in use for R or associated software such as packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "You can download “base” R system from _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) A",
            "b) B",
            "c) CRAN",
            "d) D"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can download from CRAN (Comprehensive R Archive Network). The Base R can be found in CRAN. The base R can be found in R studio. The base R system will be found in R studio."
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "Which of the following packages does not contain in “base” R system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) utils, graphics",
            "b) mesh, compiler",
            "c) splines, stats4",
            "d) grDevices, datasets"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mesh does not belong to the base R system. The other utils, graphics, compiler, splines, stats4, grDevices, datasets will contain Base R system. There are many other packages also in R studio which were pre-installed."
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "There are more than ________ packages on CRAN that have been developed by users and programmers around the world.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 40",
            "b) 400",
            "c) 4000",
            "d) 40000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: There are more than 4000 packages on CRAN. A package bundles together code, data, documentation, and tests, and is easy to share with others. As of January 2015, there were over 4000 packages available on the Comprehensive R Archive Network, or CRAN, the public clearing house for R packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "At higher level one “limitation” of R is that its functionality is based on __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Consumer demand",
            "b) User contributions",
            "c) User contributions and Consumer demand",
            "d) Lower level contributions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Its functionality is based on consumer demand and user contributions. It is only for the higher level. The capabilities of the R system generally reflect the interests of the R user community. However, now some of those communities have adopted R and we are seeing more code being written for those kinds of applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "Which of the following command is used to print an object “x” in R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) printf(x)",
            "b) print(x)",
            "c) printx",
            "d) print[x]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: print(x) command is used to print. Print(x) is the basic syntax for R. We can directly print the variable without print function also. The functions in R are helpful to the user to simplify the problem."
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "They primary R system is available from the ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) CRAN",
            "b) CRWO",
            "c) GNU",
            "d) CRDO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CRAN stands for Comprehensive R Archive Network."
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Key feature of R was that its syntax is very similar to S",
            "b) R runs only on Windows computing platform and operating system",
            "c) R has been reported to be running on modern tablets, phones, PDAs, and game consoles",
            "d) R functionality is divided into a number of Packages"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R runs on almost any standard computing platform and operating system."
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "R functionality is divided into a number of ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Packages",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Domains",
            "d) Classes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CRAN also hosts many add-on packages that can be used to extend the functionality of R."
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "Which Package contains most fundamental functions to run R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) root",
            "b) child",
            "c) base",
            "d) parent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: base package in R contains the most fundamental functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) One nice feature that R shares with many popular open source projects is frequent releases",
            "b) R has sophisticated graphics capabilities",
            "c) S’s base graphics system allows for very fine control over essentially every aspect of a plot or graph",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: R has maintained the original S philosophy, which is that it provides a language that is both useful for interactive work, but contains a powerful programming language for developing new tools."
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a base package for R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) util",
            "b) lang",
            "c) tools",
            "d) spatial"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The other packages contained in the “base” system include utils, stats, datasets, graphics, grDevices, grid, methods, parallel, compiler, splines, tcltk, stats4."
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "Which of the following is “Recommended” package in R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) util",
            "b) lang",
            "c) stats",
            "d) spatial"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: “Recommended” packages also include boot, class, cluster, codetools, foreign, KernSmooth, lattice, mgcv, nlme, rpart, survival, MASS, nnet, Matrix."
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "What is the output of getOption(“defaultPackages”) in R studio?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Installs a new package",
            "b) Shows default packages in R",
            "c) Error",
            "d) Nothing will print"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are base packages (which come with R automatically), and contributed packages. The base packages are maintained by a select group of volunteers called R Core. In addition to the base packages, there are over ten thousand additional contributed packages written by individuals all over the world."
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "Advanced users can write ___ code to manipulate R objects directly.",
        "Options": [
            "a) C, C++",
            "b) C++, Java",
            "c) Java, C",
            "d) Java"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For computationally-intensive tasks, C, C++ and Fortran code can be linked and called at run time."
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used for Statistical analysis in R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RStudio",
            "b) Studio",
            "c) Heck",
            "d) KStudio"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: RStudio is a web application framework for R."
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following R program?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">r<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\nr<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 1 is the output of the above code as indexing in R starts from 1. The output can be viewed in the R console. R studio has both R terminal and the R console. Each output format is implemented as a function in R. You can customize the output by passing arguments to the function as sub-values of the output field."
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "Which of the following operator is used to create integer sequences?",
        "Options": [
            "a) :",
            "b) ;",
            "c) –",
            "d) ~"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: “:” operator is used to create an integer sequence. The other operators are used for other purposes. Integer sequence is the basic operator used in R. The [ operator can be used to extract multiple elements of a vector by passing the operator an integer sequence."
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following R program?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">        y<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n \t<span class=\"kw2\">vector</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>y<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n \ty<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error in vector(y): invalid ‘mode’ argument",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: y is already vector; second line is an invalid argument. The third line will give us the output. When an R vector is printed you will notice that an index for the vector is printed in square brackets\n[] on the side."
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "In R language, a vector is defined that it can only contain objects of the ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Same class",
            "b) Different class",
            "c) Similar class",
            "d) Any class"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A vector can only contain objects of the same class. A vector cannot have contain objects of the different class. Same class objects are used mostly. The most basic type of R object is a vector. Empty vectors can be created with the vector() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "A list is represented as a vector but can contain objects of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Same class",
            "b) Different class",
            "c) Similar class",
            "d) Any class"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A list can contain objects of different class. But a vector can only contain objects of the same class. A vector cannot have contain objects of the different class. Same class objects are used mostly."
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "How can we define ‘undefined value’ in R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inf",
            "b) Sup",
            "c) Und",
            "d) NaN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: NaN is used to define the “undefined” value in the R language. Undefined values also have some value in R. Missing values are denoted by NA or NaN for q undefined mathematical operations. A NaN value is also NA but the converse is not true."
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "What is NaN called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Not a Number",
            "b) Not a Numeric",
            "c) Number and Number",
            "d) Number a Numeric"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: NaN is called Not a Number. It is the full form of NaN. Full forms can be viewed in R studio by typing help. A NaN value is also NA but the converse is not true. The value NaN represents an undefined value."
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "How can we define ‘infinity’ in R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inf",
            "b) Sup",
            "c) Und",
            "d) NaN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Inf is used to define “Infinity” in R. It is somewhat different from other programming languages. There is also a special number of Inf which represents infinity."
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>TRUE, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [1] “TRUE”\t“2”",
            "b) [1] “TRUE”\t 2",
            "c) [1] “0”\t“2”",
            "d) [1]   1        2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Here TRUE is taken as 1. Then it will give output as 1 and 2. FALSE can be taken as 0. T and F are short-hand ways to specify TRUE and FALSE."
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "10. What is the class defined by the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">y<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span><span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,”<span class=\"kw2\">t</span>”<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Character",
            "b) Numeric",
            "c) Logical",
            "d) Integer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Here 2 is changed into character. Since the y belongs to list. A list contains only characters. Combining a numeric object with a character object will create a character vector because numbers can usually be easily represented as strings."
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "1. What is the class defined in the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">    y<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span><span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>FALSE,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Character",
            "b) Numeric",
            "c) Logical",
            "d) Integer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Numeric and FALSE is executed as 0. It is somewhat different from other programming languages. Console will give a class as Numeric. A vector can only contain objects of the same class. A list is represented as a vector but can contain objects of different classes."
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "Which one of the following is not a basic datatype?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric",
            "b) Character",
            "c) Data frame",
            "d) Integer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Data frame is not the basic data type of R. Numeric, character, integer are the basic types of R. The basic data types are used many times. Data frames are used to store tabular data in R. They are an important type of object in R and are used in a variety of statistical modelling applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "How do you create an integer suppose 5 in R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5L",
            "b) 5l",
            "c) 5i",
            "d) 5d"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To create an integer L should be added to the integer. L is added to specify that it is an integer. An integer can also be created with many types. If you explicitly want an integer, you need to specify the L suffix."
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">       x<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>“a”,” b”<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n       <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">numeric</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [1]\t1 2",
            "b) [1]\tTRUE TRUE",
            "c) [1]\tNA NA (Warning message: NAs introduced by coercion)",
            "d) [1]     NAN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Characters cannot be expressed as numeric. Therefore NA’s are printed as output. NA will specify the missing elements in the list. When nonsensical coercion takes place, you will usually get a warning from R."
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "The dimension attribute is itself an integer vector of length _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is itself an integer vector of length 2. The dimension attribute in R is an integer vector. Real values larger in modulus than the largest integer are coerced to NA. Matrices are vectors with a dimension attribute. The dimension attribute is itself an integer vector of length 2 (number of rows, number of columns)."
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": "6. How could be the matrix constructed by using the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> m <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">matrix</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">nrow</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">ncol</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) row-wise",
            "b) column-wise",
            "c) any manner",
            "d) data insufficient"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If nothing is mentioned, matrix is created column-wise. If we want in row-wise then we have to specify. We have to mention “by row” to create a matrix in row wise. The filter( ) function is used to extract subsets of rows from a data frame. This function is similar to the existing subset( ) function."
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "Matrices can be created by row-binding with the help of the following function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rjoin()",
            "b) rbind()",
            "c) rowbind()",
            "d) rbinding()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: rbind() is used to create a matrix by row-binding. Row- binding is the basic function of R. R – bind is used to bind the functions in R. Matrices can be created by column-binding or row-binding with the cbind() and rbind() functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "What is the function used to test objects (returns a logical operator) if they are NA?",
        "Options": [
            "a) is.na()",
            "b) is.nan()",
            "c) as.na()",
            "d) as.nan()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: is.na() is the function used to test if they are NA. We can check NA ‘s at any stage of the code. Generally, We will remove the NA’s for the operations in R like mean etc.., is.na() is used to test objects if they are NA."
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Question": "What is the function used to test objects (returns a logical operator) if they are NaN?",
        "Options": [
            "a) as.nan()",
            "b) is.na()",
            "c) as.na()",
            "d) is.nan()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: is.nan() is used to test if they are NaN. We can check NAN‘s at any stage of the code. We will remove the NA’s for the operations in R. is.nan() is used to test for NaN."
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "What is the function to set column names for a matrix?",
        "Options": [
            "a) names()",
            "b) colnames()",
            "c) col.names()",
            "d) column name cannot be set for a matrix"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: colnames() is the function to set column names for a matrix. rownames() is the function to set row names for a matrix. But we can’t use both at a time. Column names and row names can be set separately using the colnames() and rownames() functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "The most convenient way to use R is at a graphics workstation running a ________ system.",
        "Options": [
            "a) windowing",
            "b) running",
            "c) interfacing",
            "d) matrix"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Most classical statistics and much of the latest methodology is available for use with R."
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Setting up a workstation to take full advantage of the customizable features of R is a straightforward thing",
            "b) q() is used to quit the R program",
            "c) R has an inbuilt help facility similar to the man facility of UNIX",
            "d) Windows versions of R have other optional help systems also"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: help command is used for knowing details of particular command in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "Which of the following is default prompt for UNIX environment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) >",
            "b) >>",
            "c) <",
            "d) <<"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When you use the R program it issues a prompt when it expects input commands."
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "Which of the following will start the R program?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $ R",
            "b) > R",
            "c) * R",
            "d) @ R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: At this point R commands may be issued."
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Windows versions of R have other optional help system also",
            "b) The help.search command (alternatively ??) allows searching for help in various ways",
            "c) R is case insensitive as are most UNIX based packages, so A and a are different symbols and would refer to different variables",
            "d) $ R is used to start the R program"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: R is an expression language with a very simple syntax."
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Options": [
            "a) help(solve)",
            "b) print(solve)",
            "c) bind(solve)",
            "d) matrix(solve)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: help is used to get more information on any specific named function."
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "Elementary commands in R consist of either _______ or assignments.",
        "Options": [
            "a) utilstats",
            "b) language",
            "c) expressions",
            "d) packages"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  If an expression is given as a command, it is evaluated, printed (unless specifically made invisible), and the value is lost."
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "If a command is not complete at the end of a line, R will give a different prompt, by default it is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) *",
            "b) –",
            "c) +",
            "d) /"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Comments can be put almost anywhere, starting with a hashmark (‘#’), everything to the end of the line is a comment."
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "Command lines entered at the console are limited to about ________ bytes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3000",
            "b) 4095",
            "c) 5000",
            "d) 6000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Elementary commands can be grouped together into one compound expression by braces (‘{’ and ‘}’)."
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "10._____ text editor provides more general support mechanisms via ESS for working interactively with R.",
        "Options": [
            "a) EAC",
            "b) Emacs",
            "c) Shell",
            "d) ECAP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The recall and editing capabilities under UNIX are highly customizable."
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "What is output of getOption(“defaultPackages”) in R studio?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Installs a new package",
            "b) Shows default packages in R",
            "c) Error",
            "d) Nothing will print"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are base packages (which come with R automatically), and contributed packages. The base packages are maintained by a select group of volunteers, called R Core. In addition to the base packages, there are over ten thousand additional contributed packages written by individuals all over the world. "
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">    x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">7</span>, NA, <span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span>, NA, <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    x <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> y</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Symbol",
            "b) Missing Data",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 15.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Missing data are a persistent and prevalent problem in many statistical analyses, especially those associated with the social sciences. R reserves the special symbol NA to represent missing data. Ordinary arithmetic with NA value gives NA’s (addition, subtraction, etc.) and applying a function to a vector that has a NA in it will usually give a NA."
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "R language is a dialect of which of the following languages?",
        "Options": [
            "a) S",
            "b) C",
            "c) MATLAB",
            "d) SAS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The R language is a dialect of S which was designed in the 1980s. Since the early 90’s the life of the S language has gone down a rather winding path. The scoping rules for R are the main feature that makes it different from the original S language."
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "R language has superficial similarity with _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) Python",
            "c) MATLAB",
            "d) SAS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The language syntax has a superficial similarity with C, but the semantics are of the FPL (functional programming language) variety with stronger affinities with Lisp and APL. There are many syntaxes in C, which are closely resembled with R."
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "5. What is the mode of ‘a’ in the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">     a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,” a”, FALSE<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric",
            "b) Character",
            "c) Integer",
            "d) Logical"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: All three elements can be expressed as a character. Both paste() and cat() will printout text to the console by combining multiple character vectors together. The original data are formatted as character strings so we convert them to R’s Date format for easier manipulation."
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "6. What is the length of b?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">b <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">7</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 6",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Length of b [1] 2 3 4 5 6 7 is 6. We can also create an empty list of a prespecified length with the vector() function. Data frames are represented as a special type of list where every element of the list has to have the same length."
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "7. What is the mode of b in the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">     b <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>TRUE, TRUE, <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric",
            "b) Character",
            "c) Integer",
            "d) Logical"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: All the elements in ‘b’ can be expressed in numeric. Both paste() and cat() will printout text to the console by combining multiple character vectors together. The original data are formatted as character strings so we convert them to R’s Data format for easier manipulation."
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "8. What are the typeof(x) and mode(x) in the following R syntax?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">     x<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric, Integer",
            "b) Integer, Numeric",
            "c) Integer, Integer",
            "d) Numeric, Numeric"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Here typeof() tells about the data type. They are an important type of object in R and are used in a variety of statistical modelling applications. You can determine an object’s type with the typeof function."
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "How many atomic vector types does R have?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R language has 6 atomic data types. They are logical, integer, real, complex, string (or character) and raw. There is also a class for “raw” objects, but they are not commonly used directly in data analysis."
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "What is the function to set row names for a data frame?",
        "Options": [
            "a) row.names()",
            "b) colnames()",
            "c) col.names()",
            "d) column name cannot be set for a data frame"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: row.names() is the function to set row names for a data frame. Data frames have a special attribute called row.names, which indicate information about each row of the data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "A single element of a character vector is referred as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Character string",
            "b) String",
            "c) Data strings",
            "d) Raw data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Single element of a character vector is often referred to as a character string. Dates are represented by the Date class and can be coerced from a character string using the as.Date() function. This is a common way to end up with a Date object in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "R files has an extension ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) .R",
            "b) .S",
            "c) .Rp",
            "d) .c"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: All R files have an extension .R.  R provides a mechanism for recalling and re-executing previous commands. All S programmed files will have an extension .S. But R has many functions than S."
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "If the code is stored in the external file, which of the following function is used to call them to a working directory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) exec()",
            "b) source()",
            "c) execute()",
            "d) sourcefile()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: source is available in the file menu. Today R runs on almost any standard computing platform and operating system. Its open source nature. The copyright for the primary source code for R is held by the R Foundation and is published under the GNU General Public License version."
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "Advanced programmers can write ______ code to manipulate R objects.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Python",
            "b) Java",
            "c) C",
            "d) Java Script"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: C, C++ and Fortran can be linked. There are a number of people had used something like C/C++ programming languages to manipulate the R objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "In ________ Insightful purchased the S language from Lucent for $2 million.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2002",
            "b) 2003",
            "c) 2004",
            "d) 2005"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: TIBCO is the current owner of the S language. In 2008, Insightful was acquired by TIBCO for $25 million. As of this writing, TIBCO is the current owner of the S language and is its exclusive developer."
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "Functionality of R is divided into a number of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Functions",
            "b) Domains",
            "c) Packages",
            "d) Files"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CRAN hosts many add-on packages that can extend the functionality of R. Connections allow R functions to talk to all different external objects without having to write custom code for each object."
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "Dataframes can be converted into a matrix by calling the following function data ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) matr()",
            "b) matrix()",
            "c) matrixf()",
            "d) matrixfunc()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: as.matrix function should be used to coerce a data frame to a matrix. It might seem that the as.matrix() function should be used to coerce a data frame to a matrix."
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">       x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>“a”, “b”<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n       <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">logical</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a  b",
            "b) “a”  “b”",
            "c) 1   1",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It is not possible to coerce, so you will get a Warning. Logical creates a logical vector of the specified length. Each element of the vector is equal to FALSE. as.logical attempts to coerce its argument to be of a logical type."
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">      a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>“a” , “b”<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n      <span class=\"kw2\">mode</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Character",
            "b) Numeric",
            "c) Complex",
            "d) Integer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mode of the given command is a character. There are a complementary function writeLines() that takes a character vector and writes each element of the vector one line at a time to a text file."
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an object of R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) calls",
            "b) expressions",
            "c) strings",
            "d) names"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Calls, expressions and names are the three types of objects that constitute the R language. There is really only one rule about vectors in R, which is that A vector can only contain objects of the same class. R objects can have names, which is very useful for writing readable code and self-describing objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": "Is It possible to inspect the source code of R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Can’t say",
            "d) Some times"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Anybody is free to download and install these packages and even inspect the source code. The instructions for obtaining R largely depend on the user’s hardware and operating system."
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "How to install for a package and all of the other packages on which for depends?",
        "Options": [
            "a) install.packages (for, depends = TRUE)",
            "b) R.install.packages (“for”, depends = TRUE)",
            "c) install.packages (“for”, depends = TRUE)",
            "d) install (“for”, depends = FALSE)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To install a package named for, open up R and type install.packages(“for”). To install foo and additionally install all of the other packages on which for depends, instead type install.packages (“for”, depends = TRUE)."
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "__________ function is used to watch for all available packages in library.",
        "Options": [
            "a) lib()",
            "b) fun.lib()",
            "c) libr()",
            "d) library()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Type library() at the command prompt to see a list of all available packages in the library. For total information about the installation of R and add-on packages, see the R Installation and Administration manual."
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "The longer programs are called ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Files",
            "b) Structures",
            "c) Scripts",
            "d) Data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The longer programs called scripts, there is too much code to write all at once at the command prompt. Furthermore, for longer scripts, it is convenient to be able to only modify a certain piece of the script and run it again in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "Scripts will run on ___________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Script Editors",
            "b) Console",
            "c) Terminal",
            "d) GCC Compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: script editors are designed to aid the communication and code writing process. They have all sorts of features including R syntax highlighting, automatic code completion, delimiter matching, and dynamic help on the R functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a “Recommended” package in R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Util",
            "b) Lang",
            "c) Stats",
            "d) Spatial"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: “Recommended” packages also include boot, class, cluster, codetools, foreign, KernSmooth, lattice, mgcv, nlme, rpart, survival, MASS, nnet, Matrix. There are about ten thousand packages in R now."
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "Full Form of GUI is ___________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Guided User Interface",
            "b) Graphical User Interface",
            "c) Guided Used Interface",
            "d) Graphical User Interval"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: GUI elements are usually accessed through a device. All programs running a GUI use a consistent set of graphical elements so that once the user learns a particular interface."
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "____________ provides a point-and-click interface to many basic statistic problems.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Commander",
            "b) GUI",
            "c) Console",
            "d) Terminal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: R Commander provides a point-and-click interface to statistical problems. It is called the “Commander” because every time one makes a selection, the code corresponding to the task is listed in the output window."
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw2\">options</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>digits <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">16</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">/</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.33",
            "b) 3.333",
            "c) 3.3333333",
            "d) 3.3333333333333333"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We know that 20/6 is a repeating decimal, We can change the number of digits displayed with options. This will make the number after the decimal point to extend for the required amount."
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "In which IDE we can interact with R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) R studio",
            "b) Console",
            "c) GCC",
            "d) Power shell"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An IDE tailored to the needs of interactive data analysis and statistical programming called R studio. In R studio we can directly interact with R through the inbuilt functions and packages. We can also download new packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "Which programming language is more based on the results?",
        "Options": [
            "a) R",
            "b) C",
            "c) C++",
            "d) Java"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Compared to other programming languages, the R community tends to be more focussed on results instead of processes. Knowledge of software engineering best practice."
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "Why learning R becomes tough?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Special files",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Packages",
            "d) Special Cases"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: You are confronted with over 20 years of evolution every time you use R. Learning R can be hard because there are many special cases in R to remember. R is the best user of memory."
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "R is mostly used in ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem solving",
            "b) Statistics",
            "c) Probability",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Statistics for relatively advanced users. R has thousands of packages, designed, maintained, and widely used by statisticians. We can code ourselves if a command is not present."
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "Why is it needed for R studio to update regularly?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bugs",
            "b) More Functions",
            "c) Methods",
            "d) For more packages"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: RStudio is very popular with a nice interface and well thought out, especially for more advanced usage. It can be a bit buggy, so make sure you update it regularly. Available on all platforms."
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “<-“?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Functions",
            "b) Loops",
            "c) Addition",
            "d) Assignment"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The expression a <- 16 creates a variable called a and gives it the value 16 called assignment. The variable on the left is assigned to the value on the right. The left side should have only a single one."
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "In the expression x <- 4 in R, what is the class of  ‘x’ as determined by the `class()’ function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Character",
            "b) Numeric",
            "c) Integer",
            "d) Word"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In R, there is an extension of the numeric or character vectors. They are not a separate type of object but simply an atomic vector with dimensions."
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "Which language is best for the statistical environment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) R",
            "c) Java",
            "d) Python"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R is a popular programming language and environment for statistical computing, graphics and also predictive analysis. Dundas BI integrates with an existing R system at the data cube level via many transforms which you can use to perform data generation or data processing."
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "In order to use the R-related functionality in Dundas BI, you must have access to an existing _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Console",
            "b) Terminal",
            "c) Packages",
            "d) R server"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In order to use the R-related functionality in Dundas BI, we must have access to an existing R server. There are configuration settings in Dundas BI that allow administrators to specify the details for connecting to the external R server."
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "The open source _________ software is available for Unix, Linux, and Windows platforms.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rserve",
            "b) BServe",
            "c) CServe",
            "d) Dserve"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The open source Rserve (Binary R Server) software is available for Unix, Linux, and Windows platforms. However, due to limitations with the Windows version, it is not recommended for use outside of evaluation purposes."
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "Modification in Dundas BI is done ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Directly",
            "b) Indirectly",
            "c) Need access to Server",
            "d) Not known"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We can view or modify configuration settings in Dundas BI through an administration screen, so there’s no need to access the Dundas BI server directly."
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "R has many functions regarding ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Statistics, Biotechnology",
            "b) Probability, Microbiology",
            "c) Distributions, Physics",
            "d) Statistics, Probability, Distributions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: R has many functions for all types of mathematical objects. For example, Statistics, Probability, Distributions like Multivariate, Continuous, Simple, Discrete etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "___________ hosts many add-on packages that can be used to extend the functionality of R.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CRAN",
            "b) GNU",
            "c) R studio",
            "d) 450"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The primary R system is available from the Comprehensive R Archive Network, also known as CRAN. CRAN also hosts many add-on packages that can be used to extend the functionality of R."
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "Which function is used to automatically vectorize?",
        "Options": [
            "a) lapply()",
            "b) kapply()",
            "c) mapply()",
            "d) happly()"
        ],
        "Answer": "answer: c\nExplanation: The mapply() function can be used to automatically “vectorize” a function. What this means is that it can be used to take a function that typically only takes single arguments and create a new function that can take vector arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "Which is simpler for statistical programming?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) Java",
            "c) R",
            "d) No language"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: R (www.r-project.org) is a commonly used free Statistics software. R allows you to carry out statistical analyses in an interactive mode, as well as allowing simple programming."
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "A _______________ is a variable that holds one value at a time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scalar variable",
            "b) Duplex",
            "c) High",
            "d) Vector"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A scalar variable was a variable which holds one value at a time. It is a single component which assumes a range of number or string values. A scalar value is associated with every point in space."
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When a complete expression is entered at the prompt, it is evaluated and the result of the evaluated expression is returned."
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The grammar of the language determines whether an expression is complete or not",
            "b) The <- symbol is the assignment operator in R",
            "c) The ## character indicates a comment",
            "d) R does not support multi-line comments or comment blocks"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Unlike some other languages, R does not support multi-line comments or comment blocks."
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "Files containing R scripts ends with extension ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) .S",
            "b) .R",
            "c) .Rp",
            "d) .SP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Under many versions of UNIX and on Windows, R provides a mechanism for recalling and re-executing previous commands."
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) : operator is used to create integer sequences",
            "b) The numbers in the square brackets are part of the vector itself",
            "c) There is a difference between the actual R object and the manner in which that R object is printed to the console",
            "d) Files containing R scripts ends with extension .R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: They are merely part of the printed output."
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "If commands are stored in an external file, say commands.R in the working directory work, they may be executed at any time in an R session with the command ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) source(“commands.R”)",
            "b) exec(“commands.R”)",
            "c) execute(“commands.R”)",
            "d) exect(“command.R”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For Windows, Source is also available on the File menu."
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "_______ will divert all subsequent output from the console to an external file.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sink",
            "b) div",
            "c) exp",
            "d) exc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sink() restores it to the console once again."
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "The entities that R creates and manipulates are known as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) objects",
            "b) task",
            "c) container",
            "d) packages"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: These may be variables, arrays of numbers, character strings, functions, or more general structures built from such components."
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be used to display the names of (most of) the objects which are currently stored within R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) object()",
            "b) objects()",
            "c) list()",
            "d) class()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: During an R session, objects are created and stored by name."
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "Collection of objects currently stored in R is called as ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) package",
            "b) workspace",
            "c) list",
            "d) task"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: All objects created during an R session can be stored permanently in a file for use in future R sessions."
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "2. What is the meaning of the following R function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\nx <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">factor</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x becomes a factor",
            "b) x is a factor",
            "c) x does not exist",
            "d) x is not a vector"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: List is a special type of vector that can contain elements of different classes. Lists is a very important data type in R. Lists can be created using the list() function, which takes an arbitrary number of arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "3. What is the meaning of the following R function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span> <span class=\"kw2\">sqrt</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.414314",
            "b) 1.414214",
            "c) Error",
            "d) 14.1414"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Factors are used to represent categorical data and can unordered and ordered. One can think of a factor as an integer vector where each integer has a label. Factors are important in statistical modelling and are treated specially by modelling functions like lm() and glm()."
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">d <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">date</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\nd</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prints todays date",
            "b) Prints some date",
            "c) Prints exact present time and date",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Functions are often used to encapsulate a sequence of expressions that need to be executed numerous times, perhaps under slightly different conditions. Functions are also often written when code must be shared with others."
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following R function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw2\">paste</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Everybody\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"is\"</span>, “a” , <span class=\"st0\">\"warrior\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “Everybody”, “is”, “a” , “warrior”",
            "b) Everybody is a warrior",
            "c) Everybody”, “is”, “a” , “warrior",
            "d) “Everybody is a warrior”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Dates are represented by the Date class and can be coerced from a character string using the as.Date() function. This is a common way to end in R with a Date. There are other alternatives to print date too."
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw2\">cat</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Everybody\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"is\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, “warrior”,sep<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"st0\">\"*\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “Everybody”, “is”, “a” , “warrior”",
            "b) Everybody*is*a*warrior",
            "c) Everybody”, “is”, “a” , “warrior",
            "d) “Everybody*is*a*warrior”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both paste() and cat() print out text to the console by combining multiple character vectors together, it is impossible for those functions to know in advance how many character vectors will be passed to the function by the user."
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following R function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw2\">nchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) no. of characters",
            "b) first 5 characters",
            "c) last 5 characters",
            "d) Does not exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Both paste() and cat() print out text to the console by combining multiple character vectors together, it is impossible to those functions to know in advance how many character vectors will be passed to the function by the user."
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw2\">Sys.<span class=\"me1\">Date</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tomorrow date",
            "b) Present date",
            "c) Some date",
            "d) Yesterday date"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: nchar will print the number of characters as output. It does not print the whole characters, it just prints the number. It does not print first 5 and also last 5 characters of the input string."
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following R function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw2\">Sys.<span class=\"me1\">time</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tomorrow date and time",
            "b) Present date and time",
            "c) Some date",
            "d) Yesterday date and time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Generally, the matrix can be printed with a matrix function. But the diagonal matrix can be easily created with diag function. In the question, we have in the same way."
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "R has how many atomic classes of objects?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The most basic type of R object is a vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Empty vectors can be created with the vector() function",
            "b) A sequence is represented as a vector but can contain objects of different classes",
            "c) “raw” objects  are commonly used directly in data analysis",
            "d) The value NaN represents undefined value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A vector can only contain objects of the same class."
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "Numbers in R are generally treated as _______ precision real numbers.",
        "Options": [
            "a) single",
            "b) double",
            "c) real",
            "d) imaginary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This means that even if you see a number like “1” or “2” in R, which you might think of as integers, they are likely represented behind the scenes as numeric objects something like “1.00” or “2.00”."
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "If you explicitly want an integer, you need to specify the _____ suffix.",
        "Options": [
            "a) D",
            "b) R",
            "c) L",
            "d) K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Entering 1 in R gives you a numeric object; entering 1L explicitly gives you an integer object."
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The value NaN represents undefined value",
            "b) Number Inf represents infinity in R",
            "c) NaN can also be thought of as a missing value",
            "d) “raw” objects  are commonly used directly in data analysis"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This allows us to represent entities like 1 / 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "Attributes of an object (if any) can be accessed using the ______ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) objects()",
            "b) attrib()",
            "c) attributes()",
            "d) obj()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Not all R objects contain attributes, in which case the attributes() function returns NULL."
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "R objects can have attributes, which are like ________ for the object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) metadata",
            "b) features",
            "c) expression",
            "d) dimensions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: These metadata can be very useful in that they help to describe the object."
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be considered as object attribute?",
        "Options": [
            "a) dimensions",
            "b) class",
            "c) length",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All objects in R have an Attribute list."
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">vector</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"numeric\"</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">length</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0",
            "c) 01",
            "d) 00120"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can also use the vector() function to initialize vectors."
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "The ________ function can be used to create vectors of objects by concatenating things together.",
        "Options": [
            "a) cp()",
            "b) c()",
            "c) concat()",
            "d) con()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The simplest such structure is the numeric vector, which is a single entity consisting of an ordered collection of numbers."
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is invalid?",
        "Options": [
            "a) x <- c(1+0i, 2+4i)",
            "b) x <- c(TRUE, FALSE)",
            "c) x <- c(T, F)",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: T and F are shorthand ways to specify TRUE and FALSE."
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Use explicit TRUE and FALSE values when indicating logical values",
            "b) rm command is used to remove objects in R",
            "c) R operates on named data structures",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A number occurring by itself in an expression is taken as a vector of length one."
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">class</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “integer”",
            "b) “numeric”",
            "c) “real”",
            "d) “imaginary”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: class is used to determine data type of the variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">logical</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) FALSE TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE",
            "b) “0” “1” “2” “3” “4” “5” “6”",
            "c) 0 1 2 3 4 5 6",
            "d) 6 5 5 3 2 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sometimes, R can’t figure out how to coerce an object and this can result in NAs being produced."
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The usual operator, <-, can be thought of as a syntactic shortcut to expression operation",
            "b) Assignment can also be made using the function assignment()",
            "c) Vectors can be used in arithmetic expressions, in which case the operations are performed element by element",
            "d) seq() is used to delete the numbers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Vectors occurring in the same expression need not all be of the same length."
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">sqrt</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">17</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -4.02",
            "b) 4.02",
            "c) NaN",
            "d) 3.67"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Assignments can also be made in the other direction, using the obvious change in the assignment operator."
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "_______ function returns a vector of the same size as x with the elements arranged in increasing order.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sort()",
            "b) orderasc()",
            "c) orderby()",
            "d) sequence()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The elementary arithmetic operators are the usual +, -, *, / and ^ for raising to a power."
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used for generating sequences?",
        "Options": [
            "a) seq()",
            "b) sequence()",
            "c) order()",
            "d) orderasc()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are other more flexible sorting facilities available like order() or sort.list() which produce a permutation to do the sorting."
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Question": "1. Which of the following statement would print “0” “1” “2” “3” “4” “5” “6” for the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) as.character(x)",
            "b) as.logical(x)",
            "c) as.numeric(x)",
            "d) as.num(y)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: as.character would print number from 0 to 6."
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rep() is be used for replicating an object in various complicated ways",
            "b) seq() function has four arguments",
            "c) sequence() is a more general facility for generating sequences",
            "d) numerical vectors are generated by conditions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The simplest form is of rep representation is : > s5 >- rep(x, times=5)."
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"b\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"c\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">numeric</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Warning",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Abnormal termination",
            "d) Prints x"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: NAs is introduced by coercion."
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"b\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"c\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">logical</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a b c",
            "b) NA NA NA",
            "c) 0 1 2",
            "d) 6 8 9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When nonsensical coercion takes place, you will usually get a warning from R."
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The elements of a logical vector cannot have the values TRUE, FALSE, and NA",
            "b) Matrices are vectors with a dimension attribute",
            "c) Numerical vectors are generated by conditions",
            "d) seq() function has four arguments"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The dimension attribute is itself an integer vector of length 2 (number of rows, number of columns)."
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">matrix</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">nrow</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">ncol</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">dim</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>m<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3 2",
            "b) 2 3",
            "c) 2 2",
            "d) 4 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Matrices are constructed column-wise."
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> m</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10",
            "b) 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11",
            "c) 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10",
            "d) 10 9 8 6 5 4 2 3 1 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Matrices can also be created directly from vectors by adding a dimension attribute."
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "1. Find the following type of vector?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5.3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">6</span>,<span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric",
            "b) Character",
            "c) Integer",
            "d) Logical"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The labels are always character irrespective of whether it is numeric or character and also Boolean etc. on the input vector. The nlevels functions will give the count of levels. Factors are created using the factor() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "All columns in a matrix must have the same mode and the _________ length.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Different",
            "b) Same",
            "c) May be the same",
            "d) May be different"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: All columns in a matrix must have the same mode(numeric, character, etc) and also the same length. byrow=TRUE indicates that the matrix should be filled by rows. byrow=FALSE indicates that the matrix should be filled by columns (the default)."
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "___________ provides optional labels with the columns and rows.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Disnames",
            "b) Dimnames",
            "c) Denmes",
            "d) Demnesd"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: byrow=TRUE indicates that the matrix should be filled by rows. byrow=FALSE indicates that the matrix should be filled by columns (the default). dimnames provides optional labels with the columns and rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "________ are similar to matrices but can have more than two dimensions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Functions",
            "b) Packages",
            "c) Arrays",
            "d) Columns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Arrays are similar to matrices which can have more than two dimensions. See help(array) for details. Factors are created using the factor() function. We can Identify elements of a list using the [[]] convention."
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "Which is more general than a matrix, in that different columns can have different modes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data types",
            "b) Data frames",
            "c) Data sets",
            "d) Databases"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A data frame is more general than a matrix, in that different columns can have different modes (numeric, character, factor, etc). This is similar to SAS and SPSS datasets. There are many ways to identify the elements of a data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "An ordered collection of objects or components are called ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data frames",
            "b) Datasets",
            "c) Databases",
            "d) Lists"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An ordered collection of objects are called lists. A list allows you to gather a variety of (possibly unrelated) objects under one name. We can Identify elements of a list using the [[]] convention."
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "The ________ stores the nominal values as a vector of integers in the range of 1 to unique values in the nominal variable.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Factor",
            "b) Matrix",
            "c) Lists",
            "d) Functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The factor stores the nominal values as a vector of integers in the range [1… k] (where k is the no. of unique values of the nominal variable), and an internal vector of character strings (the original values) mapped to these integers."
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "An ordered factor is used to represent an __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ordinal variable",
            "b) Simple variable",
            "c) Coordinal variable",
            "d) Biordinal variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An ordered factor is used to represent an ordinal variable. R will treat factors as nominal variables and also ordered factors as ordinal variables in statistical procedures and graphical analyses."
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "On what basis of a variable, OS allocates memory and decides what can be stored in the reserved memory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data bases",
            "b) Data sets",
            "c) Data types",
            "d) Lists"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Based on the data type of a variable, the OS allocates the memory and decides what can be stored on the reserved memory. This means that when you create a variable you reserve some space in memory."
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "The data type of the R-object becomes the data type of the ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Functions",
            "b) Packages",
            "c) Variables",
            "d) Lists"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In R, the variables are not declared as some data type. The variables are assigned with R-Objects and the data type of the R-object will become the data type of the variable. There are many types of R-objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "Which function is used to combine the elements into a vector?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C()",
            "b) D()",
            "c) E()",
            "d) F()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When you want to create a vector with more than one element, you should use c() function which means to combine the elements into a vector. We can Identify elements of a list using the [[]] convention."
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "A __________ is an R-object which can contain many different types of elements inside it.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vector",
            "b) Lists",
            "c) Matrix",
            "d) Functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A list is an R-object which can contain many different types of elements in it like vectors, functions and even another list inside it. We can Identify elements of a list using the [[]] convention."
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "A _________ is a two-dimensional rectangular data set.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vector",
            "b) Lists",
            "c) Matrix",
            "d) Functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A matrix is a two-dimensional rectangular data set. It can be created using the vector input to a matrix function. The labels are always character irrespective of whether it is numeric or character and also Boolean etc in the vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "Which function takes a dim attribute which creates the required number of dimensions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vector",
            "b) Array",
            "c) Matrix",
            "d) Lists"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The array function takes a dim attribute which creates the required number of dimensions. While matrices are confined to two dimensions, arrays could be of any number of dimensions."
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "Factors are the r-objects which are created using a _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vector",
            "b) Matrix",
            "c) Lists",
            "d) Array"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Factors are the r-objects which are created using a vector. It stores the vector with also the distinct values of the elements in the vector as labels. They are useful in statistical modelling."
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "Factors are created using the _______ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) C()",
            "b) Function()",
            "c) Array()",
            "d) Lists()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Factors are created using the factor() function. The labels are always character irrespective of whether it is numeric or character or also Boolean etc. in the vector. The nlevels functions will give the count of levels."
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "By what function we can create data frames?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data.frames()",
            "b) Data.sets ()",
            "c) Function ()",
            "d) C ()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Data frames are tabular data objects. Unlike a matrix in each data frame every column will contain different modes of data. Data Frames are created using the data.frame() function. It is the list of vectors of same length."
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": "vectors can be one of two types namely atomic vectors and _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix",
            "b) Vector",
            "c) Lists",
            "d) Array"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A vector is the most common and basic data structure in R. Technically, vectors can be one of two types of atomic vectors and lists. Although vector most commonly refers to the atomic types."
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "Lists can be coerced with which function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) As.lists",
            "b) Has.lists",
            "c) In.lists",
            "d) Co.lists"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Lists are sometimes called generic vectors because the elements of a list can be of any type of R object, even lists containing further lists. This property makes them fundamentally different from other atomic vectors. Create lists using list() and coerce other objects using as.list()."
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "A data frame is a special type of list where every element of the list has ______ length.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Same",
            "b) Different",
            "c) May be different",
            "d) May be same"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A data frame is a very important data type in R. It’s pretty much the de facto data structure for most tabular data and what we use for statistics. A data frame was a special type of list in which every element of the list has the same length."
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Question": "Data frames can have additional attributes such as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rowname()",
            "b) Rownames()",
            "c) R.names()",
            "d) D.names()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Data frames can have additional attributes such as rownames(), which can be useful for annotating data, like subject_id or sample_id. But most of the time they are not used. A data frame is an important data type in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "Decimal values are referred as ________ data types in R.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric",
            "b) Character",
            "c) Integer",
            "d) Lists"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Decimal values are referred to as numeric data types in R. Data frames are the tabular data objects. Unlike a matrix in data frame every column can contain different modes of data."
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "Which is the basic data structure of R containing the same type of data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Functions",
            "b) Array",
            "c) Vector",
            "d) Lists"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Vector is a basic data structure in R that contains an element of similar type. These data types in R can be logical, integer, double, character, complex and also raw. In R using the function, typeof() one can check the data type of vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "In R using the function, ________ one can check the data type of vector.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Typeof()",
            "b) Castof()",
            "c) Function()",
            "d) C()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In R using the function, typeof() one can check the data type of vector. Vector is a basic data structure in R which contains element of similar type. These data types in R can be logical, integer, double, character, complex and also raw."
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "__________are Data frames which contain lists of homogeneous data in a tabular format.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix",
            "b) Vector",
            "c) Lists",
            "d) Array"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Matrices are Data frames which contain lists of homogeneous data in a tabular format. Technically, vectors can be one of two types of atomic vectors and lists. Although vector is mostly refers to the atomic types."
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "The four most frequently used types of data objects in R  are vectors, matrices, data frames and ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Function",
            "b) Lists",
            "c) Packages",
            "d) Interfaces"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The four most frequently used types of data objects in R are vectors, matrices, data frames and lists. A list is a generalisation of a vector and represents a collection of data objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "A __________ is a set of elements appearing in rows and columns where the elements are of the same mode whether they are logical, numeric (integer or double), complex or character.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vector",
            "b) Matrix",
            "c) Lists",
            "d) Data frames"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A matrix is a set of elements appearing in rows and columns where the elements are of the same mode whether they are logical, numeric (integer or double), complex or character."
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "What is the simplest way of creating the vector?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C function",
            "b) Create",
            "c) Destroy",
            "d) Invalid"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The simplest way to create a vector is through the concatenation function, c. This function binds elements together, whether they are of character form, numeric or logical."
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "Which function replicates elements of vectors?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) Rep",
            "c) Crep",
            "d) Grep"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The rep function replicates elements of vectors. The seq function creates a regular sequence of values to form a vector. The four most frequently used types of data objects in R are vectors, matrices, data frames and lists."
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "Question": "The ________ function creates a regular sequence of values to form a vector.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sequel",
            "b) Rep",
            "c) seq",
            "d) Grep"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The rep function replicates elements of vectors. The seq function creates a regular sequence of values to form a vector. The four most frequently used types of data objects in R are vectors, matrices, data frames and lists."
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "Question": "Which function is used to enter in data at the terminal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scanned",
            "b) Scnn",
            "c) Scan",
            "d) Sccn"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The scan function is used to enter data at the terminal. This is useful for small datasets but tiresome for entering in large datasets."
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "Question": "Computation with vectors is achieved using an element-by-element operation for avoiding _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Loops",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Packages",
            "d) Interfaces"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Computation with vectors is achieved using an element-by-element operation. This is useful when writing code because it avoids ’for loops’."
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "Question": "To bind a row onto an already existing matrix, the ______ function can be used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rbind",
            "b) Sbnd",
            "c) Gbind",
            "d) Sbind"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To bind a row onto an already existing matrix, the rbind function can be used. The scan function is used to enter data at the terminal."
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a 3-dimensional dataset?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Eris",
            "b) Iris",
            "c) Toris",
            "d) Iris"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The iris dataset is a three dimensional dataset. One dimension is represented for each species: Setosa, Versicolor and Virginica."
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "Question": "Which dimension corresponds to the explanatory variables collected for each species?",
        "Options": [
            "a) First",
            "b) Second",
            "c) Third",
            "d) Fifth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The second dimension corresponds to the explanatory variables collected for each species. The third dimension corresponds to the species."
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "Question": "Using the ________ vector, we create a species factor and bind it to the columns of iris.df.",
        "Options": [
            "a) snames",
            "b) rnames",
            "c) jnames",
            "d) fnames"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Using the Snames vector, we create a species factor and bind it to the columns of iris.df. The iris dataset is a three dimensional dataset."
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "Question": "Accessing elements is achieved through a process called ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Indexing",
            "b) Outdexing",
            "c) Highlighting",
            "d) Scrapping"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Accessing elements is achieved through a process called indexing. Indexing may be done by a vector of positive integers and negative integers to indicate inclusion."
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "Question": "Which are indexed by either row or column using a specific name or number?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Datasets",
            "b) Data frames",
            "c) Data",
            "d) Functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Data frames can be indexed by either row or column using a specific name (that corresponds to either the row or column) or a number."
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "Question": "What should we use to access elements with a value greater than five?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Subsetting commands",
            "b) Use functions",
            "c) Packages",
            "d) Interfaces"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To access elements with a value greater than five we can use some subsetting commands and logical operators to produce the desired result."
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "Question": "Lists can be created using the _______ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix.li",
            "b) Matrix.lists",
            "c) Lists.matric",
            "d) List"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Lists can be created using the list function. Like data frames, they can incorporate a mixture of modes into the one list and each component can be of a different length or size."
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "Question": "First component of the list can be accessed by _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Name of the component",
            "b) List name",
            "c) Function",
            "d) Package"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are a number of ways of accessing the first component of a list. We can either access it through the name of that component (if names are assigned) or by using a number corresponding to the position of the component."
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "Question": "How can we access the first component of the list?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number of the position",
            "b) Function",
            "c) Package",
            "d) Tools"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are a number of ways of accessing the first component of a list. We can either access it through the name of that component (if names are assigned) or by using a number corresponding to the position the component."
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "Question": "The first component can be accessed using __________ operator.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Intraction",
            "b) Extraction",
            "c) AND",
            "d) OR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are a number of ways of accessing the first component of a list. We can either access it through the name of that component (if names are assigned) or by using a number corresponding to the position the component corresponds to. The former approach can be performed using subsetting ([[]]) or alternatively, by the extraction operator ($)."
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "Question": "To extract a sublist, we use _________ brackets.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Flower",
            "b) Square",
            "c) Double",
            "d) Single"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To extract a sublist, we use single brackets. There are a number of ways of accessing the first component of a list.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "Question": "The length of a list is ______ to the number of components in that list.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Double",
            "b) Equal",
            "c) Triple",
            "d) One fourth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The length of a list is equal to the number of components in that list. Lists can be created using the list function. Like data frames, they can incorporate a mixture of modes into the one list and each component can be of a different length or size."
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "Question": "Which function can be used to determine the names assigned to a list?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Names",
            "b) Name",
            "c) Nam",
            "d) Nem"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To determine the names assigned to a list, the names function can be used. Lists can be created using the list function. Like data frames, they can incorporate a mixture of modes into the one list and each component can be of a different length or size."
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "Question": "Joining two lists can be achieved either using the _________ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Concat",
            "b) Join",
            "c) Reduce",
            "d) Delete"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Joining two lists can be achieved either using the concatenation function or the append function."
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "Question": "Which function gives the list as output?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Spline",
            "b) Matrix",
            "c) Vector",
            "d) Alphabet"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are also many functions within R that produce a list as output. Examples of these functions include spline(), density() and locator().Joining two lists can be achieved either using the concatenation function or the append function."
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "Question": "Density function gives output as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix",
            "b) Lists",
            "c) Vector",
            "d) Number"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are also many functions within R that produce a list as output. Examples of these functions include spline(), density() and locator()."
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "Question": "Locator function gives output as ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix",
            "b) Lists",
            "c) Vector",
            "d) Number"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To extract a sublist, we use single brackets. There are a number of ways of accessing the first component of a list. There are also many functions within R that produce a list as output. Examples of these functions include spline(), density() and locator().\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "Question": "The _________ function returns a list of densities (y) corresponding to bin values (x).",
        "Options": [
            "a) Spline",
            "b) Density",
            "c) Lists",
            "d) Locator"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The spline function returns a list of densities (y) corresponding to bin values (x). These can be passed to the plot routine to produce a line graph of the density."
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "Question": "The ________ function takes an arbitrary number of arguments and concatenates them one by one into character strings.",
        "Options": [
            "a) copy()",
            "b) paste()",
            "c) bind()",
            "d) del()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Any numbers given among the arguments are coerced into character strings in the evident way, that is, in the same way they would be if they were printed."
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Character strings are entered using either matching double (“) or single (‘) quotes",
            "b) Character vectors may be concatenated into a vector by the c() function",
            "c) Subsets of the elements of a vector may be selected by appending to the name of the vector an index vector in square brackets",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Character quantities and character vectors are used frequently in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) matrices or more generally arrays are multi-dimensional generalizations of vectors",
            "b) factors provide compact ways to handle categorical data",
            "c) vectors provide a convenient way to return the results of a statistical computation",
            "d) lists can be explicitly created using the list() function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The dimension attribute is itself an integer vector of length 2 (number of rows, number of columns)."
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">vector</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"list\"</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">length</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) NULL",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 0",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Factor objects can be created with the factor() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "Question": "Which of the following code snippet will create a vector with NAs in it?",
        "Options": [
            "a) x >- c(1, 2, NA, 10, 3)",
            "b) x >- cNA(1, 2, NA, 10, 3)",
            "c) x >- NA(1, 2, NA, 10, 3)",
            "d) x >- NA(1, 5, NA, 10, 8)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This returns a logical vector indicating which elements are NA."
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, NaN, NA, <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">is.<span class=\"me1\">na</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) FALSE FALSE TRUE TRUE FALSE",
            "b) FALSE TRUE TRUE TRUE FALSE",
            "c) TRUE FALSE TRUE TRUE FALSE",
            "d) TRUE FALSE TRUE FALSE FALSE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The order of the levels of a factor can be set using the levels argument to factor()."
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) is.nan() is used to test objects if they are NA",
            "b) is.nan() is used to test for NaN",
            "c) NA values have a class",
            "d) NA values have a class, so there are integer NA, character NA, etc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A NaN value is also NA but the converse is not true."
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "Question": "Data frames can be converted to a matrix by calling data _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) as.matr()",
            "b) as.mat()",
            "c) as.matrix()",
            "d) as.max()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: as.matrix() function should be used to coerce a data frame to a matrix."
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">data.<span class=\"me1\">frame</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>foo <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, bar <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">T</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">T</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">F</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">F</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">ncol</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 7",
            "d) 9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Data frames are used to store tabular data in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Using factors with labels is better than using integers because factors are self-describing",
            "b) Factors are used to represent categorical data and can be unordered or ordered",
            "c) Factors are important in statistical modeling and are treated specially by modelling functions like lm() and glm()",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Data frames are represented as a special type of list where every element of the list has to have the same length."
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">names</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) NULL",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 4.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Having a variable that has values “Male” and “Female” is better than a variable that has values 1 and 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement changes column name to h and f?",
        "Options": [
            "a) colnames(m) <- c(“h”, “f”)",
            "b) columnnames(m) <- c(“h”, “f”)",
            "c) rownames(m) <- c(“h”, “f”)",
            "d) rownames(m) <- c(“f”, “f”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: R objects can have names, which is very useful for writing readable code and self-describing objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used for reading tabular data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) read.csv",
            "b) dget",
            "c) readLines",
            "d) writeline"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Matrices can have both column and row names."
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used for reading in saved workspaces?",
        "Options": [
            "a) unserialize",
            "b) load",
            "c) get",
            "d) set"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: unserialize is used for reading single R objects in binary form. Load is used for reading in saved workspaces. Search by name for an object (get) or zero or more objects (mget)."
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) write.table is used for for writing tabular data to text files (i.e. CSV) or connections",
            "b) writeLines is used for for writing character data line-by-line to a file or connection",
            "c) dump is used for for dumping a textual representation of multiple R objects",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are analogous functions for writing data to files."
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "Question": "________ is used for outputting a textual representation of an R object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dput",
            "b) dump",
            "c) dget",
            "d) dset"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: dump is used for dumping a textual representation of multiple R objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "Question": "Which of the following argument denotes if the file has a header line?",
        "Options": [
            "a) header",
            "b) sep",
            "c) file",
            "d) footer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sep is a string indicating how the columns are separated."
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) unserialize is used for converting an R object into a binary format for outputting to a connection",
            "b) save is used for saving an arbitrary number of R objects in binary format to a file",
            "c) The read.data() function is one of the most commonly used functions for reading data",
            "d) save is not used for saving an arbitrary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: read.table reads a file in table format and creates a data frame from it."
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement would read file “foo.txt”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) data <- read.table(“foo.txt”)",
            "b) read.data <- read.table(“foo.txt”)",
            "c) data <- read.data(“foo.txt”)",
            "d) data <- data(“foo.txt”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: R will automatically skip lines that begin with a #."
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "Question": "Which of the following function is identical to read .table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) read.csv",
            "b) read.data",
            "c) read.tab",
            "d) read.del"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The read.csv() function is identical to read.table except that some of the defaults are set differently (like the sep argument)."
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "Question": "Which of the following code would read 100 rows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) initial <- read.table(“datatable.txt”, nrows = 100)",
            "b) tabAll <- read.table(“datatable.txt”, colClasses = classes)",
            "c) initial <- read.table(“datatable.txt”, nrows = 99)",
            "d) initial <- read.table(“datatable.txt”, nrows = 101)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can use the Unix tool wc to calculate the number of lines in a file."
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "Question": "Unlike writing out a table or CSV file, dump() and dput() preserve the ______ so that another user doesn’t have to specify the all over again.",
        "Options": [
            "a) metadata",
            "b) backup data",
            "c) attribute data",
            "d) normal data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The read.table() function is one of the most commonly used functions for reading data. The help file with read.table() is worth reading in its entirety if only because the function gets used a lot."
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "Question": "One way to pass data around is by de parsing the R object with _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) dput()",
            "b) write()",
            "c) read()",
            "d) dget()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: dput is used for outputting a textual representation of an R object. The dump() and dput() functions are useful because the resulting textual format is editable, and in the case of corruption, potentially recoverable."
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "Question": "Main way to read the data back in (parsing it) using the function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dput()",
            "b) write()",
            "c) read()",
            "d) dget()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: One way to pass data around is by deparsing the R object with dput() and reading it back in (parsing it) using dget(). dget is used for reading in R code files (inverse of dput)."
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "Question": "dput() output is in the form of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) R code",
            "b) text file code",
            "c) binary code",
            "d) both binary and text"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: dput is used for outputting a textual representation of an R object. The dump() and dput() functions are useful because the resulting textual format is editable, and in the case of corruption, potentially recoverable."
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "Question": "Multiple objects can be de parsed at once using the ______ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dput()",
            "b) write()",
            "c) dump()",
            "d) dget()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: dput is used for outputting a textual representation of an R object. The dump() and dput() functions are useful because the resulting textual format is editable, and in the case of corruption, potentially recoverable."
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "Question": "Multiple objects can be de parsed at once and read back using function _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) source()",
            "b) read()",
            "c) dget()",
            "d) dput()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Martin Machler made an important contribution by making Ross and Robert use the GNU General Public License to make R free software. This was critical because this allowed for the source code for the entire R system to be accessible to anyone who wanted to tinker with it."
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "Question": "We can dump() R objects to a file by passing _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) character vector of their names",
            "b) object name",
            "c) arguments",
            "d) file name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Dump is used for dumping a textual representation of multiple R objects. Descriptive representation of an R object by using the dput() or dump() functions. The dump() and dput() functions are useful because the resulting textual format is editable, and in the case of corruption, potentially recoverable."
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "Question": "If we want to save individual R objects to a file, we use the _______ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) save()",
            "b) save.image()",
            "c) serialize()",
            "d) deserialize()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Save is used for saving an arbitrary number of R objects with a binary format (possibly compressed) to a file. The output of dput() can also be saved directly to a file."
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "Question": "If you have a lot of objects that you want to save to a file, we use ________ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) save()",
            "b) save.image()",
            "c) serialize()",
            "d) deserialize()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Save is used for saving an arbitrary number of R objects with a binary format (possibly compressed) to a file. The output of dput() can also be saved directly to a file. Save.Image can be used mostly in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "Question": ".rda extension used when saving data with function __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) save()",
            "b) save.image()",
            "c) save and save.image functions",
            "d) serialize()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Save is used for saving an arbitrary number of R objects with a binary format (possibly compressed) to a file. The output of dput() can also be saved directly to a file. Save.Image can be used mostly in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "Question": ".RData extension used when we save data using the functions ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) save()",
            "b) save.image()",
            "c) save and save.image functions",
            "d) serialize()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Save is used for saving an arbitrary number of R objects with a binary format (possibly compressed) to a file. The output of dput() can also be saved directly to a file. Save.Image can be used mostly in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "Question": "When you call serialize() on an R object, the output will be ____ coded in hexadecimal format.",
        "Options": [
            "a) raw vector",
            "b) character vector",
            "c) integer vector",
            "d) binary vector"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When you call serialize() on an R object, the output will be raw vector coded in hexadecimal format. Serialize is used for converting an R object into a binary format for outputting to a connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "Question": "The benefit of the _____ function is that it is the only way to perfectly repressed an R object in an exportable format, without losing precision or any metadata.",
        "Options": [
            "a) save()",
            "b) save.image()",
            "c) unserialize()",
            "d) serialize()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Unserialize is used for reading single R objects in the binary form. Serialize is used for converting an R object into a binary format for outputting to a connection (or file)."
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "Question": "load() is used for _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) reading",
            "b) loading",
            "c) working",
            "d) not exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Load is used for reading in saved workspaces. After installing the package it is important that you load it into your R session with the library() function. you can load the data into R using the readRDS() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "Question": "readlines is used for ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) working on data",
            "b) reading files",
            "c) reading lines in files",
            "d) not exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ReadLines is used for reading lines of a text file. you can load the data into R using the readRDS() function. Text files can be read line by line using the readLines() function. This function is useful for reading text files that may be unstructured or contain non-standard data."
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "Question": "Individual R objects can be saved to a file using the _____ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) save",
            "b) put",
            "c) save_image",
            "d) get"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The key functions for converting R objects into a binary format are save(), save.image(), and serialize()."
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The complement to the textual format is the binary format",
            "b) If you have a lot of objects that you want to save to a file, you can save all objects in your workspace using the save.image() function",
            "c) The serialize() function is used to convert individual R objects into a binary format that can be communicated across an arbitrary connection",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It’s better to stick with a binary format for efficiency and accuracy."
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "Question": "3. Which of the following R statement will save the output to the file for following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">data.<span class=\"me1\">frame</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw7\">rnorm</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>, y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw7\">runif</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">4.4</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) save(a, b, file = “mydata.rda”)",
            "b) save_image(a, b, file = “mydata.rda”)",
            "c) keep(a, b, file = “mydata.rda”)",
            "d) keep_image(a, b, file = “mydata.rda”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can save all objects in your workspace using the save.image() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement will load the objects to the file named “mydata.RData”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) save(“mydata.RData”)",
            "b) load(“mydata.RData”)",
            "c) loadAll(“mydata.RData”)",
            "d) put(“mydata.RData”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: .rda and .RData are fairly common extensions and you may want to use them because they are recognized by other software."
    },
    {
        "id": 239,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) When you call unserialize() on an R object, the output will be a raw vector coded in hexadecimal format",
            "b) serialize() function is the only way to perfectly represent an R object in an exportable format",
            "c) .rda extension is used when save() function is incorporated",
            "d) The complement to the textual format is the binary format"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Output may get sent to a file, but it could get sent over a network or other connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 240,
        "Question": "________ opens a connection to a file compressed with gzip.",
        "Options": [
            "a) url",
            "b) gzfile",
            "c) bzfile",
            "d) file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: “file” opens a connection to a file."
    },
    {
        "id": 241,
        "Question": "Connections to text files can be created with the ________ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) url",
            "b) gzfile",
            "c) bzfile",
            "d) file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The file() function has a number of arguments that are common to many other connection functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 242,
        "Question": "Which of the following R code creates a connection to ‘foo.txt’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) con <- file(“foo.txt”)",
            "b) open(con, “r”)",
            "c) opencon(con, “r”)",
            "d) ocon(con, “r”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Open is used for opening connection to ‘foo.txt’ in read-only mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 243,
        "Question": "Which of the following code opens a connection to the file foo.txt, reads from it, and closes the connection when its done?",
        "Options": [
            "a) data <- read.csv(“foo.txt”)",
            "b) data <- read.csvo(“foo.txt”)",
            "c) data <- readonly.csv(“foo.txt”)",
            "d) data <- getonly.csv(“foo.txt”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Connections must be opened, then the are read from or written to, and then they are closed."
    },
    {
        "id": 244,
        "Question": "Which of the following opens connection to gz-compressed text file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) con <- gzfiles(“words.gz”)",
            "b) con <- gzfile(“words.gz”)",
            "c) con <- gzfile2(“words.gz”)",
            "d) con <- gzfiles2(“words.gz”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For more structured text data like CSV files or tab-delimited files, there are other functions like read.csv() or read.table()."
    },
    {
        "id": 245,
        "Question": "1. Which of the following extracts first element from the following R vector?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"b\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"c\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"c\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"d\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x[10] ",
            "b) x[1] ",
            "c) x[0] ",
            "d) x[2]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The element which we want to extract will be in the format of variable[index value of the element] in R script."
    },
    {
        "id": 246,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) There are three operators that can be used to extract subsets of R objects",
            "b) The [ operator is used to extract elements of a list or data frame by literal name",
            "c) The [[ operator is used to extract elements of a list or data frame by string name",
            "d) There are five operators that can be used to extract subsets of R objects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Three operators are [,[[ and $."
    },
    {
        "id": 247,
        "Question": "3.  Which of the following extracts first four element from the following R vector?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"b\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"c\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"c\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"d\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x[0:4] ",
            "b) x[1:4] ",
            "c) x[0:3] ",
            "d) x[4:3]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The multiple successive elements which we want to extract will be in the format of variable[index value of the start element:index value of the last element] in R script."
    },
    {
        "id": 248,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"b\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"c\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"c\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"d\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “a” “b” “c”",
            "b) “a” “c” “c”",
            "c) “a” “c” “b”",
            "d) “b” “c” “b”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The sequence does not have to be in order; you can specify any arbitrary integer vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 249,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $ operator semantics are similar to that of [[",
            "b) The [ operator always returns an object of the same class as the original",
            "c) The $ operator is used to extract elements of a list or a data frame",
            "d) There are three operators that can be used to extract subsets of R objects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The [[ operator is used to extract elements of a list or a data frame. It can only be used to extract a single element and the class of the returned object will not necessarily be a list or data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 250,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">matrix</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Matrices can be subsetted in the usual way with (i,j) type indices where i is the row and j is the column numbers."
    },
    {
        "id": 251,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">matrix</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 3 5",
            "b) 2 3 5",
            "c) 3 3 5",
            "d) file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Matrices can be subsetted in the usual way with (i,j) type indices where i is the row and j is the column numbers. If only row or only column number is specified, then the respective full row or column is printed."
    },
    {
        "id": 252,
        "Question": "8. Which of the following R code extracts the second column for the following matrix?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">matrix</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x[2, ] ",
            "b) x[1, 2] ",
            "c) x[, 2] ",
            "d) x[1 1 2]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This behavior is used to access entire rows or columns of a matrix."
    },
    {
        "id": 253,
        "Question": "1. Which of the following extracts first element from the following R list?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>foo <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, bar <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0.6</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x[[1]] ",
            "b) x[1] ",
            "c) x[[0]] ",
            "d) x[0]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The [[ operator can also use named indices so that you don’t have to remember the exact ordering of every element of the list."
    },
    {
        "id": 254,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can also use the $ operator to extract elements by name",
            "b) $ operator can be used with computed indices",
            "c) The [[ operator can only be used with literal names",
            "d) $ operator semantics are similar to that of [["
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You don’t need the quotes when you use the $ operator."
    },
    {
        "id": 255,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>foo <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, bar <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0.6</span>, baz <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> name <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"foo\"</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x$name</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) NULL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Element “name” doesn’t exist."
    },
    {
        "id": 256,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>foo <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, bar <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0.6</span>, baz <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> name <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"foo\"</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span>name<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4",
            "b) 0 1 2 3",
            "c) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One thing that differentiates the [[ operator from the $ is that the [[ operator can be used with computed indices."
    },
    {
        "id": 257,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">12</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">14</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>, b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3.14</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2.81</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13",
            "b) 14",
            "c) 15",
            "d) 18"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The [[ operator can take an integer sequence if you want to extract a nested element of a list."
    },
    {
        "id": 258,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>aardvark <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x$a</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) 2 3 5",
            "c) 1 3 3 5",
            "d) 1 2 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Partial matching of names is allowed with [[ and $."
    },
    {
        "id": 259,
        "Question": "7. Which of the following code extracts 1st element of the 2nd element?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">12</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">14</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>, b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3.14</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2.81</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x[[c(2, 1)]] ",
            "b) x[[c(1, 2)]] ",
            "c) x[[c(2, 1,1)]] ",
            "d) x[[(2, 2,1)]]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: [ operator always returns an object of the same class as the original."
    },
    {
        "id": 260,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">list</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>aardvark <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, exact <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> FALSE<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) 2 3 5",
            "c) 1 3 3 5",
            "d) 1 2 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This is often very useful during interactive work if the object you’re working with has very long element names."
    },
    {
        "id": 261,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, NA, <span class=\"nu0\">4</span>, NA, <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> bad <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">is.<span class=\"me1\">na</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>bad<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) FALSE FALSE FALSE FALSE TRUE FALSE",
            "b) FALSE TRUE TRUE FALSE TRUE FALSE",
            "c) FALSE FALSE TRUE FALSE TRUE FALSE",
            "d) FALSE TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE FALSE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A common task in data analysis is removing missing values (NAs)."
    },
    {
        "id": 262,
        "Question": "1. Which of the following is example of vectorized operation as far as subtraction is concerned?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">9</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x+y",
            "b) x-y",
            "c) x/y",
            "d) x–y"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Subtraction, multiplication and division are also vectorized."
    },
    {
        "id": 263,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Very less operations in R are vectorized",
            "b) Vectorization allows you to write code that is efficient, concise, and easier to read than in non-vectorized languages",
            "c) vectorized means that operations occur in parallel in certain R objects",
            "d) Matrix operations are also vectorized"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Many operations in R are vectorized."
    },
    {
        "id": 264,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> y\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> z</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7 9 11 13",
            "b) 7 9 11 13 14",
            "c) 9 7 11 13",
            "d) NULL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This is  simplest example of adding two vectors together."
    },
    {
        "id": 265,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4",
            "b) FALSE FALSE TRUE TRUE",
            "c) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "d) 5 4 3 1 2 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Another operation you can do in a vectorized manner is logical comparisons."
    },
    {
        "id": 266,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dates are represented by the Date class",
            "b) Times are represented by the POSIXct or the POSIXlt class",
            "c) Dates are represented by the DateTime class",
            "d) Times can be coerced from a character string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Dates are stored internally as the number of days since 1970-01-01 while times are stored internally as the number of seconds since 1970-01-01."
    },
    {
        "id": 267,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">/</span>y</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.1666667 0.2857143 0.4444444",
            "b) 0.1666667 0.2857143 0.3750000 0.4444444",
            "c) 0.2857143 0.3750000 0.4444444",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Logical operations return a logical vector of TRUE and FALSE."
    },
    {
        "id": 268,
        "Question": "Which of the following code represents internal representation of a Date object?",
        "Options": [
            "a) class(as.Date(“1970-01-02”))",
            "b) unclass(as.Date(“1970-01-02”))",
            "c) unclassint(as.Date(“1970-01-02”))",
            "d) classint(as.Date(“1970-02-02”))"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can see the internal representation of a Date object by using the unclass() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 269,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">Date</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1970-01-01\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “1970-01-01”",
            "b) “1970-01-02”",
            "c) “1970-02-01”",
            "d) “1970-02-02”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Matrix operations are also vectorized, making for nicely compact notation."
    },
    {
        "id": 270,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">Sys.<span class=\"me1\">time</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">class</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “POSIXct” “POSIXt”",
            "b) “POSIXXt” “POSIXt”",
            "c) “POSIXct” “POSIct”",
            "d) “POSIXt” “POSIXt”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Dates are represented by the Date class and can be coerced from a character string using the as.Date() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 271,
        "Question": "Which of the following function gives the day of the week?",
        "Options": [
            "a) weekdays",
            "b) months",
            "c) quarters",
            "d) semesters"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Weekdays will give the day of the week. months function give the month name. Quarters divide the year into fourths. Semesters divide the year into halfs."
    },
    {
        "id": 272,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Times use the POSIXct and POSIXlt class",
            "b) Dates and times have special classes in R that allow for numerical and statistical calculations",
            "c) Character strings can be coerced to Date/Time classes using the strptime function",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Character strings can be coerced to Date/Time classes using the as.Date, as.POSIXlt, or as.POSIXct."
    },
    {
        "id": 273,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">POSIXlt</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">names</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">unclass</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> p$wday</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) NULL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The POSIXlt object contains some useful metadata."
    },
    {
        "id": 274,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> datestring <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"January 10, 2012 10:40\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"December 9, 2011 9:10\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">strptime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>datestring, <span class=\"st0\">\"%B %d, %Y %H:%M\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “2012-01-10 10:40:00 EST” “2011-12-09 09:10:00 EST”",
            "b) “2012-01-10 10:40:00 IST” “2011-12-09 09:10:00 IST”",
            "c) “2012-01-10 10:40:00 GMT” “2011-12-09 09:10:00 GMT”",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: strptime() takes a character vector that has dates and times and converts them into to a POSIXlt object."
    },
    {
        "id": 275,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) POSIXct is just a very large integer under the hood",
            "b) POSIXlt stores a bunch of other useful information like the day of the week, day of the year, month, day of the month",
            "c) There are a number of generic functions that work on dates and times to help you extract pieces of dates and/or times",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: POSIXct uses a useful class when you want to store times in something like a data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 276,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">Date</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2012-01-01\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">strptime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"9 Jan 2011 11:34:21\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"%d %b %Y %H:%M:%S\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>y</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Time difference of 356.3095 days",
            "b) Warning",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You can use mathematical operations on dates and times."
    },
    {
        "id": 277,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">Date</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2012-03-01\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">Date</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2012-02-28\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>y</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Time difference of 3 days",
            "b) Time difference of 2 days",
            "c) Time difference of 1 days",
            "d) Time difference of 5 days"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Matrix operations are also vectorized, making for nicely compact notation."
    },
    {
        "id": 278,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">POSIXct</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2012-10-25 01:00:00\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">as.<span class=\"me1\">POSIXct</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2012-10-25 06:00:00\"</span>, tz <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"GMT\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>x</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Time difference of 1 hour",
            "b) Time difference of 1 min",
            "c) Time difference of 1 sec",
            "d) Time difference of 5 sec"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: POSIXct is just a very large integer under the hood."
    },
    {
        "id": 279,
        "Question": "Which of the following return a subset of the columns of a data frame?",
        "Options": [
            "a) select",
            "b) retrieve",
            "c) get",
            "d) set"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One important contribution of the dplyr package is that it provides a “grammar” for data manipulation and for operating on data frames."
    },
    {
        "id": 280,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The data frame is a key data structure in statistics and in R",
            "b) R has an internal implementation of data frames that is likely the one you will use most often",
            "c) There are packages on CRAN that implement data frames via things like relational databases that allow you to operate on very very large data frames",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The basic structure of a data frame is that there is one observation per row and each column represents a variable, a measure, feature, or characteristic of that observation."
    },
    {
        "id": 281,
        "Question": "_________ extract a subset of rows from a dataframe based on logical conditions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rename",
            "b) filter",
            "c) set",
            "d) subset"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rename is used to rename variables in a dataframe."
    },
    {
        "id": 282,
        "Question": "_________ generate summary statistics of different variables in the data frame, possibly within strata.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rename",
            "b) summarize",
            "c) set",
            "d) subset"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The dplyr package as a number of its own data types that it takes advantage of."
    },
    {
        "id": 283,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The dplyr package was developed by Hadley Wickham of RStudio",
            "b) The dplyr package is an optimized and distilled version of his plyr package",
            "c) The dplyr package provides any “new” functionality to R",
            "d) The dplyr package does not provide any “new” functionality to R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The dplyr package does not provide any “new” functionality to R."
    },
    {
        "id": 284,
        "Question": "________ add new variables/columns or transform existing variables.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mutate",
            "b) add",
            "c) apped",
            "d) arrange"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: arrange is used to reorder rows of a dataframe."
    },
    {
        "id": 285,
        "Question": "The _______ operator is used to connect multiple verb actions together into a pipeline.",
        "Options": [
            "a) pipe",
            "b) piper",
            "c) start",
            "d) end"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is denoted by %>% sign."
    },
    {
        "id": 286,
        "Question": "The dplyr package can be installed from GitHub using the _______ package.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dev",
            "b) devtools",
            "c) devtool",
            "d) devdel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The GitHub repository will usually contain the latest updates to the package and the development version."
    },
    {
        "id": 287,
        "Question": "The dplyr package can be installed from CRAN using __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) installall.packages(“dplyr”)",
            "b) install.packages(“dplyr”)",
            "c) installed.packages(“dplyr”)",
            "d) installed.packages(“dpl”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: After installing the package it is important that you load it into your R session with the library() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 288,
        "Question": "Which of the following object is masked from ‘package: stats’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) filter",
            "b) union",
            "c) set difference",
            "d) get difference"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The following objects are masked from ‘package:base’: intersect, setdiff, setequal, union."
    },
    {
        "id": 289,
        "Question": "The _________ function can be used to select columns of a data frame that you want to focus on.",
        "Options": [
            "a) select",
            "b) rename",
            "c) get",
            "d) set"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The select() function allows you to get the few columns you might need."
    },
    {
        "id": 290,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can also omit variables using the select() function by using the negative sign",
            "b) The arrange() function also allows a special syntax that allows you to specify variable names based on patterns",
            "c) Reordering rows of a data frame is normally easier to do in R",
            "d) The dplyr package provides any “new” functionality to R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The arrange() function is used to reorder rows of a data frame according to one of the variables/columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 291,
        "Question": "________ function is similar to the existing subset() function in R but is quite a bit faster.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rename",
            "b) filter",
            "c) set",
            "d) subset"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The filter() function is used to extract subsets of rows from a data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 292,
        "Question": "Columns can be arranged in descending order too by using the special ____ operator.",
        "Options": [
            "a) asc()",
            "b) desc()",
            "c) descending()",
            "d) subset"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This will sort the order in decreasing order."
    },
    {
        "id": 293,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Renaming a variable in a data frame in R is surprisingly hard to do",
            "b) The mutate() function exists to compute transformations of variables in a data frame",
            "c) mute() function, which does the same thing as mutate() but then drops all non-transformed variables",
            "d) The data frame is a key data structure in statistics and in R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The rename() function is designed to make this process easier."
    },
    {
        "id": 294,
        "Question": "The _________ function is used to generate summary statistics from the data frame within strata defined by a variable.",
        "Options": [
            "a) groupby()",
            "b) group()",
            "c) group_by()",
            "d) arrange"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The general operation here is a combination of splitting a data frame into separate pieces defined by a variable or group of variables (group_by()), and then applying a summary function across those subsets (summarize())."
    },
    {
        "id": 295,
        "Question": "The ______ operator allows you to string operations in a left-to-right fashion.",
        "Options": [
            "a) %>%>",
            "b) %>%",
            "c) >%>%",
            "d) >>>>%%%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The pipeline operator %>% is very handy for stringing together multiple dplyr functions in a sequence of operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 296,
        "Question": "There is an SQL interface for relational databases via the _______ package.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DIB",
            "b) DB2",
            "c) DBI",
            "d) DIB21"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: dplyr can work with other data frame “backends” such as SQL databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 297,
        "Question": "dplyr can be integrated with the ________ package for large fast tables.",
        "Options": [
            "a) data.table",
            "b) read.table",
            "c) data.data",
            "d) table.read"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The dplyr package is handy way to both simplify and speed up your data frame management code."
    },
    {
        "id": 298,
        "Question": "Which of the following function is similar to summarize?",
        "Options": [
            "a) arrange_by()",
            "b) group()",
            "c) group_by()",
            "d) arrange"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The dplyr package provides a concise set of operations for managing data frames."
    },
    {
        "id": 299,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Blocks are evaluated until a new line is entered after the closing brace",
            "b) Single statements are evaluated when a new line is typed at the start of the syntactically complete statement",
            "c) The if/else statement conditionally evaluates two statements",
            "d) Break will execute a loop while a condition is true"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The if/else statement returns, as its value, the value of the statement that was selected."
    },
    {
        "id": 300,
        "Question": "Which of the following R syntax is correct for while loop?",
        "Options": [
            "a) while ( statement1 ) statement2",
            "b) while ( statement1 ) else statement2",
            "c) while ( statement1 ) do statement2",
            "d) while ( statement2 ) doelse statement2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The while statement is very similar to the repeat statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) for will execute a loop a fixed number of times",
            "b) break will execute a loop while a condition is true",
            "c) if and else tests a condition and acting on it",
            "d) break is used to break the execution of a loop"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The if-else structure allows you to test a condition and act on it depending on whether it’s true or false."
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "Question": "_______ is used to break the execution of a loop.",
        "Options": [
            "a) next",
            "b) skip",
            "c) break",
            "d) delete"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Control structures allow you to respond to inputs or to features of the data and execute different R expressions accordingly."
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement can be used to explicitly control looping?",
        "Options": [
            "a) if",
            "b) while",
            "c) break",
            "d) for"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The break statement causes an exit from the innermost loop that is currently being executed."
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "Question": "Which of the following should be preferred for evaluation from list of alternatives?",
        "Options": [
            "a) subsett",
            "b) eval",
            "c) switch",
            "d) set"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: eval(x[[condition]]) is the best way to select one for evaluation."
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The only way to exit a repeat loop is to call break",
            "b) Infinite loops should generally be avoided",
            "c) Control structures like if, while, and for allow you to control the flow of an R program",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Control structures are primarily useful for writing programs; for command line interactive work."
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "Question": "_________ initiates an infinite loop right from the start.",
        "Options": [
            "a) never",
            "b) repeat",
            "c) break",
            "d) set"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: These are not commonly used in statistical or data analysis applications but they do have their uses."
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Statements cannot be grouped together using braces ‘{’ and ‘}’",
            "b) Computation in R consists of sequentially evaluating statements",
            "c) Single statements are evaluated when a new line is typed at the end of the syntactically complete statement",
            "d) next is used to skip an iteration of a loop"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Blocks are not evaluated until a new line is entered after the closing brace."
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "Question": "_______ is used to skip an iteration of a loop.",
        "Options": [
            "a) next",
            "b) skip",
            "c) group",
            "d) cancel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: No statement below next in the current loop is evaluated."
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "Question": "R has ________ statements that provide explicit looping.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: They are for, while and repeat."
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "Question": "The syntax of the repeat loop is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) rep statement",
            "b) repeat statement",
            "c) repeat else",
            "d) repeat while"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The repeat statement causes repeated evaluation of the body until a break is specifically requested."
    },
    {
        "id": 311,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">switch</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">mean</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>, <span class=\"kw7\">rnorm</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.2903605  2.3271663 -0.7060073  1.3622045 -0.2892720",
            "b) 5.5",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The else clause is optional. The statement if(any(x <= 0)) x <- x[x <= 0] is valid."
    },
    {
        "id": 312,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">switch</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">mean</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>, <span class=\"kw7\">rnorm</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 5.5",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) 58"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If value is a number between 1 and the length of list then the corresponding element of list is evaluated and the result returned."
    },
    {
        "id": 313,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Statements, such as x<-1:10 or mean(y), can be separated by either a semicolon or a new line",
            "b) Whenever the evaluator is presented with a syntactically complete statement that statement is evaluated and the value returned",
            "c) Computation in R consists of sequentially evaluating statements",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both semicolons and new lines can be used to separate statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 314,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">switch</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"kw2\">mean</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>, <span class=\"kw7\">rnorm</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 1",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If value is too large or too small NULL is returned."
    },
    {
        "id": 315,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"fruit\"</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">switch</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>y, fruit <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"banana\"</span>, vegetable <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"broccoli\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"Neither\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “banana”",
            "b) “Neither”",
            "c) “broccoli”",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If value is a character vector then the element of ‘…’ with a name that exactly matches value is evaluated."
    },
    {
        "id": 316,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The next statement causes an exit from the innermost loop that is currently being executed",
            "b) There are two statements that can be used to explicitly control looping",
            "c) The break statement immediately causes control to return to the start of the loop",
            "d) Computation in R consists of sequentially evaluating statements"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: They are break and next."
    },
    {
        "id": 317,
        "Question": "6.What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> centre <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x, type<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw2\">switch</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>type,\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>        <span class=\"kw2\">mean</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw2\">mean</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>,\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>        <span class=\"kw7\">median</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw7\">median</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>,\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>        trimmed <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw2\">mean</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x, trim <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> .1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw7\">rcauchy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> centre<span class=\"br0\">(</span>x, <span class=\"st0\">\"mean\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.8760325",
            "b) 0.5360891",
            "c) 0.6086504",
            "d) gives mean with values depending on rcauchy values"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A common use of switch is to branch according to the character value of one of the arguments to a function. Generates a random point pattern, a simulated realisation of the Neyman-Scott process with Cauchy cluster kernel."
    },
    {
        "id": 318,
        "Question": "R has ________ basic indexing operators.",
        "Options": [
            "a) two",
            "b) three",
            "c) four",
            "d) five"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R contains several constructs which allow access to individual elements or subsets through indexing operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 319,
        "Question": "Which of the following is apply function in R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply()",
            "b) tapply()",
            "c) fapply()",
            "d) rapply()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Functions can be passed as arguments to other functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 320,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Writing functions is a core activity of an R programmer",
            "b) Functions are often used to encapsulate a sequence of expressions that need to be executed numerous times",
            "c) Functions are also often written when code must be shared with others or the public",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It represents the key step of the transition from a mere “user” to a developer who creates new functionality for R."
    },
    {
        "id": 321,
        "Question": "Functions are defined using the _________ directive and are stored as R objects.",
        "Options": [
            "a) function()",
            "b) funct()",
            "c) functions()",
            "d) fun()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In particular, they are R objects of class “function”."
    },
    {
        "id": 322,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>             <span class=\"co1\">## This is an empty function</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) No result",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This function takes no arguments and does nothing."
    },
    {
        "id": 323,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Functions in R are “second class objects”",
            "b) The writing of a function allows a developer to create an interface to the code, that is explicitly specified with a set of parameters",
            "c) Functions provides an abstraction of the code to potential users",
            "d) Writing functions is a core activity of an R programmer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Functions in R are “first class objects”, which means that they can be treated much like any other R object."
    },
    {
        "id": 324,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>              <span class=\"co1\">## This is an empty function</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">class</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “function”",
            "b) “class”",
            "c) “procedure”",
            "d) “system”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Functions have their own class."
    },
    {
        "id": 325,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>num<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> hello <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Hello, world!<span class=\"es0\">\\n</span>\"</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw2\">for</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"kw2\">seq_len</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>num<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                    <span class=\"kw2\">cat</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>hello<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                    chars <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">nchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>hello<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> num\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                    chars\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> meaningoflife <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>meaningoflife<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32",
            "b) 42",
            "c) 52",
            "d) 46"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In general, if you find yourself doing a lot of cutting and pasting, that’s usually a good sign that you might need to write a function."
    },
    {
        "id": 326,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following R code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">paste</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"b\"</span>, se <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\":\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “a+b”",
            "b) “a=b”",
            "c) “a b :”",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: With the paste() function, the arguments sep and collapse must be named explicitly and in full if the default values are not going to be used."
    },
    {
        "id": 327,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) In R, a function is an object which has the mode function",
            "b) R interpreter is able to pass control to the function, along with arguments that may be necessary for the function to accomplish the actions that are desired",
            "c) Functions are also often written when code must be shared with others or the public",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An argument list is a comma separated list of formal arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 328,
        "Question": "The __________ function returns a list of all the formal arguments of a function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) formals()",
            "b) funct()",
            "c) formal()",
            "d) fun()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Functions have named arguments which can optionally have default values."
    },
    {
        "id": 329,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A formal argument can be a symbol, a statement of the form ‘symbol = expression’, or the special formal argument",
            "b) The first component of the function declaration is the keyword function",
            "c) The value returned by the call to function is not a function",
            "d) Functions are also often written when code must be shared with others or the public"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The value returned by the call to function is a function."
    },
    {
        "id": 330,
        "Question": "You can check to see whether an R object is NULL with the _________ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) is.null()",
            "b) is.nullobj()",
            "c) null()",
            "d) as.nullobj()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is sometimes useful to allow an argument to take the NULL value, which might indicate that the function should take some specific action."
    },
    {
        "id": 331,
        "Question": "Which of the following code will print NULL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) > args(paste)",
            "b) > arg(paste)",
            "c) > args(pastebin)",
            "d) > arg(bin)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One catch with … is that any arguments that appear after … on the argument list must be named explicitly and cannot be partially matched or matched positionally."
    },
    {
        "id": 332,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following R code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a, b<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>       a<span class=\"sy0\">^</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The formal arguments are the arguments included in the function definition."
    },
    {
        "id": 333,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following R code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">paste</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"b\"</span>, sep <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\":\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “a+b”",
            "b) “a=b”",
            "c) “a:b”",
            "d) a*b"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This function never actually uses the argument b, so calling f(2) will not produce an error because the 2 gets positionally matched to a."
    },
    {
        "id": 334,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following R code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a, b<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>              <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>              <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>b<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">45</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32",
            "b) 42",
            "c) 52",
            "d) 45"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: With the paste() function, the arguments sep and collapse must be named explicitly and in full if the default values are not going to be used."
    },
    {
        "id": 335,
        "Question": "R Commander is used to ___________ in R.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Export data",
            "b) Import data",
            "c) Use data",
            "d) Work on data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R Commander is used to import data in R language. To start the R commander GUI, the user should type in the command Rcmdr into the console. There are 3 different types in which data can be imported in R language."
    },
    {
        "id": 336,
        "Question": "Two vectors M and N are defined as M <- c(3, 2, 4) and N <- c(1, 2). What will be the output of vector Z that is defined as Z <- M*N.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Z <- (3, 2, 4)",
            "b) Z <- (3, 6, 4)",
            "c) Z <- (3, 4, 5)",
            "d) Z <- (3, 4, 4)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In R language when the vectors have different lengths, the multiplication begins with the smaller vector and continues till all the elements in the larger vector have been multiplied."
    },
    {
        "id": 337,
        "Question": "How missing values and impossible values are represented in R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NA",
            "b) NAN",
            "c) NA & NAN",
            "d) Not Exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: NaN (Not a Number) is used to represent impossible values whereas NA (Not Available) is referred to represent missing values. It is good to find the missing values and then take the necessary steps to handle them."
    },
    {
        "id": 338,
        "Question": "CRAN package ecosystem has more than ______ packages.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5000",
            "b) 4000",
            "c) 6000",
            "d) 8000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: R language has several packages for solving a particular problem. CRAN package ecosystem has more than 6000 packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 339,
        "Question": "Which function in R language is used to find out whether the means of 2 groups are equal to each other or not?",
        "Options": [
            "a) f.tests ()",
            "b) l.tests ()",
            "c) t.tests ()",
            "d) not exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: t.tests () function in R language is used to find out whether the means of 2 groups are equal to each other. It is not used most commonly in R. It is used in some specific conditions."
    },
    {
        "id": 340,
        "Question": "__________ is the best way for communicating the results of data analysis using the R language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Single document",
            "b) Files",
            "c) Structures",
            "d) Loadings"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answers: a\nExplanation: The best possible way to do this is to combine the data, code and analysis results for a single document by knitr for reproducible research. This helps others to verify the findings, then engage in discussions."
    },
    {
        "id": 341,
        "Question": "How many types of data structures does R language have?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: R language consists of Homogeneous and Heterogeneous data structures. Homogeneous data structures have the same type of objects – Vector, Matrix and Array. Heterogeneous data structures have a different type of objects – Data frames and lists."
    },
    {
        "id": 342,
        "Question": "__________ is the easiest method for reshaping the data before analysis.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Transpose()",
            "b) Structure()",
            "c) Package",
            "d) Function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Transpose t () is the easiest method for reshaping the data before analysis. The transpose (reversing rows and columns) is always the simplest method of reshaping a dataset. Use the t() function to transpose a matrix or a data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 343,
        "Question": "___________ function is used to apply an expression for a given dataset.",
        "Options": [
            "a) This()",
            "b) With()",
            "c) Unwith()",
            "d) That()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: With a () function is used to apply an expression for a given dataset. R language has a large number of in-built functions and the user can create their own functions. In R, a function is an object to the R interpreter is able to pass control to the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 344,
        "Question": "__________ package is used to speed up data frame management code.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data.table",
            "b) Dplyr",
            "c) Table",
            "d) Data.dplyr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: dplyr is a powerful R-package to transform and summarize tabular data with rows and columns. dplyr package is used to speed up data frame management code. dplyr is a package for data manipulation, written and maintained regularly by Hadley Wickham."
    },
    {
        "id": 345,
        "Question": "Which package can be integrated with dplyr for large fast tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table",
            "b) Data, dplyr",
            "c) Data.table",
            "d) Dplyr.table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Data.table package can be integrated with dplyr for large fast tables. dplyr package is used to speed up data frame management code. dplyr is a package for data manipulation, written and maintained regularly by Hadley Wickham."
    },
    {
        "id": 346,
        "Question": "In the base graphics system, which function is used to add elements to a plot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Boxplot()",
            "b) Text()",
            "c) Boxplot() or Text()",
            "d) Treat()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the base graphics system, boxplot or text function is used to add elements to a plot."
    },
    {
        "id": 347,
        "Question": "What are the different types of sorting algorithms available in R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bubble",
            "b) Selection",
            "c) Merge",
            "d) All sorts"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Bucket Sort, Selection Sort, Quick Sort, Bubble Sort, Merge Sort is the different sorts available in R language. Each and Every sorting algorithm is available in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 348,
        "Question": "What is the command used to store R objects in a file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) save (x, file=”x.Rdata”)",
            "b) save (x, file=x.Rdata)",
            "c) save (x, file=”x.Rdata”);",
            "d) save (x, file=”x.data”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function save() can be used to save one or more R objects to a specified file (in .RData or .rda type file formats). The function can be read back from the file using the function load(). Note that if you save your data with save(), it cannot be restored under a different name."
    },
    {
        "id": 349,
        "Question": "___________ can be used for storing the data for long-term.",
        "Options": [
            "a) HDLS",
            "b) HDFS",
            "c) HDLSV",
            "d) HSSLV"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) is the primary data storage system used in Hadoop applications. The Hadoop Distributed File System ( HDFS ) is a distributed file system designed for a run on commodity hardware."
    },
    {
        "id": 350,
        "Question": "MapReduce jobs submitted from either Oozie, Pig or Hive can be used to encode, improve and sample the data sets from _________ into R.",
        "Options": [
            "a) HDLS",
            "b) HDFS",
            "c) HDLSV",
            "d) HSSLV"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MapReduce jobs submitted from either Oozie, Pig or Hive can be used for encode, improve and sample the data sets from HDFS into R. This helps to leverage complex analysis tasks with the subset of data prepared in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 351,
        "Question": "What will be the output of log (-5.8) when executed on R console?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NAN",
            "b) NA",
            "c) Error",
            "d) 0.213"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Executing the above on R console or terminal will display a warning sign that NaN (Not a Number)  will be produced in R console because it is not possible to take a log of a negative number(-)."
    },
    {
        "id": 352,
        "Question": "How is a Data object represented internally in R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) unclass (as.time (“2018-12-28″))",
            "b) unclass (as.dat (“2018-12-28″))",
            "c) unclass (as.D (2018-12-28))",
            "d) unclass (as.Date (“2018-12-28″))"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: unclass returns (a copy of) its argument with its class information removed. Unclass with an object is to remove from a class or category."
    },
    {
        "id": 353,
        "Question": "Which package in R supports the exploratory analysis of genomic data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Adegenat",
            "b) Adegenet",
            "c) Adegnet",
            "d) Adezenet"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Adegenet package in R supports the exploratory analysis of genomic data. R has a large number of in-built functions and the user can create their own functions. In R, a function is an object so the R interpreter is able to pass control to the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 354,
        "Question": "__________ can contain heterogeneous inputs.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix",
            "b) Data Frames",
            "c) Matrix and Data Frames",
            "d) Does not exists"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Data frame can contain heterogeneous inputs while a matrix cannot. In the matrix, only similar data types can be stored whereas in a data frame there can be different data types like characters, integers or other data frames."
    },
    {
        "id": 355,
        "Question": "________ function can be used to add datasets in R provided with the columns in the datasets should be the same.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rbind()",
            "b) bbind()",
            "c) jbind()",
            "d) hbind()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rbind () function can be used add datasets in R language provided the columns in the datasets should be the same. R has a large number of in-built functions and also the user can create their own functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 356,
        "Question": "_________ variables are categorical variables which can hold either string or numeric values.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Factor",
            "b) Simpler",
            "c) Function",
            "d) Package"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Factor variables are categorical variables that hold the string or numeric values. Factor variables are used in various types of graphics and particularly for statistical modelling where a correct number of degrees of freedom is assigned to them."
    },
    {
        "id": 357,
        "Question": "What is the memory limit in R for 64 bit system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8 TB",
            "b) 9TB",
            "c) 10TB",
            "d) 16TB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 8TB is the memory limit for 64-bit system memory and 3GB is the limit for 32-bit system memory. A solid understanding of R’s memory management will help you predict how much memory you’ll need for a given task."
    },
    {
        "id": 358,
        "Question": "What is the memory limit in R for 32 bit system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8 TB",
            "b) 9TB",
            "c) 10TB",
            "d) 3GB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 8TB is the memory limit for 64-bit system memory and 3GB is the limit for 32-bit system memory. A solid understanding of R’s memory management will help you predict how much memory you’ll need for a given task."
    },
    {
        "id": 359,
        "Question": "What are the data types in R on which binary operators can be applied?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scalars",
            "b) Matrices",
            "c) Vectors",
            "d) Scalars, Matrices and Vectors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: R has a large number of in-built functions and the user can create their own functions. In R, a function is an object. So the R interpreter is able to pass control to the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 360,
        "Question": "__________ function is used in applying a function each level of factors.",
        "Options": [
            "a) With()",
            "b) By()",
            "c) To()",
            "d) Here()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: BY () function is used for applying a function each level of factors. R has a large number of in-built functions and also user can create their own functions. In R, a function is an object. So the R interpreter is able to pass control to the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 361,
        "Question": "How do you create log linear models in R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) loglm()",
            "b) logmn()",
            "c) logfn()",
            "d) loghy()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: loglm is fit log-linear models by iterative proportional scaling. This function provides a front-end of the standard function, loglin, to allow log-linear models to be specified and fitted in a manner similar to that of other fitting functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 362,
        "Question": "What will be the class of the vector if you concatenate a number and NA?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number",
            "b) Character",
            "c) Integer",
            "d) No class"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The class of the resulting vector if you concatenate a number and NA is a Number. Decimal values are also called numeric in R. It is the default computational data type in R language."
    },
    {
        "id": 363,
        "Question": "____________ is one type of the simplest machine learning classification algorithms that is a subset of supervised learning based on lazy learning.",
        "Options": [
            "a) K-Nearest Neighbour",
            "b) Naïve Bayes",
            "c) Travelling Salesman",
            "d) N-Queen"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: K-Nearest Neighbour is one type of the simplest machine learning classification algorithms that is a subset of supervised learning based on lazy learning. In this algorithm the function is approximated and also computations are deferred until classification."
    },
    {
        "id": 364,
        "Question": "What will be the class of the vector if you concatenate a number and a character?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number",
            "b) Character",
            "c) Integer",
            "d) No class"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The class of the resulting vector if you concatenate a number and a character is Character class. Decimal values are called numeric in R. It is the default computational data type in R language."
    },
    {
        "id": 365,
        "Question": "R code can be tested using _________________ package.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dplyr",
            "b) Hadley’s testthat",
            "c) SKLearn",
            "d) KNN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R code can be tested using Hadley’s testthat package. Testthat draws inspiration from the xUnit family of testing packages, as well as from many of the innovative ruby testing libraries."
    },
    {
        "id": 366,
        "Question": "If the programmers want the output to be a data frame or a vector, then  ________ function is used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lapply",
            "b) Sapply",
            "c) Vapply",
            "d) Zapply"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If the programmers want the output to be a data frame or a vector, then sapply function is used whereas if the programmer wants the output to be a list then lapply is used. vapply allows the programmer to specific the output type."
    },
    {
        "id": 367,
        "Question": "If a programmer wants the output to be a list then ___________ function is used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lapply",
            "b) Sapply",
            "c) Vapply",
            "d) Zapply"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sapply() function does the same jobs as lapply() function but returns a vector. We can use a user built-in function into lapply() or sapply(). We create a function named avg to compute the average of the minimum and maximum of the vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 368,
        "Question": "_____________ function is preferred over sapply as vapply allows the programmer to specific the output type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lapply",
            "b) Japply",
            "c) Vapply",
            "d) Zapply"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Vapply is similar to sapply, but has a pre-specified type of return value, so it can be safer (and sometimes faster) to use. simplify2array() is the utility called from sapply() when simplify is not false and is similarly called from mapply()."
    },
    {
        "id": 369,
        "Question": "Which function is difficult to implement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lapply",
            "b) Japply",
            "c) Vapply",
            "d) Zapply"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Vapply allows the programmer to specific the output type. The disadvantage of using vapply is that it is very  difficult to be implemented and more verbose. vapply is similar to sapply, but has a pre-specified type of return value, so it can be safer to use."
    },
    {
        "id": 370,
        "Question": "Which function is more verbose?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lapply",
            "b) Japply",
            "c) Vapply",
            "d) Zapply"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If a programmer wants the output to be a list then lapply is used. vapply allows the programmer to specific the output type. The disadvantage of using vapply is that it is very difficult to be implemented and more verbose."
    },
    {
        "id": 371,
        "Question": "_____________ will produce a sequential vector c( (1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9)).",
        "Options": [
            "a) Seq(9)",
            "b) Seq(10)",
            "c) Seq(15)",
            "d) Seq(12)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Seq generates a sequence of a priori known pattern. Seq_along(6) will produce a vector with length 6 whereas seq(6) will produce a sequential vector from 1 to 6 c((1,2,3,4,5,6))."
    },
    {
        "id": 372,
        "Question": "__________ function is used for reading the .csv file in R language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Write.csv()",
            "b) Read.csv ()",
            "c) Let.csv()",
            "d) Table.csv()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: read.csv () function is used for reading the .csv file in R language. We will use the built in the read.csv() function call, which reads the data as the data frame, and assign the data frame to a variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 373,
        "Question": "The line of code in R language should begin with a ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hash symbol",
            "b) Alphabet",
            "c) Number",
            "d) Character"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The line of code in R language should begin with a hash symbol (#). R has a large number of in-built functions and also the user can create their own functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 374,
        "Question": "_______________ returns TRUE then X can be termed as a matrix data object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) is.”matrix(X”)",
            "b) is.matrix(X)",
            "c) is.notamatrix(X )",
            "d) is.matrix(“X”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function call is.matrix(X ) returns TRUE then X can be termed as a matrix data object. R has a large number of in-built functions and also the user can create their own functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 375,
        "Question": "If two vectors with different lengths perform some operation, the elements of the shorter vector will be used again to complete the operation. This is referred to as _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Element Recycling",
            "b) Recycling",
            "c) Cycling",
            "d) Element Cycling"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If two vectors with different lengths perform an operation, the elements of the shorter vector will be used again to complete the operation. This is referred to as element recycling."
    },
    {
        "id": 376,
        "Question": "If the function in a console is.matrix(X) returns true then X can be considered as a _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix object",
            "b) Matrix data object",
            "c) Matrix vector",
            "d) Vector"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function call is.matrix(X) returns TRUE then X can be termed as a matrix data object. R has a large number of in-built functions and also the user can create their own functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 377,
        "Question": "______________ measures the probability of the binary response variable in R language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Logical Regression",
            "b) Multivariate Regression",
            "c) Simpler Regression",
            "d) Statistics"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Logistic regression can be used for this and the function glm () in R language provides this functionality. Logistic regression is a statistical method for analysing a dataset in which there are one or more independent variables which determine an outcome."
    },
    {
        "id": 378,
        "Question": "______________ function will measure the probability of the binary response variable in R language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Glm()",
            "b) Glmi()",
            "c) Gelmi()",
            "d) Jlm()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Glm () in R language provides this functionality. Logistic regression is a statistical method for analysing a dataset in which there are one or more independent variables that determine an outcome."
    },
    {
        "id": 379,
        "Question": "____________ function can be used to select the random sample of size ‘n’ from a huge dataset.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple()",
            "b) Sample()",
            "c) While()",
            "d) Signal()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sample () function can be used to select a random sample of size ‘n’ from the huge dataset. R has a large number of in-built functions and also the user can create their own functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 380,
        "Question": "Which function is used to select variables and observations from a given dataset?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Subset()",
            "b) Sample()",
            "c) While()",
            "d) Signal()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Subset () function is used to select variables and observations from a given dataset. R has a large number of in-built functions and also the user can create their own functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 381,
        "Question": "____________ package in R language provides various options for re-randomization and permutations based on statistical tests.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Coin",
            "b) Vain",
            "c) Join",
            "d) Lain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Coin package in R language provides various options for re-randomization and permutations based on statistical tests. When test assumptions cannot be met then this package serves as a good alternative to classical methods."
    },
    {
        "id": 382,
        "Question": "A matrix of scatterplots can be produced using _________ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pears",
            "b) Pairs",
            "c) Tears",
            "d) Cars"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A matrix of scatterplots can be produced using pairs. Pairs function takes various parameters like formula, data, subset, labels, etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 383,
        "Question": "__________ function takes various parameters like formula, data, subset, labels, etc.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pears",
            "b) Pairs",
            "c) Tears",
            "d) Cars"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pairs function takes various parameters like formula, data, subset, labels, etc. A matrix of scatterplots can be produced using pairs. "
    },
    {
        "id": 384,
        "Question": "How will you check if an element is present in a vector?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Match()",
            "b) Dismatch()",
            "c) Mismatch()",
            "d) Search()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It can be done using the match () function- match () function returns the first appearance of a particular element. The other way is to use %in% which returns a Boolean value either true or false."
    },
    {
        "id": 385,
        "Question": "________ function is usually used inside another function and throws a warning whenever a particular package is not found.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dplyr",
            "b) Require",
            "c) Coin",
            "d) Sample"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Require () function is usually used inside the other function and gives a warning whenever a particular package is not found. Library () function will give an error message if the desired package is not loaded."
    },
    {
        "id": 386,
        "Question": "___________ function gives an error message if the desired package cannot be loaded.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dplyr",
            "b) Require",
            "c) Library",
            "d) Sample"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Library () function gives an error message if the desired package cannot be loaded. Require () function is usually used inside a function and throws a warning whenever a particular package is not found. "
    },
    {
        "id": 387,
        "Question": "A ________________ in R programming language can also contain numeric and alphabets along with special characters like dot and underline.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Variable name",
            "b) Number",
            "c) Integer",
            "d) Character"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A variable name in R programming language can also contain numeric and alphabets along with special characters like a dot and underline. Variable names in R language can begin with an alphabet and also the dot symbol."
    },
    {
        "id": 388,
        "Question": "The current user defined objects like lists, vectors, etc. is referred to as __________ in the R language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Work names",
            "b) Work space",
            "c) Environment",
            "d) Console"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The current R working environment of the user which has user defined objects like lists, vectors, etc. is referred to as Workspace in R language. The workspace of R is flexible to all functions of statistics."
    },
    {
        "id": 389,
        "Question": "Which function helps you perform sorting in R language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Order",
            "b) Inorder",
            "c) Simple",
            "d) Library"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Order returns a permutation which rearranges its first argument into ascending and also descending order. The result of the order command is a vector where each value references to the values of the position of the object in the original data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 390,
        "Question": "Which function is used to create a histogram for visualisation in R programming language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Library",
            "b) Hist",
            "c) Data",
            "d) Refer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Hist function is used to create a histogram for visualisation in R programming language. The generic function hist computes a histogram of the given data values. This function takes a vector as the input and also uses some more parameters to plot histograms."
    },
    {
        "id": 391,
        "Question": "Write the syntax to set the path of the current working directory in R environment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Setwd(“dipath”)",
            "b) Setwd(dir_path)",
            "c) Setwd(“dir_path”)",
            "d) Set(“dir_path”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The current R working environment of a user which has user-defined objects like lists, vectors, etc. is referred to as Workspace in R language. The workspace of R is flexible to all functions of statistics."
    },
    {
        "id": 392,
        "Question": "What will be the output of runif()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Random number",
            "b) Numbers",
            "c) Character",
            "d) Path generation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Random numbers from a normal distribution can be generated using runif() function. We can specify the range of the uniform distribution with the help of max and min argument. If not provided, the default range will be between 0 and 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 393,
        "Question": "________ function generates “n” normal random numbers based on the mean and standard deviation arguments passed to the function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rnorm",
            "b) vnorm",
            "c) knorm",
            "d) lnorm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rnorm function generates “n” normal random numbers based on the mean and standard deviation arguments passed to the function. The workspace of R is flexible to all functions of statistics."
    },
    {
        "id": 394,
        "Question": "Write a function to extract the first name in the string “Mrs. Jake Luther”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Substring",
            "b) Substr",
            "c) Substi",
            "d) Return"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The substr() function gives a part of a string. The substr() method will give parts of a string, beginning at the character of the specified position, and returns the specified number of characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 395,
        "Question": "_________ package provides basic functionalities in R environment like arithmetic calculations, input/output.",
        "Options": [
            "a) R base",
            "b) R boost",
            "c) R serve",
            "d) R comm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: R Base package is the package that is loaded by default whenever the R programming environment is loaded .R base package provides basic functionalities in R environment like arithmetic calculations, input/output."
    },
    {
        "id": 396,
        "Question": "Which function basically finds the intersection between two different sets of data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Converge",
            "b) Merge",
            "c) Delegate",
            "d) Swap"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Merge () function is used to combine two data frames and it identifies common rows or columns between the 2 data frames. Merge () function basically finds the intersection between two different sets of data."
    },
    {
        "id": 397,
        "Question": "Which function calculates the count of each category of a categorical variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table",
            "b) Intact",
            "c) Tables",
            "d) Retabs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The frequency distribution of a categorical variable can be checked using the table function in the R language. Table () function calculates the count of each category of a categorical variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 398,
        "Question": "The cumulative frequency distribution of a categorical variable can be checked using the ________ function in R language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sum",
            "b) Cumsum",
            "c) Lumpsum",
            "d) Resum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The cumulative frequency distribution of a categorical variable can be checked using the cumsum () function in the R language. The frequency distribution of a categorical variable can be checked using the table function in the R language."
    },
    {
        "id": 399,
        "Question": "A programmer builds a _________ to avoid repeating the same task or reduce complexity.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Function",
            "b) Package",
            "c) Code",
            "d) Console"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A function, in a programming environment, is a set of instructions. A programmer builds a function to avoid repeating the same task or reduce complexity. A function should be written to carry out specified tasks and may or may not include arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 400,
        "Question": "_________ is an indication that a fatal problem has occurred and execution of the function stops.",
        "Options": [
            "a) message",
            "b) error",
            "c) warning",
            "d) message & warning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Errors are produced by the stop() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) R has a number of ways to indicate to you that something’s not right",
            "b) Executing any function in R may result in the condition",
            "c) “condition” is a generic concept for indicating that something unexpected has occurred",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Programmers can create their own custom conditions if they want."
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "Question": "3. What would be the value of following R expression?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"kw2\">log</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Warning in log(-1): NaNs produced",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Null",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This warning lets you know that taking the log of a negative number results in a NaN value because you can’t take the log of negative numbers."
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "Question": "Warnings are generated by the _________ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) warning()",
            "b) error()",
            "c) run()",
            "d) message()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: warning is an indication that something is wrong but not necessarily fatal; execution of the function continues."
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) POSIX represents a portable operating system interface, primarily for UNIX systems",
            "b) There are different levels of indication that can be used, ranging from mere notification to fatal error",
            "c) The default input format for POSIX dates consists of the month, followed by the year and day, separated by slashes or dashes",
            "d) R don’t have any way to indicate to you that something’s not right"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Dates stored in the POSIX format are date/time values (like dates with the chron library), but also allow modification of time zones."
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> printmessage <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw2\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>         <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is greater than zero\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>         <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is less than or equal to zero\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw2\">invisible</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> printmessage<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Warning",
            "c) Messages",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function seems to work fine. No errors, warnings, or messages."
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "Question": "To get the current date, the _______ function will return a Date object which can be converted to a different class if necessary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sys.Time",
            "b) Sys.Date",
            "c) Sys.DateTime",
            "d) DateTime"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The POSIXlt class stores date/time values as a list of components (hour, min, sec, mon, etc.) making it easy to extract these parts."
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> printmessage <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw2\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>         <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is greater than zero\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>         <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is less than or equal to zero\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw2\">invisible</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> printmessage<span class=\"br0\">(</span>NA<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Warning",
            "c) Messages",
            "d) Null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can’t do that test if x is a NA or NaN value."
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following R code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw7\">lm</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> x <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw7\">lm</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) function(x) { x * x }",
            "b) func(x) { x * x }",
            "c) function(x) { x / x }",
            "d) function { x $ x }"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When R tries to bind a value to a symbol, it searches through a series of environments to find the appropriate value."
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The search list can be found by using the searchlist() function",
            "b) The search list can be found by using the search() function",
            "c) The global environment or the user’s workspace is always the second element of the search list",
            "d) R has separate namespaces for functions and non-functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Base package is always the last element."
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "Question": "A function, together with an environment, makes up what is called a ______ closure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) formal",
            "b) function",
            "c) reflective",
            "d) symmetry"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function closure model can be used to create functions that “carry around” data with them."
    },
    {
        "id": 411,
        "Question": "4. Which of the variable in the following R code is variable?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x, y<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>            x<span class=\"sy0\">^</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> z\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x",
            "b) y",
            "c) z",
            "d) yy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This function has 2 formal arguments x and y. In the body of the function there is another symbol z. In this case z is called a free variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 412,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The order of the packages on the search list does not matter",
            "b) R has separate namespaces for functions and non-functions",
            "c) Users can configure which packages get loaded on startup so if you are writing a function",
            "d) The search list can be found by using the search() function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The order of the packages on the search list matters, particularly if there are multiple objects with the same name in different packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 413,
        "Question": "R uses _________ scoping6 0 or static scoping.",
        "Options": [
            "a) reflective",
            "b) transitive",
            "c) lexical",
            "d) closure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Lexical scoping in R means that the values of free variables are searched for in the environment in which the function was defined."
    },
    {
        "id": 414,
        "Question": "The only environment without a parent is the ________ environment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) full",
            "b) half",
            "c) null",
            "d) empty"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Every environment has a parent environment and it is possible for an environment to have multiple “children”."
    },
    {
        "id": 415,
        "Question": "The ________ for R are the main feature that make it different from the original S language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) scoping rules",
            "b) closure rules",
            "c) environment rules",
            "d) closure & environment rules"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This function never actually uses the argument b, so calling f(2) will not produce an error because the 2 gets positionally matched to a."
    },
    {
        "id": 416,
        "Question": "The _________ function is a kind of “constructor function” that can be used to construct other functions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) make.pow()",
            "b) make.power()",
            "c) keep.power()",
            "d) keep.pow()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Typically, a function is defined in the global environment, so that the values of free variables are just found in the user’s workspace."
    },
    {
        "id": 417,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following R code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> g <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>             a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>             x<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>y\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>          <span class=\"co1\">## 'y' is a free variable</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 42",
            "c) 8",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Object ‘y’ not found error is displayed."
    },
    {
        "id": 418,
        "Question": "________ functions can be “built which contain all of the necessary data for evaluating the function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Objective",
            "b) reflective",
            "c) Nested",
            "d) Symmetry"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: However, an objective function that needs to be minimized might depend on a host of other things besides its parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 419,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dynamic scoping turns out to be particularly useful for simplifying statistical computations",
            "b) Lexical scoping turns out to be particularly useful for simplifying statistical computations",
            "c) The scoping rules of a language determine how values are assigned to free variables",
            "d) An environment is a collection of (symbol, value) pairs, i.e. x is a symbol and 3.14 might be its value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Free variables are not formal arguments and are not local variables (assigned inside the function body)."
    },
    {
        "id": 420,
        "Question": "Which of the following language supports lexical scoping?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Perl",
            "b) Python",
            "c) Common Lisp",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Lexical scoping in R has consequences beyond how free variables are looked up."
    },
    {
        "id": 421,
        "Question": "_________ require you to pass a function whose argument is a vector of parameters.",
        "Options": [
            "a) optimize()",
            "b) optimise()",
            "c) opt()",
            "d) opm()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Optimization routines in R like optim(), nlm(), and optimize() require you to pass a function."
    },
    {
        "id": 422,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) An environment is a collection of (symbol, value) pairs, i.e. x is a symbol and 3.14 might be its value",
            "b) If the value of a symbol is not found in the environment in which a function was defined, then the search is continued in the child environment",
            "c) After the top-level environment, the search continues down the search list until we hit the parent environment",
            "d) Dynamic scoping turns out to be particularly useful for simplifying statistical computations"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Every environment has a parent environment and it is possible for an environment to have multiple “children”."
    },
    {
        "id": 423,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n          params<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"sy0\">!</span>fixed<span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> p\n          mu <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> params<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n          sigma <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> params<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"co1\">## Calculate the Normal density</span>\n          a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">0.5</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw2\">length</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw8\">data</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw2\">log</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw2\">pi</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>sigma<span class=\"sy0\">^</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n          b <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">0.5</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw2\">sum</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>data<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>mu<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">^</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>sigma<span class=\"sy0\">^</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n          <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">ls</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">environment</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>nLL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “data” “fixed” “param”",
            "b) “data” “variable” “params”",
            "c) “data” “fixed” “params”",
            "d) “data” “param”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: nLL is one of the optimization functions in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 424,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> nLL <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> make.<span class=\"me1\">NegLogLik</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>normals, <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>FALSE, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw7\">optimize</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>nLL, <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>$minimum</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.217775",
            "b) 2.217775",
            "c) 3",
            "d) empty"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: optimize() function can be used rather than optim()."
    },
    {
        "id": 425,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> nLL <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> make.<span class=\"me1\">NegLogLik</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>normals, <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, FALSE<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw7\">optimize</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>nLL, <span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>1e<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>6, <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>$minimum</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.217775",
            "b) 1.800596",
            "c) 3.73424",
            "d) empty"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sigma is estimated by holding mu fixed at 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 426,
        "Question": "The _________ function is used to plot negative likelihood.",
        "Options": [
            "a) plot()",
            "b) graph()",
            "c) graph.plot()",
            "d) plot.graph()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For simple scatter plots, plot.default will be used."
    },
    {
        "id": 427,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> g <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>               a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>               x<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>y\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>             <span class=\"co1\">## 'y' is a free variable</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 42",
            "c) 8",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Here, y is defined in the global environment, which also happens to be where the function g() is defined."
    },
    {
        "id": 428,
        "Question": "________ loop over a list and evaluate a function on each element.",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply()",
            "b) lapply()",
            "c) sapply()",
            "d) mapply()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An auxiliary function split is also useful, particularly in conjunction with lapply."
    },
    {
        "id": 429,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Multi-line expressions with curly braces are just not that easy to sort through when working on the command line",
            "b) lappy() loops over a list, iterating over each element in that list",
            "c) lapply() does not always returns a list",
            "d) You cannot use lapply() to evaluate a function multiple times each with a different argument"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: lapply() always returns a list, regardless of the class of the input."
    },
    {
        "id": 430,
        "Question": "__________ function is same as lapply in R.",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply()",
            "b) lapply()",
            "c) sapply()",
            "d) mapply()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: lapply tries to simplify the result."
    },
    {
        "id": 431,
        "Question": "Which of the following is multivariate version of lapply?",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply()",
            "b) lapply()",
            "c) sapply()",
            "d) mapply()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The mapply() function is a multivariate apply of sorts which applies a function in parallel over a set of arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 432,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) lapply() takes elements of the list and passes them as the first argument of the function you are applying",
            "b) You can use lapply() to evaluate a function multiple times each with a different argument",
            "c) Functions that you pass to lapply() may have other arguments",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The lapply() function and its friends make heavy use of anonymous functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 433,
        "Question": "________ applies a function over the margins of an array.",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply()",
            "b) lapply()",
            "c) tapply()",
            "d) mapply()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The apply() function is used to a evaluate a function (often an anonymous one) over the margins of an array."
    },
    {
        "id": 434,
        "Question": "_______ is used to apply a function over subsets of a vector.",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply()",
            "b) lapply()",
            "c) tapply()",
            "d) mapply()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: t in tapply stands for table."
    },
    {
        "id": 435,
        "Question": "lappy functions takes _________ arguments in R language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) two",
            "b) three",
            "c) four",
            "d) five"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This function takes three arguments: (1) a list X; (2) a function (or the name of a function) FUN; (3) other arguments via its … argument."
    },
    {
        "id": 436,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The sapply() function behaves similarly to lapply()",
            "b) With multiple factors and many levels, creating an interaction can result in many levels that are empty",
            "c) apply() can be thought of as a combination of split() and sapply() for vectors only",
            "d) You can use tsplit() to evaluate a function single time each with a same argument"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: tapply() can be thought of as a combination of split() and sapply() for vectors only."
    },
    {
        "id": 437,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) split() takes elements of the list and passes them as the first argument of the function you are applying",
            "b) You can use tsplit() to evaluate a function single time each with a same argument",
            "c) Sequence of operations is sometimes referred to as “map-reduce”",
            "d) apply() can be thought of as a combination of split() and sapply() for vectors only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The results of applying the function over the subsets are then collated and returned as an object."
    },
    {
        "id": 438,
        "Question": "The _____ function takes a vector or other objects and splits it into groups determined by a factor or list of factors.",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply()",
            "b) lsplit()",
            "c) split()",
            "d) mapply()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The combination of split() and a function like lapply() or sapply() is a common paradigm in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 439,
        "Question": "Which of the following is valid body of split function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) function (x, f)",
            "b) function (x, drop = FALSE, …)",
            "c) function (x, f, drop = FALSE, …)",
            "d) function (drop = FALSE, …)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: x is a vector (or list) or data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 440,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following R expression?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\">  <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">log</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2.3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Warning in log(-2.3): NaNs produced",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Null",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This warning lets you know that taking the log of a negative number results in a NaN value because you can’t take the log of negative numbers."
    },
    {
        "id": 441,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vectorizing the function can be accomplished easily with the Vectorize() function",
            "b) There are different levels of indication that can be used, ranging from mere notification to fatal error",
            "c) Vectorizing the function can be accomplished easily with the vector() function",
            "d) Warnings are generated by the run() function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Vectorize() function does not preserve the invisibility of the return value."
    },
    {
        "id": 442,
        "Question": "What will be the value of following R expression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Warning in log(c(-1, 2)): NaNs produced",
            "b) Error in log(c(-1, 2)): NaNs produced",
            "c) Message",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Warning is produced due to negative values."
    },
    {
        "id": 443,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> printmessage2 <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                      <span class=\"kw2\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">is.<span class=\"me1\">na</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                              <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is a missing value!\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                      <span class=\"kw1\">else</span> <span class=\"kw2\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                              <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is greater than zero\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                      <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                              <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is less than or equal to zero\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                      <span class=\"kw2\">invisible</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> printmessage2<span class=\"br0\">(</span>NA<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “x is a missing value!”",
            "b) “x is greater than zero”",
            "c) “x is less than or equal to zero”",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We can fix Missing value problem by anticipating the possibility of NA values and checking to see if the input is NA with the is.na() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 444,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> printmessage <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;-</span> <span class=\"kw2\">function</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                      <span class=\"kw2\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                           <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is greater than zero\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                      <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                           <span class=\"kw2\">print</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is less than or equal to zero\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>                      <span class=\"kw2\">invisible</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> printmessage<span class=\"br0\">(</span>NA<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Warning",
            "c) Messages",
            "d) x is greater than zero"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can’t do that test if x is a NA or NaN value."
    },
    {
        "id": 445,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">mean</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n  Error <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"kw2\">mean</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> object <span class=\"st0\">'x'</span> not found\n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">traceback</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1: mean(x)",
            "b) Null",
            "c) 0",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The traceback() function shows you how many levels deep you were when the error occurred."
    },
    {
        "id": 446,
        "Question": "The recover() function will first print out the function call stack when an _______ occurs.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Warning",
            "c) Messages",
            "d) delete"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When you choose a frame number, you will be put in the browse and will have the ability to poke around."
    },
    {
        "id": 447,
        "Question": "__________ prints out the function call stack after an error occurs.",
        "Options": [
            "a) trace()",
            "b) traceback()",
            "c) back()",
            "d) traback()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: traceback() does nothing if there’s no error. trace() Interactive tracing and debugging of calls to a function or method."
    },
    {
        "id": 448,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The primary task of debugging any R code is correctly diagnosing what the problem is",
            "b) R provides only two tools to help you with debugging your code",
            "c) print statement can be used for debugging purpose",
            "d) The traceback() function must be called immediately after an error occurs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R provides a number of tools to help you with debugging your code."
    },
    {
        "id": 449,
        "Question": "Which of the following is primary tool for debugging?",
        "Options": [
            "a) debug()",
            "b) trace()",
            "c) browser()",
            "d) traceback()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Primary tools are mainly used for debugging R code."
    },
    {
        "id": 450,
        "Question": "________ allows you to insert debugging code into a function a specific places",
        "Options": [
            "a) debug()",
            "b) trace()",
            "c) browser()",
            "d) traceback()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function call stack is the sequence of functions that was called before the error occurred."
    },
    {
        "id": 451,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The traceback() function must be called immediately after an error occurs",
            "b) The debugger calls the browser at the very low level of the function body",
            "c) Every time you call the mod() function it will launch the interactive debugger",
            "d) R provides only two tools to help you with debugging your code"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Once another function is called, you lose the traceback."
    },
    {
        "id": 452,
        "Question": "_______ allows you to modify the error behavior so that you can browse the function call stack",
        "Options": [
            "a) debug()",
            "b) trace()",
            "c) recover()",
            "d) traceback()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The recover() function can be used to modify the error behavior of R when an error occurs."
    },
    {
        "id": 453,
        "Question": "______ suspends the execution of a function wherever it is called and puts the function in debug mode.",
        "Options": [
            "a) debug()",
            "b) trace()",
            "c) recover()",
            "d) browser()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The debug() function initiates an interactive debugger (also known as the “browser” in R) for a function."
    },
    {
        "id": 454,
        "Question": "debug() flags a function for ______ mode in R mode.",
        "Options": [
            "a) debug",
            "b) run",
            "c) compile",
            "d) recover"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: debug() allows you to step through execution of a function one line at a time."
    },
    {
        "id": 455,
        "Question": "________ generate random Normal variates with a given mean and standard deviation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dnorm",
            "b) rnorm",
            "c) pnorm",
            "d) rpois"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The “r” function is the one that actually simulates random numbers from that distribution."
    },
    {
        "id": 456,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) R comes with a set of pseudo-random number generators",
            "b) Random number generators cannot be used to model random inputs",
            "c) Statistical procedure does not require random number generation",
            "d) For each probability distribution there are typically three functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: R allows you to simulate from well known probability distributions like the Normal, Poisson, and binomial."
    },
    {
        "id": 457,
        "Question": "______ evaluate the cumulative distribution function for a Normal distribution.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dnorm",
            "b) rnorm",
            "c) pnorm",
            "d) rpois"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: p stands for cumulative distribution."
    },
    {
        "id": 458,
        "Question": "_______ generate random Poisson variates with a given rate.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dnorm",
            "b) rnorm",
            "c) pnorm",
            "d) rpois"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: q stands for quantile function (inverse cumulative distribution)."
    },
    {
        "id": 459,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) For each probability distribution there are typically three functions",
            "b) For each probability distribution there are typically four functions",
            "c) r function is sufficient for simulating random numbers",
            "d) R comes with a set of pseudo-random number generators"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are typically four functions available that start with a “r”, “d”, “p”, and “q”."
    },
    {
        "id": 460,
        "Question": "Which of the following evaluate the Normal probability density (with a given mean/SD) at a point?",
        "Options": [
            "a) dnorm",
            "b) rnorm",
            "c) pnorm",
            "d) rpois"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: That point can be a vector of points."
    },
    {
        "id": 461,
        "Question": "_________ is the most common probability distribution to work with.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Gaussian",
            "b) Parametric",
            "c) Paradox",
            "d) Simulation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Working with the Normal distributions requires using four functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 462,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"kw7\">pnorm</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.9772499",
            "b) 1.9772499",
            "c) 0.6772499",
            "d) 2.6772499"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: We can modify the default parameters to simulate numbers with mean 20 and standard deviation 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 463,
        "Question": "_________ ensures reproducibility of the sequence of random numbers.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sets.seed()",
            "b) set.seed()",
            "c) set.seedvalue()",
            "d) set.value()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Setting the random number seed with set.seed() ensures reproducibility of the sequence of random numbers."
    },
    {
        "id": 464,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) When simulating any random numbers it is not essential to set the random number seed",
            "b) It is not possible to generate random numbers from other probability distributions like the Poisson",
            "c) You should always set the random number seed when conducting a simulation",
            "d) Statistical procedure does not require random number generation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Otherwise, you will not be able to reconstruct the exact numbers that you produced in an analysis."
    },
    {
        "id": 465,
        "Question": "5 Normal random numbers can be generated with rnorm() by setting seed value to ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: set.seed(1) will give 5 normal random numbers."
    },
    {
        "id": 466,
        "Question": "_______ function is used to simulate binary random variables.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dnorm",
            "b) rbinom()",
            "c) binom()",
            "d) rpois"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: rbinom() is used to simulate a predictor variable x that is binary instead of having a Normal distribution."
    },
    {
        "id": 467,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Drawing samples from specific probability distributions can be done with “s” functions",
            "b) The sample() function draws randomly from a specified set of (scalar) objects allowing you to sample from arbitrary distributions of numbers",
            "c) The sampling() function draws randomly from a specified set of objects",
            "d) You should always set the random number seed when conducting a simulation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The sample() function can be used to draw random samples from arbitrary vectors."
    },
    {
        "id": 468,
        "Question": "__________ distribution is commonly used to model data that come in the form of counts.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Gaussian",
            "b) Parametric",
            "c) Poisson",
            "d) Simulation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It is possible to generate random numbers from other probability distributions like the Poisson."
    },
    {
        "id": 469,
        "Question": "Which of the following code represents count with mean of 2?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rpois(10, 2)",
            "b) rpois(10, 20)",
            "c) rpois(20, 2)",
            "d) rpois(20, 20)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rpois(10, 20) give counts with a mean of 20."
    },
    {
        "id": 470,
        "Question": "________ is a systematic way to examine how much time is spent in different parts of a program.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Profiling",
            "b) Monitoring",
            "c) Logging",
            "d) Debugging"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sometimes profiling becomes necessary as a project grows and layers of code are placed on top of each other."
    },
    {
        "id": 471,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The Rprofiler() function starts the profiler in R",
            "b) Using system.time() allows you to test certain functions or code blocks to see if they are taking excessive amounts of time",
            "c) R must not be compiled with profiler support",
            "d) Rprofiler() tabulates how much time is spent inside each function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: However, this approach assumes that you already know where the problem is and can call system.time() on it that piece of code."
    },
    {
        "id": 472,
        "Question": "R comes with a ________ to help you optimize your code and improve its performance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) debugger",
            "b) monitor",
            "c) browser",
            "d) profiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In general, it’s usually a bad idea to focus on optimizing your code at the very beginning of development."
    },
    {
        "id": 473,
        "Question": "The _______ function computes the time (in seconds) needed to execute an expression.",
        "Options": [
            "a) system.timedeb()",
            "b) system.time()",
            "c) system.datetime()",
            "d) system.deb()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: They system.time() function takes an arbitrary R expression as input and returns the amount of time taken to evaluate the expression."
    },
    {
        "id": 474,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rprofiler() tabulates how much time is spent inside each function",
            "b) Rprof() keeps track of the function call stack at regularly sampled intervals",
            "c) By default, the profiler samples the function call stack every 2 seconds",
            "d) R must not be compiled with profiler support"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The profiler is started by calling the Rprof() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 475,
        "Question": "system.time function returns an object of class _______ which contains two useful bits of information.",
        "Options": [
            "a) debug_time",
            "b) proc_time",
            "c) procedure_time",
            "d) date.time_time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: if there’s an error, gives the time until the error occurred."
    },
    {
        "id": 476,
        "Question": "_________ time is time charged to the CPU(s) for the R expression.",
        "Options": [
            "a) elapsed",
            "b) user",
            "c) response",
            "d) monitor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Usually, the user time and elapsed time are relatively close, for straight computing tasks."
    },
    {
        "id": 477,
        "Question": "The elapsed time may be ________ than the user time if your machine has multiple cores/processors.",
        "Options": [
            "a) smaller",
            "b) greater",
            "c) equal to",
            "d) null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The elapsed time may be greater than the user time if the CPU spends a lot of time waiting around."
    },
    {
        "id": 478,
        "Question": "Parallel processing is done via __________ package can make the elapsed time smaller than the user time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) parallel",
            "b) statistics",
            "c) distributed",
            "d) symmetry"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When you have multiple processors/- cores/machines working in parallel, the amount of time that the collection of CPUs spends working on a problem is the same as with a single CPU, but because they are operating in parallel, there is a savings in elapsed time."
    },
    {
        "id": 479,
        "Question": "You can time ________ expressions by wrapping them in curly braces within the call to system.time().",
        "Options": [
            "a) smaller",
            "b) longer",
            "c) error",
            "d) grater"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If your expression is getting pretty long (more than 2 or 3 lines), it might be better to either break it into smaller pieces or to use the profiler."
    },
    {
        "id": 480,
        "Question": "The profiler can be turned off by passing _________ to Rprof().",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) NULL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Rprof(NULL) is used to turn off the profiler."
    },
    {
        "id": 481,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rprof() is used to turn off the profiler",
            "b) At each line of the output, the profiler writes out the function call stack",
            "c) The summaryprof() function tabulates the R profiler output",
            "d) The Rprofiler() function starts the profiler in R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Rprofiler() function starts the profiler in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 482,
        "Question": "How many methods exist for normalizing the data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) one",
            "b) two",
            "c) three",
            "d) profiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are two methods for normalizing the data."
    },
    {
        "id": 483,
        "Question": "_______ divides the time spend in each function by the total run time",
        "Options": [
            "a) “by.sum”",
            "b) “by.total”",
            "c) “by.self”",
            "d) “by.del”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: “by.self” does the same as “by.total”."
    },
    {
        "id": 484,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) “by.total” first subtracts out time spent in functions above the current function in the call stack",
            "b) The summaryRprof() function calculates how much time is spend in which function",
            "c) By default, the profiler samples the function call stack every 0.02 seconds",
            "d) The Rprofiler() function starts the profiler in R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Output of by.self is more useful than by.total for interpreting the data."
    },
    {
        "id": 485,
        "Question": "Which of the following function actually fits the linear model?",
        "Options": [
            "a) lm.time()",
            "b) lm.date()",
            "c) lm.fit()",
            "d) lm.interval()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: lm() function does a bit of pre-processing and checking before it actually fits the model."
    },
    {
        "id": 486,
        "Question": "The final bit of output that summaryRprof() provides is the ______ interval and the total runtime.",
        "Options": [
            "a) response",
            "b) sampling",
            "c) processing",
            "d) retrieve"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You’re going to be spending a lot of time in preprocessing and checking."
    },
    {
        "id": 487,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement gives sampling interval?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $sampling.interval",
            "b) $sampling.time",
            "c) $sampling.date",
            "d) $sampling.datetime"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sampling time is expressed in secs."
    },
    {
        "id": 488,
        "Question": "Which of the following code is not profiled?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) C++",
            "c) Java",
            "d) PHP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: C or Fortran code is not profiled."
    },
    {
        "id": 489,
        "Question": "_______ grammar makes a clear distinction between your data and what gets displayed on the screen or page.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ggplot1",
            "b) ggplot2",
            "c) d3.js",
            "d) ggplot3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The emphasis in ggplot2 is reducing the amount of thinking time by making it easier to go from the plot in your brain to the plot on the page."
    },
    {
        "id": 490,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mean_se is used to calculate mean and standard errors on either side",
            "b) hmisc wraps up a selection of summary functions from Hmisc to make it easy to use",
            "c) plot is used to create a scatterplot matrix (experimental)",
            "d) translate_qplot_base is used for translating between qplot and base graphics"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: plotmatrix is used to create a scatterplot matrix (experimental)."
    },
    {
        "id": 491,
        "Question": "Which of the following cuts numeric vector into intervals of equal length?",
        "Options": [
            "a) cut_interval",
            "b) cut_time",
            "c) cut_number",
            "d) cut_date"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: cut_number cuts numeric vector into intervals containing equal number of points."
    },
    {
        "id": 492,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a plot to investigate the order in which observations were recorded?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ggplot",
            "b) ggsave",
            "c) ggpcp",
            "d) ggorder"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ggsave save a ggplot with sensible defaults."
    },
    {
        "id": 493,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) theme_minimal is minimalistic theme with no background annotations",
            "b) theme_color is classic-looking theme, with x and y axis lines and no gridlines",
            "c) theme_classic is a classic-looking theme",
            "d) translate_qplot_base is used for translating between qplot and base graphics"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: theme_classic is a classic-looking theme, with x and y axis lines and no gridlines."
    },
    {
        "id": 494,
        "Question": "________ is used for translating between qplot and base graphics.",
        "Options": [
            "a) translate_qplot_base",
            "b) translate_qplot_gpl",
            "c) translate_qplot_lattice",
            "d) translate_qplot_ggplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: translate_qplot_gpl is used for translating between qplot and Graphics Production Library (GPL)."
    },
    {
        "id": 495,
        "Question": "__________ modifies geom/stat aesthetic defaults for future plots.",
        "Options": [
            "a) translate_qplot_base",
            "b) translate_qplot_gpl",
            "c) translate_qplot_defaults",
            "d) translate_qplot_ggplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: translate_qplot_gpl is used for translating between qplot and Graphics Production Library (GPL)."
    },
    {
        "id": 496,
        "Question": "Which of the following is discrete state calculator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) discrete_scale",
            "b) ggpcp",
            "c) ggfluctuation",
            "d) ggmissing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ggpcp is used to create a parallel coordinate plot."
    },
    {
        "id": 497,
        "Question": "Which of the following creates fluctuation plot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ggmissplot",
            "b) ggmissing",
            "c) ggfluctuation",
            "d) ggpcp"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Fluctuations are used to detect outliers."
    },
    {
        "id": 498,
        "Question": "________ is used to create a plot to illustrate patterns of missing values.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ggmissplot",
            "b) ggmissing",
            "c) ggfluctuation",
            "d) ggpcp"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The missing values plot is a useful tool to get a rapid overview of the number and pattern of missing values in a dataset."
    },
    {
        "id": 499,
        "Question": "_________ generate aesthetic mappings that describe how variables in the data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) aes_all",
            "b) aes_auto",
            "c) aes",
            "d) aes_string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: aes generate aesthetic mappings that describe how variables in the data. aes_auto is used for automatic aesthetic mapping."
    },
    {
        "id": 500,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) update_element update contents of a theme",
            "b) Use theme_update_element to modify a small number of elements of the current theme or use theme_set to completely override it",
            "c) theme_bw is theme with grey background and white gridlines",
            "d) is.rel reports whether x is a theme object"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: update_element function is deprecated. Use %+replace% or +.gg instead."
    },
    {
        "id": 501,
        "Question": "______ generate aesthetic mappings from a string.",
        "Options": [
            "a) aes_all",
            "b) aes_auto",
            "c) aes_string",
            "d) aes_position"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Aesthetic mappings describe how variables in the data are mapped to visual properties (aesthetics) of geoms."
    },
    {
        "id": 502,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a differentiation related aesthetic?",
        "Options": [
            "a) aes_position",
            "b) aes_group_order",
            "c) aes_linetype_size_shape",
            "d) ggorder"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: aes_position is position related aesthetics."
    },
    {
        "id": 503,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) is.rel reports whether x is a theme object",
            "b) is.theme reports whether x is a theme object",
            "c) opts build a theme (or partial theme) from theme elements",
            "d) theme_bw is theme with grey background and white gridlines"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: is.rel reports whether x is a real object."
    },
    {
        "id": 504,
        "Question": "________ modify a ggplot or theme object by adding on new components.",
        "Options": [
            "a) +.gg",
            "b) -.gg",
            "c) /.gg",
            "d) .gg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This operator allows you to add objects to a ggplot or theme object."
    },
    {
        "id": 505,
        "Question": "__________ create a complete ggplot appropriate to a particular data type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) autoplot",
            "b) is.ggplot",
            "c) printplot",
            "d) qplot_ggplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: autoplot uses ggplot2 to draw a particular plot for an object of a particular class in a single command. "
    },
    {
        "id": 506,
        "Question": "Which of the following creates a new ggplot plot from a data frame?",
        "Options": [
            "a) qplot_ggplot",
            "b) ggplot.data.frame",
            "c) ggfluctuation",
            "d) ggmissplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Default list of aesthetic mappings are displayed."
    },
    {
        "id": 507,
        "Question": "Which of the following draws plot on current graphics device?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ggmissplot",
            "b) printplot",
            "c) print.ggplot",
            "d) ggfluctuation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: print.ggplot is also known as plot.ggplot."
    },
    {
        "id": 508,
        "Question": "________ is used for relative sizing of theme elements.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rel",
            "b) size",
            "c) relative",
            "d) timrinterval"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The syntax for rel is rel(X) where x is a number representing the relative size."
    },
    {
        "id": 509,
        "Question": "_________ display contours of a 3d surface in 2d.",
        "Options": [
            "a) aes_contour",
            "b) geom_contour",
            "c) aes_gem",
            "d) aes_auto"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A layer specific dataset – only needed if you want to override the plot defaults."
    },
    {
        "id": 510,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) autoplotgraph is used to complete ggplot appropriate to a particular data type",
            "b) auto_element wraps up a projection of summary functions",
            "c) ggplot.data create a new ggplot plot from a data frame",
            "d) aes_sdensity display a smooth density estimate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: is.ggplot reports whether x is a ggplot object."
    },
    {
        "id": 511,
        "Question": "______ display a smooth density estimate.",
        "Options": [
            "a) geom_density2",
            "b) geom_density",
            "c) aes_sdensity",
            "d) geom_contour"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: geom_density display a smooth density estimate. A smooth density estimate calculated by stat_density."
    },
    {
        "id": 512,
        "Question": "Which of the following draws nothing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) geom_blank",
            "b) geom",
            "c) geom_bin2d",
            "d) geom_contour"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: geom_bin2d adds heatmap of 2d bin counts."
    },
    {
        "id": 513,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) is.theme reports whether x is a real object",
            "b) is.object reports whether x is a aesthetic object",
            "c) qplot is used for quick plot",
            "d) ggplot describe the type of plot you will produce"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: is.rel reports whether x is a real object."
    },
    {
        "id": 514,
        "Question": "_________ describe the type of plot you will produce.",
        "Options": [
            "a) geoms",
            "b) ggplot",
            "c) fplot",
            "d) gplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Geoms is short form for geometric objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 515,
        "Question": "__________ is interval represented by a vertical line, with a point in the middle.",
        "Options": [
            "a) geom_range",
            "b) geom_pointrange",
            "c) printplot",
            "d) geom_contour"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: autoplot uses ggplot2 to draw a particular plot for an object of a particular class in a single command. "
    },
    {
        "id": 516,
        "Question": "Which of the following create a set of identity mappings?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ggplot",
            "b) aes_all",
            "c) aes",
            "d) ggorder"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Character vector is given for the creation of identity."
    },
    {
        "id": 517,
        "Question": "_________  is new package that makes it easy to “tidy” your data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) tidy",
            "b) tidyr",
            "c) tidyneat",
            "d) tidynr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Tidy data is data that’s easy to work in R."
    },
    {
        "id": 518,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Each row is an observation in tidy data",
            "b) Each column is a variable in tidy data",
            "c) Arranging your data in tidy way makes it easier to work",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: When use tidy data and tidy tools, you spend less time worrying about how to feed the output from one function into the input of another."
    },
    {
        "id": 519,
        "Question": "Which of the following is complementary to tidyr?",
        "Options": [
            "a) geolr",
            "b) dplyr",
            "c) d3lr",
            "d) gekl2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Its easy to munge with dplyr."
    },
    {
        "id": 520,
        "Question": "How many functions exist for tidying the data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) one",
            "b) two",
            "c) three",
            "d) four"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: tidyr provides three main functions for tidying your messy data: gather(), separate() and spread()."
    },
    {
        "id": 521,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) gather() makes “wide” data longer",
            "b) Two functions are present for tidy data",
            "c) separate() makes “wide” data longer",
            "d) spread() function takes multiple columns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Other names for gather include melt (reshape2), pivot (spreadsheets) and fold (databases)."
    },
    {
        "id": 522,
        "Question": "Which of the following function takes multiple columns?",
        "Options": [
            "a) spread()",
            "b) gather()",
            "c) separate()",
            "d) extract()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: gather() gathers column into key-value pairs."
    },
    {
        "id": 523,
        "Question": "__________  uses regex groups instead of a splitting pattern or position.",
        "Options": [
            "a) spread()",
            "b) gather()",
            "c) separate()",
            "d) extract()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: separate() allows you to tease columns apart."
    },
    {
        "id": 524,
        "Question": "Which of the following function works similar to separate()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) extract()",
            "b) gather()",
            "c) sep()",
            "d) separate()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: extract() works in a similar way."
    },
    {
        "id": 525,
        "Question": "Which of the following d takes two columns and spreads them into multiple columns?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ggmissplot",
            "b) printplot",
            "c) print.ggplot",
            "d) ggplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: spread() makes “long” data wide."
    },
    {
        "id": 526,
        "Question": "__________ is used when you have variables that form rows instead of columns.",
        "Options": [
            "a) tidy()",
            "b) spread()",
            "c) separate()",
            "d) gather()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You need spread() less frequently than gather() or separate()."
    },
    {
        "id": 527,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) tidyr and dplyr packages do not make use of the pipe operator",
            "b) tidyr does less than reshape2",
            "c) tidyr provides ability to string multiple functions together by incorporating %",
            "d) tidyr does greater than reshape2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Just as reshape2 did less than reshape, tidyr does less than reshape2."
    },
    {
        "id": 528,
        "Question": "Which of the following merges two variables into one?",
        "Options": [
            "a) spread()",
            "b) gather()",
            "c) separate()",
            "d) unite()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The unite() function is a convenience function to paste together multiple variable values into one."
    },
    {
        "id": 529,
        "Question": "How many functions exist for wrangling the data with dplyr package?",
        "Options": [
            "a) one",
            "b) seven",
            "c) three",
            "d) five"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: dplyr provides seven main functions for tidying your messy data."
    },
    {
        "id": 530,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) gather() makes “long” data wider",
            "b) tidyr is a reframing of reshape designed to accompany the tidy data framework",
            "c) there are two fundamental verbs of data tidying",
            "d) tidyr and dplyr packages do not make use of the pipe operator"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In particular, built-in methods only work for data frames, and tidyr provides no margins or aggregation."
    },
    {
        "id": 531,
        "Question": "________ add new variables/columns or transform existing variables.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mutate",
            "b) add",
            "c) apped",
            "d) arrange"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: arrange is used to reorder rows of a data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 532,
        "Question": "_________ extract a subset of rows from a data frame based on logical conditions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rename",
            "b) filter",
            "c) set",
            "d) subset"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rename is used to rename variables in a data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 533,
        "Question": "Spread function is known as ___________ in spreadsheets.",
        "Options": [
            "a) pivot",
            "b) unpivot",
            "c) cast",
            "d) order"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Spread is known by other names in other places: it’s cast in reshape2, unpivot in spreadsheets and unfold in databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 534,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a principle of analytic graphics?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Don’t plot more than two variables at at time",
            "b) Make judicious use of color in your scatterplots",
            "c) Show box plots (univariate summaries)",
            "d) Show causality, mechanism, explanation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Only do what your tools allow you to do."
    },
    {
        "id": 535,
        "Question": "What is the role of exploratory graphs in data analysis?",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are made for formal presentations",
            "b) They are typically made very quickly",
            "c) Axes, legends, and other details are clean and exactly detailed",
            "d) They are used in place of formal modeling"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: EDA is used to summarize main characteristic of data."
    },
    {
        "id": 536,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about the base plotting system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Margins and spacings are adjusted automatically depending on the type of plot and the data",
            "b) Plots are typically created with a single function call",
            "c) Plots are created and annotated with separate functions",
            "d) The system is most useful for conditioning plots"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Functions like ‘plot’ or ‘hist’ typically create the plot on the graphics device and functions like ‘lines’, ‘text’, or ‘points’ will annotate or add data\nto the plot."
    },
    {
        "id": 537,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an example of a valid graphics device in R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A socket connection",
            "b) A Microsoft Word document",
            "c) A PDF file",
            "d) A file folder"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: PNG file is also valid graphics device."
    },
    {
        "id": 538,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an example of a vector graphics device in R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) JPEG",
            "b) PNG",
            "c) GIF",
            "d) SVG"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SVG stands for scalable vector graphics."
    },
    {
        "id": 539,
        "Question": "Bitmapped file formats can be most useful for ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plots that may need to be resized",
            "b) Plots that require animation or interactivity",
            "c) Plots that are not scaled to a specific resolution",
            "d) Scatterplots with many many points"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Scatterplots would be used frequently for particular dimension."
    },
    {
        "id": 540,
        "Question": "Which of the following functions is typically used to add elements to a plot in the base graphics system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) lines()",
            "b) hist()",
            "c) plot()",
            "d) boxplot()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: text() also can be used to add elements to a plot. boxplot() used to add elements to a plot in the base graphics system."
    },
    {
        "id": 541,
        "Question": "Which function opens the screen graphics device for the Mac?",
        "Options": [
            "a) bitmap()",
            "b) quartz()",
            "c) pdf()",
            "d) png()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: quartz starts a graphics device driver for the Mac."
    },
    {
        "id": 542,
        "Question": "What does the ‘pch’ option to par() control?",
        "Options": [
            "a) the size of the plotting symbol in a scatterplot",
            "b) the line width in the base graphics system",
            "c) the orientation of the axis labels on the plot",
            "d) the plotting symbol/character in the base graphics system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: R makes it easy to combine multiple plots into one overall graph, using either the par ( ) or layout( ) function."
    },
    {
        "id": 543,
        "Question": "If I want to save a plot to a PDF file, which of the following is a correct way of doing that?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Construct the plot on the screen device and then copy it to a PDF file with dev.copy2pdf()",
            "b) Construct the plot on the PNG device with png(), then copy it to a PDF with dev.copy2pdf()",
            "c) Open the PostScript device with postscript(), construct the plot, then close the device with dev.off()",
            "d) Open the screen device with quartz(), construct the plot, and then close the device with dev.off()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: With the par( ) function, you can include the option mfrow=c(nrows, ncols) to create a matrix of nrows x ncols plots that are filled in by row."
    },
    {
        "id": 544,
        "Question": "__________ produces box-and-whisker plots.",
        "Options": [
            "a) xyplot",
            "b) dotplot",
            "c) barchart",
            "d) bwplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Bwplot plots a series of vertical box-and-whisker plots where the individual boxplots represent the data subdivided by the value of some factor. Optionally the y-axis may be scaled logarithmically. Dotplot produces Cleveland dot plots. Barchart produces bar plots."
    },
    {
        "id": 545,
        "Question": "__________ produces bivariate scatterplots or time-series plots.",
        "Options": [
            "a) xyplot",
            "b) dotplot",
            "c) barchart",
            "d) bwplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: xyplot has points that show the relationship between two sets of data. Optionally the y-axis may be scaled logarithmically. dotplot produces Cleveland dot plots. barchart produces bar plots."
    },
    {
        "id": 546,
        "Question": "Annotation of plots in any plotting system involves adding points, lines, or text to the plot, in addition to customizing axis labels or adding titles. Different plotting systems have different sets of functions for annotating plots in this way. Which of the following functions can be used to annotate the panels in a multi-panel lattice plot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) points()",
            "b) panel.abline()",
            "c) lines()",
            "d) axis()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: panel.abline() is one of the most used panel function."
    },
    {
        "id": 547,
        "Question": "____________ produces one-dimensional scatterplots.",
        "Options": [
            "a) xyplot",
            "b) stripplot",
            "c) barchart",
            "d) bwplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This function along with other high-level Lattice functions, respond to a common set of arguments. "
    },
    {
        "id": 548,
        "Question": "which of the following functions can be used to finely control the appearance of all lattice plots ?",
        "Options": [
            "a) par()",
            "b) print.trellis()",
            "c) splom()",
            "d) trellis.par.set()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All high-level function in lattice are generic."
    },
    {
        "id": 549,
        "Question": "What is ggplot2 an implementation of?",
        "Options": [
            "a) the Grammar of Graphics developed by Leland Wilkinson",
            "b) 3D visualization system",
            "c) the S language originally developed by Bell Labs",
            "d) the base plotting system in R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ggplot2 package, created by Hadley Wickham, offers a powerful graphics language for creating elegant and complex plots."
    },
    {
        "id": 550,
        "Question": "For barchart and _________ non-trivial methods exist for tables and arrays, documented at barchart.table.",
        "Options": [
            "a) scatterplot",
            "b) dotplot",
            "c) xyplot",
            "d) scatterplot & xyplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The numeric methods are equivalent to a call with no left hand side and no conditioning variables in the formula. "
    },
    {
        "id": 551,
        "Question": "What is a geom in the ggplot2 system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) a plotting object like point, line, or other shape",
            "b) a method for making conditioning plots",
            "c) a method for mapping data to attributes like color and size",
            "d) a statistical transformation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The bar geom is used to produce 1d area plots."
    },
    {
        "id": 552,
        "Question": "Logical flag is applicable to which of the following plots?",
        "Options": [
            "a) scatterplot",
            "b) dotplot",
            "c) xyplot",
            "d) zyplot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Logical flag applicable to bwplot, dotplot, barchart, and stripplot."
    },
    {
        "id": 553,
        "Question": "___________ is used to determine what is plotted for each group.",
        "Options": [
            "a) panel.expose",
            "b) panel.impose",
            "c) panel.superpose",
            "d) panel.depose"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: panel.superpose can be combined with different panel.groups functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 554,
        "Question": "Which of the following code create n samples of size “size” with probability prob from the binomial?",
        "Options": [
            "a) z <- rinom(n,size,prob)",
            "b) z <- rbinom(n,size,prob)",
            "c) z <- binom(n,size,prob)",
            "d) z >- nom(n,size,prob)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To use the rbinom() function, you need to define three parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 555,
        "Question": "Which of the following code create a n item vector of random normal deviates?",
        "Options": [
            "a) x1 <- c(snorm(n))",
            "b) x1 <- c(pnorm(n))",
            "c) x1 <- c(rnorm(n))",
            "d) x1 >- c(norm(n))"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: rnorm generates random deviates."
    },
    {
        "id": 556,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement can read csv files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) read.table(filename,header=TRUE,sep=’,’)",
            "b) read.csv(filename,header=TRUE,sep=’,’)",
            "c) read.tab(filename,header=TRUE,sep=’,’)",
            "d) read.tab(filename,header=False,sep=’,’)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Each row of the table appears as one line of the file."
    },
    {
        "id": 557,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement read a tab or space delimited file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) read.table(filename,header=TRUE)",
            "b) read.CSV(filename,header=TRUE)",
            "c) read.table(filename,header=FALSE)",
            "d) read.tableall(filename,header=TRUE)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: read.csv and read.csv2 are identical to read.table except for the defaults."
    },
    {
        "id": 558,
        "Question": "which of the following statement chose those objects meeting a logical criterion?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sub(dataset,logical)",
            "b) subset(dataset,logical)",
            "c) subsetcon(dataset,logical)",
            "d) subcon(dataset,logical)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R subsetting operators are powerful and fast."
    },
    {
        "id": 559,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is another way to get a subset?",
        "Options": [
            "a) subsetcon(dataset,logical)",
            "b) data.df[data.df=logical] ",
            "c) sub(dataset,logical)",
            "d) subcon(dataset,logical)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: subset(data.df,select=variables,logical) get those objects from a data frame that meet a criterion."
    },
    {
        "id": 560,
        "Question": "Which of the following sort a dataframe by the order of the elements in B?",
        "Options": [
            "a) x[rev(order(x$B)),] ",
            "b) x[ordersort(x$B),] ",
            "c) x[order(x$B),] ",
            "d) x[rev(x$B),]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: x[rev(order(x$B)),] sort the dataframe in reverse order."
    },
    {
        "id": 561,
        "Question": "Which of the following is Mac menu command?",
        "Options": [
            "a) browse.workspace",
            "b) browse.works",
            "c) browser.workspace",
            "d) a statistical transformation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is a Mac menu command that creates a window with information about all variables in the workspace."
    },
    {
        "id": 562,
        "Question": "_____ list the variables in the workspace.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rm(x)",
            "b) rm(list=ls())",
            "c) ls()",
            "d) attach(mat)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: rm(x) removes x from the workspace."
    },
    {
        "id": 563,
        "Question": "___________ remove all the variables from the workspace.",
        "Options": [
            "a) rm(x)",
            "b) rm(list=ls())",
            "c) ls()",
            "d) attach(mat)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: attach(mat) make the names of the variables in the matrix or data frame available in the workspace."
    },
    {
        "id": 564,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is normal distribution?",
        "Options": [
            "a) dnorm(x, mean=0, sd=1, log = FALSE)",
            "b) pnorm(q, mean=0, sd=1, lower.tail = TRUE, log.p = FALSE)",
            "c) qnorm(p, mean=0, sd=1, lower.tail = TRUE, log.p = FALSE)",
            "d) rnorm(n, mean=0, sd=1)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: new <- old[-n,] drops the nth row."
    },
    {
        "id": 565,
        "Question": "which of the following statement gives cumulative sum?",
        "Options": [
            "a) cumsum(x,na=rm=TRUE)",
            "b) cumprod(x)",
            "c) cummax(x)",
            "d) cummin(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: new <- subset(old,logical) select those cases that meet the logical condition."
    },
    {
        "id": 566,
        "Question": "Which of the following is uniform distribution?",
        "Options": [
            "a) dunif(x, min=0, max=1, log = FALSE)",
            "b) punif(q, min=0, max=1, lower.tail = TRUE, log.p = FALSE)",
            "c) qunif(p, min=0, max=1, lower.tail = TRUE, log.p = FALSE)",
            "d) runif(n, min=0, max=1)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: new <- old[n1:n2,n3:n4] select the n1 through n2 rows of variables n3 through n4."
    },
    {
        "id": 567,
        "Question": "Which of the following truncates real x to integers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) as.order(x)",
            "b) as.integer(x)",
            "c) as.numeric(x)",
            "d) as.character(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: d stands for density."
    },
    {
        "id": 568,
        "Question": "Which of the following tests each element of x for membership in y?",
        "Options": [
            "a) y%in%x",
            "b) all(x)",
            "c) any(x)",
            "d) x%in%y"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: cummax() function returns the cumulative maxima."
    },
    {
        "id": 569,
        "Question": "Which of the following finds the maximum value in the vector x, exclude missing values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rm(x)",
            "b) max(x, na.rm=TRUE)",
            "c) all(x)",
            "d) x%in%y"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: These functions provide information about the uniform distribution on the interval from min to max."
    },
    {
        "id": 570,
        "Question": "Which of the following produces the variance covariance matrix?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sd(x, na.rm=TRUE)",
            "b) mad(x, na.rm=TRUE)",
            "c) fivenum(x, na.rm=TRUE)",
            "d) var(x, na.rm=TRUE)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: as.integer for object of class truncates decimal part of image values and then converts to type integer."
    },
    {
        "id": 571,
        "Question": "Which of the following will reverse the order of values in x?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rev(x)",
            "b) max(x, na.rm=TRUE)",
            "c) all(x)",
            "d) x%in%y"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: rev provides a reversed version of its argument."
    },
    {
        "id": 572,
        "Question": "Which of the following finds row sums for each level of a grouping variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rowSums (x, na.rm = FALSE, dims = 1)",
            "b) colMeans(x, na.rm = FALSE, dims = 1)",
            "c) rowMeans(x, na.rm = FALSE, dims = 1)",
            "d) rowsum(x, group, reorder = TRUE, …)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: False value leads to unexpected result."
    },
    {
        "id": 573,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement applies the function (FUN) to either rows (1) or columns (2) on object X?",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply(x,1,min)",
            "b) apply(x,2,max)",
            "c) col.max(x)",
            "d) apply(X, MARGIN, FUN, …)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: apply(x,2,max) finds the maximum for each column."
    },
    {
        "id": 574,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement finds the maximum for each column?",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply(x,2,max)",
            "b) col.max(x)",
            "c) which.min(x)",
            "d) which.max(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: col.max(x) is another way to find which column has the maximum value for each row."
    },
    {
        "id": 575,
        "Question": "which of the following statement tells the row with the minimum value for every column?",
        "Options": [
            "a) which.min(x)",
            "b) which.max(x)",
            "c) z=apply(x,1,which.min)",
            "d) z=apply(1,1,which.max)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: which() function gives the TRUE indices of a logical object, allowing for array indices."
    },
    {
        "id": 576,
        "Question": "Which of the following may be used for linear regression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) X %*% Y",
            "b) solve(A)",
            "c) solve(A,B)",
            "d) X $*$ Y"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: solve(A,B) implies inverse of A * B."
    },
    {
        "id": 577,
        "Question": "Which of the following finds row sums for each level of a grouping variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) as.numeric(x)",
            "b) rowsum(x, group, reorder = TRUE, …)",
            "c) as.order(x)",
            "d) colSums (x, na.rm = FALSE, dims = 1)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: rowsum compute column sums across rows of a numeric matrix-like object for each level of a grouping variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 578,
        "Question": "Which of the following sets the size of the outer margins for the graph?",
        "Options": [
            "a) par(mfrow=c(nrow,mcol))",
            "b) par(ask=TRUE)",
            "c) par(omi=c(0,0,1,0) )",
            "d) par(ask=False)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: par can be used to set or query graphical parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 579,
        "Question": "Which of the following function is used for plotting histogram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) hist()",
            "b) histog()",
            "c) histg()",
            "d) histo()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The generic function hist computes a histogram of the given data values."
    },
    {
        "id": 580,
        "Question": "Which of the following will add the title “R language” to the graph?",
        "Options": [
            "a) titleAdd( “R language”)",
            "b) title( “R language”)",
            "c) titleBar( “R language”)",
            "d) var(x, na.rm=TRUE)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This function can be used to add labels to a plot."
    },
    {
        "id": 581,
        "Question": "______  let’s you perform SQL queries on your R data frames.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sqldf",
            "b) plyr",
            "c) forecast",
            "d) daply"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sqldf uses SQLite syntax. Plyr will split-apply-combine paradigm for R. Forecast is a generic function for forecasting from time series or time series models. The function invokes particular methods which depend on the class of the first argument."
    },
    {
        "id": 582,
        "Question": "______ splits a data frame and results an array (hence the da). Hopefully you’re getting the idea here.",
        "Options": [
            "a) apply",
            "b) daply",
            "c) stats",
            "d) plyr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ddply splits a data frame and returns a data frame."
    },
    {
        "id": 583,
        "Question": "________ makes it incredibly easy to fit time series models like ARIMA, ARMA, AR, Exponential Smoothing, etc.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sqldf",
            "b) plyr",
            "c) forecast",
            "d) stats"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Most important feature is the resulting forecast plot."
    },
    {
        "id": 584,
        "Question": "________ provides needed string operators in R.",
        "Options": [
            "a) str",
            "b) forecast",
            "c) stringr",
            "d) sqldf"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: stringr is remarkably easy to use."
    },
    {
        "id": 585,
        "Question": "Which of the following syntax is used to install forecast package?",
        "Options": [
            "a) install.pack(“forecast”)",
            "b) install.packages(“cast”)",
            "c) install.packages(“forecast”)",
            "d) install.pack(“forecastcast”)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: forecast is used for time series analysis."
    },
    {
        "id": 586,
        "Question": "Which of the following is similar to Moment.js?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stringr",
            "b) lubridate",
            "c) ploy",
            "d) forecast"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: lubridate is one of those magical libraries that just seems to do exactly what you expect it to."
    },
    {
        "id": 587,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a library for statistical quality control?",
        "Options": [
            "a) gcc",
            "b) qcc",
            "c) anc",
            "d) pnc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: qcc can help you monitor transaction volumes, visitors or logins on your website, database operations, and lots of other processes."
    },
    {
        "id": 588,
        "Question": "______ specializes in converting data from wide to long format.",
        "Options": [
            "a) gcc",
            "b) reshape",
            "c) reshape2",
            "d) gcc2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: reshape2 is used in conjunction with ggplot2 and plyr."
    },
    {
        "id": 589,
        "Question": "_________ is used to convert wide data to long data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) melt",
            "b) dcast",
            "c) cast",
            "d) rcast"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: dcast is used to go from long to wide."
    },
    {
        "id": 590,
        "Question": "______  is used to view all packages installed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) library()",
            "b) search()",
            "c) .libPaths()",
            "d) stringr()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Both require() and library() can load (strictly speaking, attach) an R package."
    },
    {
        "id": 591,
        "Question": "______ is used to get library location in R.",
        "Options": [
            "a) library()",
            "b) search()",
            "c) .libPaths()",
            "d) stringr()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: libPaths() can add new paths to set of library trees searched."
    },
    {
        "id": 592,
        "Question": "________ is used to view packages currently loaded.",
        "Options": [
            "a) library()",
            "b) search()",
            "c) .libPaths()",
            "d) stringr()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This search will allow you to search the contents of the R functions, package vignettes, and task views."
    },
    {
        "id": 593,
        "Question": "________ contains tools for Approximate Bayesian Computation (ABC).",
        "Options": [
            "a) str",
            "b) abc",
            "c) zyz",
            "d) yxq"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The package implements several ABC algorithms for performing parameter estimation and model selection."
    },
    {
        "id": 594,
        "Question": "Which of the following package combine multi-dimensional arrays?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stringr",
            "b) comb",
            "c) abind",
            "d) anlyz"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This is a generalization of cbind and rbind."
    },
    {
        "id": 595,
        "Question": "Which of the following contains functions for processing uniaxial minute-to-minute accelerometer data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) accelerometry",
            "b) abc",
            "c) accrued",
            "d) comb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This package contains a collection of functions that perform operations on time-series accelerometer data, such as identify non-wear time, flag minutes that are part of an activity about, and find the maximum 10-minute average count value."
    },
    {
        "id": 596,
        "Question": "__________ is used for selecting regression transformations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) gac()",
            "b) gpl()",
            "c) avas()",
            "d) ggc()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ace() and avas() both are used for selecting regression transformations."
    },
    {
        "id": 597,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an R package for the exploratory analysis of genetic and genomic data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) adeg",
            "b) adegenet",
            "c) anc",
            "d) abc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This package contains Classes and functions for genetic data analysis within the multivariate framework."
    },
    {
        "id": 598,
        "Question": "______ specializes in functions for analytical Customer Relationship Management.",
        "Options": [
            "a) adagio",
            "b) ada",
            "c) aCRM",
            "d) adeg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Convenience functions for data preparation and modeling are often used in aCRM."
    },
    {
        "id": 599,
        "Question": "10._________ searches for significant clusters in genetic data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) BayesCount",
            "b) BayesComm",
            "c) bayesclust",
            "d) Bayescolcount"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Bayesclust is an R package for testing and searching for significant clusters. BayesCount is used for power calculations and Bayesian analysis of count distributions and FECRT data using MCMC."
    },
    {
        "id": 600,
        "Question": "______  Uses Grieg-Smith method on 2 dimensional spatial data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) G.S.",
            "b) g.data",
            "c) G1DBN",
            "d) G2db"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function returns a GriegSmith object which is a matrix with block sizes, sum of squares for each block size as well as mean sums of squares. G1DBN is a package performing Dynamic Bayesian Network Inference."
    },
    {
        "id": 601,
        "Question": "______ finds K best paths in a given graph.",
        "Options": [
            "a) kBestShortestPaths",
            "b) kcirt",
            "c) ktrees",
            "d) kmap"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This package provides some routines to conduct the K-adaptive partitioning (kaps) and recursive partitioning (lrtree) for survival data."
    },
    {
        "id": 602,
        "Question": "________ is a package for parsing, applying, and manipulating data cleaning rules",
        "Options": [
            "a) edr",
            "b) editrules",
            "c) edrGraphicalTools",
            "d) edrtools"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: editrules is a package for parsing, applying, and manipulating data cleaning rules. edrGraphicalTools provides tools for dimension reduction methods."
    },
    {
        "id": 603,
        "Question": "________ performs class prediction based on microarray data and clinical parameters",
        "Options": [
            "a) M3",
            "b) M2",
            "c) MAclinical",
            "d) M5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: M3 is used for reading M3 files."
    },
    {
        "id": 604,
        "Question": "Which of the following package provide namespace management functions not yet present in base R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stringr",
            "b) namespace",
            "c) nbpMatching",
            "d) messagewarning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The package namespace is one of the most confusing parts of building a package. nbpMatching contains functions for non-bipartite optimal matching."
    },
    {
        "id": 605,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to analyze paleontological time-series?",
        "Options": [
            "a) accelerometry",
            "b) parfossil",
            "c) paleoTS",
            "d) nbpMatching"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This package contains parfossil parallelized functions for palaeoecological and palaeogeographical analysis."
    },
    {
        "id": 606,
        "Question": "__________ is used for the analysis of air pollution data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) air",
            "b) openair",
            "c) opena",
            "d) openara"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Data are typically hourly time series and both monitoring data and dispersion model output can be analysed."
    },
    {
        "id": 607,
        "Question": "Which of the following package contains functions for reading and displaying satellite data for oceanographic applications with R?",
        "Options": [
            "a) saves",
            "b) satin",
            "c) saws",
            "d) termstrc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Saves is used for faster loading of variables."
    },
    {
        "id": 608,
        "Question": "______ is used for Visualisation, verification and calibration of ternary probabilistic forecasts.",
        "Options": [
            "a) toss",
            "b) termstrc",
            "c) ternvis",
            "d) satin"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: TESS is used for faster simulation of reconstructed phylogenetic trees under time-dependent birth-death processes."
    },
    {
        "id": 609,
        "Question": "_________ uniforms and customizes plots of packages ggplot2, graphics and lattice.",
        "Options": [
            "a) uniCox",
            "b) uniPlot",
            "c) unknownR",
            "d) unigraph"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: uniPlot() allows to change parameters of the packages graphics, lattice and ggplot2 and to make these changes persistent over one R session."
    },
    {
        "id": 610,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following R code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"rsplus\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw8\">install.<span class=\"me1\">packages</span></span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"devtools\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"roxygen2\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Develops the tools",
            "b) Exits R studio",
            "c) Installs the given packages",
            "d) Nothing happens"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Make sure you have the latest version of R and then run the above code to get the packages you’ll need. It installs the given packages. Confirm that you have a recent version of RStudio."
    },
    {
        "id": 611,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the formal requirement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Package",
            "b) Function",
            "c) Letters",
            "d) Interfaces"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: There are three formal requirements: the name can only consist of letters, numbers and periods, i.e., it must start with the letter and it should not end with a period."
    },
    {
        "id": 612,
        "Question": "To start with the new package in RStudio, double-click the pkgname.Rproj file that _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Delete()",
            "b) Create()",
            "c) Run()",
            "d) Exit()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To get started with your new package in RStudio, double-click the pkgname.Rproj file that create() just made. This will open a new RStudio project for your package. Projects are the way to develop packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 613,
        "Question": "If you have an existing package that doesn’t have an .Rproj file, you can use devtools for the use_rstudio(“_____/to/package”) to add it.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Path",
            "b) Package",
            "c) Function",
            "d) Class"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If you have an existing package that doesn’t have an .Rproj file, you can use devtools for the use_rstudio(“path/to/package”) to add it."
    },
    {
        "id": 614,
        "Question": "An .Rproj file is a ____ file.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pdf",
            "b) Jpeg",
            "c) Text",
            "d) Png"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: An .Rproj file is a text file. If you don’t use RStudio, you can get many of the benefits by starting a new R session and ensuring that the directory is set to the package directory."
    },
    {
        "id": 615,
        "Question": "A bundled package is a package that’s been compressed into a ______ file.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Double",
            "b) Triple",
            "c) Single",
            "d) No file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A bundled package is a package that’s been compressed into a single file. A source package is just a directory with components like R/, DESCRIPTION, and so on."
    },
    {
        "id": 616,
        "Question": "________ are built in R so that you get HTML.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vignettes",
            "b) Vighnaants",
            "c) Bignats",
            "d) Viddnets"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Vignettes are built for getting the HTML and PDF output instead of Markdown or LaTeX input. A bundled package is a package that’s been compressed into a single file."
    },
    {
        "id": 617,
        "Question": "Which of the following package has temporary files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Single",
            "b) Source",
            "c) Bundle",
            "d) Double"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Source package might contain temporary files used to save time during development and the compilation artifacts in a source. These will be never found in a bundle."
    },
    {
        "id": 618,
        "Question": "files listed in the Rbuildignore are not included in the ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) single",
            "b) source",
            "c) bundle",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Files listed in the Rbuildignore were not included in the bundle. .Rbuildignore prevents files from the src package and appearing in the bundled package. It allows you to have some extra directories in your source package that will not be included in the package bundle."
    },
    {
        "id": 619,
        "Question": ".Rbuildignore prevents files in the ___________  package from appearing in the bundled package.",
        "Options": [
            "a) single",
            "b) source",
            "c) bundle",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: .Rbuildignore prevents files from the source package and appearing in the bundled package. It allows to have some extra directories in your source package that will not be included in the package bundle."
    },
    {
        "id": 620,
        "Question": "_______ is not useful when developing a package since you have to install the package first.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Function",
            "b) Library",
            "c) Interface",
            "d) Class"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: library() is not useful when developing a package since you have to install the package first. A library is a simple directory containing installed packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 621,
        "Question": "Which function is used for seeing currently active libraries?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Curlib()",
            "b) Currlib()",
            "c) .libpaths()",
            "d) Pathlibr()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A library is simply a directory containing installed packages. Everyone can use the dot libPaths() for seeing which libraries are currently active."
    },
    {
        "id": 622,
        "Question": "Which function is used for loading packages?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Library",
            "b) Interface",
            "c) Loader",
            "d) Linker"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: library() function is used to load a package. library() is not useful when we are developing a package since you have to install the package first. A library is a simple directory containing installed packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 623,
        "Question": "The job of the __________ file is to store important metadata about your package.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Description",
            "b) Interface",
            "c) Thinker",
            "d) Loader"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The job of the DESCRIPTION file is to store the metadata about your package. When you first start writing packages, you’ll mostly use these metadata to record what packages are needed to run your package."
    },
    {
        "id": 624,
        "Question": "DCF is an abbreviation for__________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Debian control function",
            "b) Differentiative common function",
            "c) Debian control format",
            "d) Debian common format"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: DESCRIPTION uses a very simple file format called DCF, the Debian control format. When you first start writing packages, you’ll mostly use these metadata to record what packages are needed to run your package."
    },
    {
        "id": 625,
        "Question": "Which of the following is most important when releasing the package?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Versioning",
            "b) Developing",
            "c) Redundancy",
            "d) Functioning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Versioning is most important when you release your package. Usually, people don’t have exactly the same versions of packages installed that you do."
    },
    {
        "id": 626,
        "Question": "Which of the following is called a one-line description of the package?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Function",
            "b) Title",
            "c) Interface",
            "d) Class"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Title is a one-line description of the package, and is often also shown in package listing. It should be plain text, capitalised like a title, and NOT end in a period."
    },
    {
        "id": 627,
        "Question": "To release a package to _____ you must pick a standard license.",
        "Options": [
            "a) R",
            "b) CRAN",
            "c) CRON",
            "d) Studio"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To release your package to CRAN, you must pick a standard license. Otherwise, it’s difficult for CRAN to determine whether or not it’s legal to distribute your package."
    },
    {
        "id": 628,
        "Question": "_____ package version is the sequence of atleast two integers separated by either. or -.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Java",
            "b) C",
            "c) R",
            "d) Python"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: R package version is the sequence of atleast two integers separated by either. or -. When you first start writing packages, you’ll mostly use these metadata to record what packages are needed to run your package."
    },
    {
        "id": 629,
        "Question": "The ________ number of your package increases with subsequent releases of a package.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Function",
            "b) Studio",
            "c) Version",
            "d) Sequence"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The version number of your package increases with subsequent releases of a package, but it’s more than just an incrementing the counter of the way the number changes with each release can convey information."
    },
    {
        "id": 630,
        "Question": "Which of the following is one of the most important aspects of a good package?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Title",
            "b) Description",
            "c) Documentation",
            "d) Libraries"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Documentation is one of the most important aspects of a good package. Without it, users won’t know how to use your package. Documentation is very much useful for the future."
    },
    {
        "id": 631,
        "Question": "___________ are the most commonly documented object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Interface",
            "b) Class",
            "c) Functions",
            "d) Libraries"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Function is very most commonly documented object. The introduction block, most functions have three tags namely @param, @examples and @return."
    },
    {
        "id": 632,
        "Question": "Which of the following method make vector of repeated values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rep()",
            "b) data()",
            "c) view()",
            "d) read()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: data() load (often into a data.frame) built-in dataset."
    },
    {
        "id": 633,
        "Question": "Which of the following finds the position of a quantile in a dataset?",
        "Options": [
            "a) quantile()",
            "b) barplot()",
            "c) barchart()",
            "d) rep()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: barplot() produces a bar graph."
    },
    {
        "id": 634,
        "Question": "Which of the following function cross-tabulate tables using formulas?",
        "Options": [
            "a) table",
            "b) stem",
            "c) xtabs",
            "d) read"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: table() list all values of a variable with frequencies."
    },
    {
        "id": 635,
        "Question": "Which of the following groups find the correlation matrix?",
        "Options": [
            "a) factor.model",
            "b) col.max(x)",
            "c) stem",
            "d) which.max(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: factor.congruence is used to find the factor congruence coefficients."
    },
    {
        "id": 636,
        "Question": "which of the following statement make a mosaic plot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) histogram()",
            "b) mosaicplot()",
            "c) bar()",
            "d) which.max(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: histogram() is lattice command for producing a histogram."
    },
    {
        "id": 637,
        "Question": "Which of the following compute proportions from a contingency table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) par()",
            "b) prop.table()",
            "c) anova()",
            "d) mosaicplot()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: par() is used to  query and edit graphical settings."
    },
    {
        "id": 638,
        "Question": "Which of the following is lattice command for producing a scatterplot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) plot()",
            "b) lm()",
            "c) xyplot()",
            "d) anova()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: plot() produces a scatterplot."
    },
    {
        "id": 639,
        "Question": "Which of the following builds empirical cumulative distribution function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ecdf()",
            "b) cum",
            "c) cumsum",
            "d) lm()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: cumsum() is used to produce running total of values for input vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 640,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to view dataset in a spreadsheet-type format ?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Disp()",
            "b) View()",
            "c) Seq()",
            "d) lm()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: seq() make arithmetic progression vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 641,
        "Question": "________ function carries out a chi-square test.",
        "Options": [
            "a) chisq.test()",
            "b) t.test()",
            "c) prop.test()",
            "d) fisher.test()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: prop.test() is used to inference for 1 proportion using normal approx."
    },
    {
        "id": 642,
        "Question": "Which of the following adds marginal sums to an existing table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) par()",
            "b) prop.table()",
            "c) addmargins()",
            "d) quantile()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: prop.table() computes proportions from a contingency table."
    },
    {
        "id": 643,
        "Question": "Which of the following lists names of variables in a data.frame?",
        "Options": [
            "a) quantile()",
            "b) names()",
            "c) barchart()",
            "d) par()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: names function is used to associate name with the value in the vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 644,
        "Question": "Which of the following is tool for chi-square distributions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) pchisq()",
            "b) chisq()",
            "c) pnorm",
            "d) barchart()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: pnorm() is tool for normal distributions."
    },
    {
        "id": 645,
        "Question": "Which of the following groups values of a variable into larger bins?",
        "Options": [
            "a) cut",
            "b) col.max(x)",
            "c) stem",
            "d) which.max(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: stem() is used to make a stemplot."
    },
    {
        "id": 646,
        "Question": "Which of the following determine the least-squares regression line?",
        "Options": [
            "a) histo()",
            "b) lm",
            "c) barlm()",
            "d) col.max(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: lm calls the lower level functions lm.fit."
    },
    {
        "id": 647,
        "Question": "Which of the following is tool for checking normality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) qqline()",
            "b) qline()",
            "c) anova()",
            "d) lm()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: qqnorm is another tool for checking normality."
    },
    {
        "id": 648,
        "Question": "Which of the following is lattice command for producing boxplots?",
        "Options": [
            "a) plot()",
            "b) bwplot()",
            "c) xyplot()",
            "d) barlm()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function bwplot() makes box-and-whisker plots for numerical variables."
    },
    {
        "id": 649,
        "Question": "Which of the following compute analysis of variance table for fitted model?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ecdf()",
            "b) cum()",
            "c) anova()",
            "d) bwplot()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ecdf() builds empirical cumulative distribution function."
    },
    {
        "id": 650,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to find variance of all values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) var()",
            "b) sd()",
            "c) mean()",
            "d) anova()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sd() is used to calculate standard deviation."
    },
    {
        "id": 651,
        "Question": "10.The purpose of fisher.test() is _______ test for contingency table.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Chisq",
            "b) Fisher",
            "c) Prop",
            "d) Stem"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: prop.test() is used to inference for 1 proportion using normal approx."
    },
    {
        "id": 652,
        "Question": "Which of the following convert a matrix of phi coefficients to polychoric correlations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) poly()",
            "b) qline()",
            "c) phi2poly",
            "d) multi.plot()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In statistics, polychoric correlation is a technique for estimating the correlation between two theorized normally distributed continuous latent variables, from two observed ordinal variables."
    },
    {
        "id": 653,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to plot multiple histograms?",
        "Options": [
            "a) multi.plot()",
            "b) multi.hist",
            "c) xyplot.multi()",
            "d) poly()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A histogram is a graphical representation of the distribution of numerical data."
    },
    {
        "id": 654,
        "Question": "Which of the following count the number of good cases when doing pairwise analysis?",
        "Options": [
            "a) count.pairwise",
            "b) count() +",
            "c) anova.para()",
            "d) count.poly()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pairwise comparison generally is any process of comparing entities in pairs to judge which of each entity is preferred."
    },
    {
        "id": 655,
        "Question": "Which of the following gives the summary of values likes mean etc?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mean",
            "b) sd",
            "c) describe",
            "d) lm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Describe give means, sd, skew, n, and se."
    },
    {
        "id": 656,
        "Question": "The purpose of correct.cor is to correct _________ in values.",
        "Options": [
            "a) difference",
            "b) reliability",
            "c) error",
            "d) similar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Correlation matrix and a vector of reliabilities is given to correct reliability."
    },
    {
        "id": 657,
        "Question": "What plot(s) are used to view the linear regression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scatterplot",
            "b) Box plot",
            "c) Density plot",
            "d) Scatterplot, Boxplot, Density plot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Each plot has its own importance of highlighting a specific feature. Scatter plot is used to visualise the relationship between the variables, Box plot is used to spot the outliers which effect line of best fit. "
    },
    {
        "id": 658,
        "Question": "In lm(response ~ terms), terms specification of the form “first*second” is same as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) first+second",
            "b) first:second",
            "c) first+second+first:second",
            "d) first:second+second:first"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For choosing linear regression model it is always advised to have more R-squared and lower F-Statistic. It ensures the best fit for the given data."
    },
    {
        "id": 659,
        "Question": "In practice, Line of best fit or regression line is found when _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sum of residuals (∑(Y – h(X))) is minimum",
            "b) Sum of the absolute value of residuals (∑|Y-h(X)|) is maximum",
            "c) Sum of the square of residuals ( ∑ (Y-h(X))2) is minimum",
            "d) Sum of the square of residuals ( ∑ (Y-h(X))2) is maximum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Here we penalize higher error value much more as compared to the smaller one, such that there is a significant difference between making big errors and small errors, which makes it easy to differentiate and select the best fit line."
    },
    {
        "id": 660,
        "Question": "If Linear regression model perfectly first i.e., train error is zero, then _____________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Test error is also always zero",
            "b) Test error is non zero",
            "c) Couldn’t comment on Test error",
            "d) Test error is equal to Train error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Test Error depends on the test data. If the Test data is an exact representation of train data then test error is always zero. But this may not be the case."
    },
    {
        "id": 661,
        "Options": [
            "a) ii and iv",
            "b) i and ii",
            "c) ii, iii and iv",
            "d) i, ii, iii and iv"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: These (R Squared, Adjusted R Squared, F Statistics, RMSE / MSE / MAE) are some metrics which you can use to evaluate your regression model."
    },
    {
        "id": 662,
        "Question": "How many coefficients do you need to estimate in a simple linear regression model (One independent variable)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In simple linear regression, there is one independent variable so 2 coefficients (Y=a+bx+error)."
    },
    {
        "id": 663,
        "Question": "In a simple linear regression model (One independent variable), If we change the input variable by 1 unit. How much output variable will change?",
        "Options": [
            "a) by 1",
            "b) no change",
            "c) by intercept",
            "d) by its slope"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: For linear regression Y=a+bx+error. If neglect error then Y=a+bx. If x increases by 1, then Y = a+b(x+1) which implies Y=a+bx+b. So Y increases by its slope."
    },
    {
        "id": 664,
        "Question": "Function used for linear regression in R is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) lm(formula, data)",
            "b) lr(formula, data)",
            "c) lrm(formula, data)",
            "d) regression.linear(formula, data)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: lm(formula, data) refers to a linear model in which formula is the object of the class “formula”, representing the relation between variables. Now this formula is on applied on the data to create a relationship model."
    },
    {
        "id": 665,
        "Question": "In syntax of linear model lm(formula,data,..), data refers to ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix",
            "b) Vector",
            "c) Array",
            "d) List"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Formula is just a symbol to show the relationship and is applied on data which is a vector. In General, data.frame are used for data."
    },
    {
        "id": 666,
        "Question": "In the mathematical Equation of Linear Regression Y = β1 + β2X + ϵ, (β1, β2) refers to __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) (X-intercept, Slope)",
            "b) (Slope, X-Intercept)",
            "c) (Y-Intercept, Slope)",
            "d) (slope, Y-Intercept)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Y-intercept is β1 and X-intercept is – (β1 / β2). Intercepts are defined for axis and formed when the coordinates are on the axis."
    },
    {
        "id": 667,
        "Question": "________ is an incredibly powerful tool for analyzing data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linear regression",
            "b) Logistic regression",
            "c) Gradient Descent",
            "d) Greedy algorithms"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Linear regression is an incredibly powerful tool for analysing data. we’ll focus on finding one of the simplest type of relationship: linear. This process is unsurprisingly called linear regression, and it has many applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 668,
        "Question": "The square of the correlation coefficient r 2 will always be positive and is called the ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Regression",
            "b) Coefficient of determination",
            "c) KNN",
            "d) Algorithm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The square of the correlation coefficient r square will always be positive and is called the coefficient of determination. This also is equal to the proportion of the total variability that’s explained by a linear model."
    },
    {
        "id": 669,
        "Question": "Predicting y for a value of x that’s outside the range of values we actually saw for x in the original data is called ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Regression",
            "b) Extrapolation",
            "c) Intra polation",
            "d) Polation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Predicting y for a value of x that is within the interval of points that we saw in the original data is called interpolation. Predicting y for a value of x that’s outside the range of values we actually saw for x in the original data is called extrapolation."
    },
    {
        "id": 670,
        "Question": "What is predicting y for a value of x that is within the interval of points that we saw in the original data called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Regression",
            "b) Extrapolation",
            "c) Intra polation",
            "d) Polation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Predicting y for a value of x that is within the interval of points that we saw in the original data is called interpolation. Predicting y for a value of x that’s outside the range of values we actually saw for x in the original data is called extrapolation."
    },
    {
        "id": 671,
        "Question": "Analysis of variance in short form is?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ANOV",
            "b) AVA",
            "c) ANOVA",
            "d) ANVA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the ANOVA test determines that the model explains a significant portion of the variability in the data, then we can consider testing each of the hypotheses and correcting for multiple comparisons."
    },
    {
        "id": 672,
        "Question": "________ is a simple approach to supervised learning. It assumes that the dependence of Y on X1, X2, . . . Xp is linear.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linear regression",
            "b) Logistic regression",
            "c) Gradient Descent",
            "d) Greedy algorithms"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Linear regression is a simple approach to supervised learning. It assumes that the dependence of Y on X1, X2, . . . Xp is linear. linear regression is an incredibly powerful tool for analysing data."
    },
    {
        "id": 673,
        "Question": "Although it may seem overly simplistic, _______ is extremely useful both conceptually and practically.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linear regression",
            "b) Logistic regression",
            "c) Gradient Descent",
            "d) Greedy algorithms"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Linear regression is a simple approach to supervised learning. It assumes that the dependence of Y on X1, X2, . . . Xp is linear. linear regression is an incredibly powerful tool for analysing data."
    },
    {
        "id": 674,
        "Question": "When there are more than one independent variables in the model, then the linear model is termed as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Unimodal",
            "b) Multiple model",
            "c) Multiple Linear model",
            "d) Multiple Logistic model"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When there are more than one independent variables in the model, then the linear model is termed as the multiple linear regression model."
    },
    {
        "id": 675,
        "Question": "The parameter β0 is termed as intercept term and the parameter β1 is termed as slope parameter. These parameters are usually called as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Regressionists",
            "b) Coefficients",
            "c) Regressive",
            "d) Regression coefficients"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The parameter β0 is termed as intercept term and the parameter β1 is termed as slope parameter. These parameters are usually called as regression coefficients."
    },
    {
        "id": 676,
        "Question": "The sum of squares of the difference between the observations and the line in the horizontal direction in the scatter diagram can be minimized to obtain the estimates is generally called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) reverse regression method",
            "b) formal regression",
            "c) logistic regression",
            "d) simple regression"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The sum of squares of the difference between the observations and the line in the horizontal direction in the scatter diagram can be minimized to obtain the estimates of 0 1 β and β. This is generally called a reverse or inverse regression method. "
    },
    {
        "id": 677,
        "Question": "______ regression method is also known as the ordinary least squares estimation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple",
            "b) Direct",
            "c) Indirect",
            "d) Mutual"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Direct regression method also known as the ordinary least squares estimation. Assuming that a set of n paired observations are available which satisfy the linear regression model."
    },
    {
        "id": 678,
        "Question": "__________ refers to a group of techniques for fitting and studying the straight-line relationship between two variables.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linear regression",
            "b) Logistic regression",
            "c) Gradient Descent",
            "d) Greedy algorithms"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Linear regression is an incredibly powerful tool for analysing data. we’ll focus on finding one of the simplest type of relationship: linear. This process is unsurprisingly called linear regression, and it has many applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 679,
        "Question": "In order to calculate confidence intervals and hypothesis tests, it is assumed that the errors are independent and normally distributed with mean zero and _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mean",
            "b) Variance",
            "c) SD",
            "d) KNN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In order to calculate confidence intervals and hypothesis tests, it is assumed that the errors are independent and normally distributed with mean zero and variance."
    },
    {
        "id": 680,
        "Question": "What do we do the curvilinear relationship in linear regression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) consider",
            "b) ignore",
            "c) may be considered",
            "d) sometimes consider"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Linear regression models the straight-line relationship between Y and X. Any curvilinear relationship is ignored. This assumption is most easily evaluated by using a scatter plot."
    },
    {
        "id": 681,
        "Question": "When hypothesis tests and confidence limits are to be used, the residuals are assumed to follow the __________distribution.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Formal",
            "b) Mutual",
            "c) Normal",
            "d) Abnormal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When hypothesis tests and confidence limits are to be used, the residuals are assumed to follow the normal distribution."
    },
    {
        "id": 682,
        "Question": "The IBM _________ analytics appliances combine high-capacity storage for Big Data with a massively-parallel processing platform for high-performance computing.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Watson",
            "b) Netezza",
            "c) InfoSight",
            "d) LityxEQ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: IBM Watson is a system based on cognitive computing. With the addition of Revolution R Enterprise for IBM Netezza, you can use the power of the R language to build predictive models on Big Data."
    },
    {
        "id": 683,
        "Question": "______ is an integrated hosted analytics platform for marketing insights, predictive models, and marketing optimization”",
        "Options": [
            "a) LityxEQ",
            "b) WatSon",
            "c) LityxIQ",
            "d) InfoSight"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: LityxIQ allows marketers to automate the loading and managing multiple data sources, automatically build and manage predictive models, and optimize marketing budget and media decisions."
    },
    {
        "id": 684,
        "Question": "________ is rapidly being adopted for computing descriptive and query types of analytics on Big data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) EDR",
            "b) Hadoop",
            "c) Azure",
            "d) InfoSight"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: However, it has a reputation for not being a suitable environment for high performance complex iterative algorithms such as logistic regression, generalized linear models, and decision trees."
    },
    {
        "id": 685,
        "Question": "_________ involves predicting a response with meaningful magnitude, such as quantity sold, stock price, or return on investment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Regression",
            "b) Summarization",
            "c) Clustering",
            "d) Classification"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Regression and classification are two common types predictive models."
    },
    {
        "id": 686,
        "Question": "Which of the following involves predicting a categorical response?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Regression",
            "b) Summarization",
            "c) Clustering",
            "d) Classification"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Classification techniques are widely used in data mining to classify data."
    },
    {
        "id": 687,
        "Question": "Which of the following contains pre-built predictive tools?",
        "Options": [
            "a) alteryx",
            "b) fossilx",
            "c) paleoTS",
            "d) ssas"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Alteryx Analytics, with deep integration of the R statistics and predictive language, offers a way to bridge these two worlds of ease of use and sophisticated predictive analytics."
    },
    {
        "id": 688,
        "Question": "__________ is proprietary tool for predictive analytics.",
        "Options": [
            "a) R",
            "b) SAS",
            "c) SSAS",
            "d) EDR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SAS (Statistical Analysis System) is a software suite developed by SAS Institute for advanced analytics."
    },
    {
        "id": 689,
        "Question": "Which of the following is preferred for text analytics?",
        "Options": [
            "a) R",
            "b) Python",
            "c) S",
            "d) EDR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: pandas is an open source, BSD-licensed library providing high-performance, easy-to-use data structures and data analysis tools for the Python programming."
    },
    {
        "id": 690,
        "Question": "______ is simplest class of analytics.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Descriptive",
            "b) Predictive",
            "c) Prescriptive",
            "d) Summarization"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Descriptive is the simplest class of analytics. Predictive analytics can only forecast what might happen in the future because all predictive analytics are probabilistic in nature."
    },
    {
        "id": 691,
        "Question": "10._________  is a JavaScript charting library and feature-rich API set that lets you build interactive Flash or HTML5 charts.",
        "Options": [
            "a) InstantAtlas",
            "b) Alterian",
            "c) ZingChart",
            "d) paleoTS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ZingChart lets you create HTML5 Canvas charts and more."
    },
    {
        "id": 692,
        "Question": "The _______ and ________ of a discrete random variable is easy to compute at the console.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mean, Variance",
            "b) Variance, Packages",
            "c) Packages, Functions",
            "d) Median, Mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The mean and variance of a discrete random variable are easy to compute at the console. To calculate the mean µ, we need to multiply the corresponding values of x and f and add them."
    },
    {
        "id": 693,
        "Question": "Which of the following simple the square root of σ square?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Variance",
            "b) Standard deviation",
            "c) Mean",
            "d) Median"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Standard deviation is the measure of dispersion of a set of data from its mean. The standard deviation σ is simply the square root of σ square."
    },
    {
        "id": 694,
        "Question": "The abbreviation of Cumulative Distributive Function is ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CDFN",
            "b) CMDF",
            "c) CMD",
            "d) CDF"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A cumulative distributive function P(x) is the probability of getting some value less than a certain value x. If p(x) will be the density function for a probability distribution, then that will be the cumulative distributive function P(x) is calculated as the integral of p(x) over the interval −∞ to x."
    },
    {
        "id": 695,
        "Question": "Which function is used to simulate discrete uniform random variables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sample",
            "b) Simple",
            "c) Function",
            "d) Variance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One can choose an integer at random with the sample function. The general syntax of the simulation of the discrete uniform random variable is a sample (x, size, replace = TRUE)."
    },
    {
        "id": 696,
        "Question": "The binomial distribution is based on _______ trial.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Einstein",
            "b) Bernoulli",
            "c) Bohr",
            "d) Kepler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The binomial distribution is the distribution based on the Bernoulli trial, which is a random experiment in which there are only two possible outcomes: success (S) and failure (F)."
    },
    {
        "id": 697,
        "Question": "The corresponding R function for the PMF is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trinom",
            "b) Dbinorm",
            "c) Dbinom",
            "d) Fnorm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: dnorm is the height of the density of a normal curve while dbinom returns the probability of an outcome of a binomial distribution."
    },
    {
        "id": 698,
        "Question": "The corresponding R function for the CDF is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dbinom",
            "b) Pbinom",
            "c) Cbinorm",
            "d) Hbinorm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function pbinom is very useful for summing consecutive binomial probabilities. The pbinom function returns the probability that the value of a variable that follows the binomial distribution."
    },
    {
        "id": 699,
        "Question": "Random variables defined via the _______ package.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Distri",
            "b) Diestr",
            "c) Distr",
            "d) Diftr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Random variables defined via the distr package may be plotted, which will return graphs of the PMF, CDF, and quantile function."
    },
    {
        "id": 700,
        "Question": "MGF means _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Moment Generating Formulas",
            "b) Movement Generating Formulas",
            "c) Moment Generating Functions",
            "d) Moment Graphic Functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The moment generating function, if it exists in a neighbourhood of zero, determines a probability distribution uniquely."
    },
    {
        "id": 701,
        "Question": "The empirical cumulative distribution function can be called as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) EMCDF",
            "b) EDFC",
            "c) ECDF",
            "d) EGDF"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The empirical cumulative distribution function is the probability distribution that places into the probability mass. ECDF refers to the empirical cumulative distribution function."
    },
    {
        "id": 702,
        "Question": "Two important methods in analysis is differentiation and   __________ transformation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bernoulli",
            "b) Fourier",
            "c) Bohr",
            "d) Rutherford"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Two important methods in the analysis is differentiation and Fourier transformation. Unfortunately, not all functions are differentiable or have a Fourier transform."
    },
    {
        "id": 703,
        "Question": "Every ________ function has a probability distribution function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous",
            "b) Discrete",
            "c) Categorical",
            "d) Random"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Every continuous random variable x has a great Probability Density Function (PDF). The PDF can sometimes be greater than 1. This is in contrast to the discrete case."
    },
    {
        "id": 704,
        "Question": "Which package resorts to numerical methods when it encounters a model it does not recognize.",
        "Options": [
            "a) destrEx",
            "b) ditrEx",
            "c) distrEx",
            "d) Exdistr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: distrEx provides some extensions of package distr and further functionalities like var, sd, IQR, mad, median, skewness, kurtosis truncated moments."
    },
    {
        "id": 705,
        "Question": "When µ = ___ and σ = ___ we say that the random variable has a standard normal distribution.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0,1",
            "b) 0,0",
            "c) 1,0",
            "d) 1,1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When µ = 0 and σ = 1 we say that the random variable has a standard normal distribution and we typically write Z ∼ norm(mean = 0, sd = 1)."
    },
    {
        "id": 706,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the symbol of standard normal PDF?",
        "Options": [
            "a) φ",
            "b) #",
            "c) &",
            "d) *"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The lowercase Greek letter phi (φ) is used to denote the standard normal PDF and the capital Greek letter phi Φ is used to denote the standard normal CDF."
    },
    {
        "id": 707,
        "Question": "The __________ package has functionality to investigate transformations of univariate distributions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Distri",
            "b) Dirtr",
            "c) Distr",
            "d) Hyperbolic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The distr package has a functionality to find the transformations of one variable distribution. There are exact results for the ordinary transformations for the standard distributions, and distr takes advantage of these in many cases."
    },
    {
        "id": 708,
        "Question": "Which distribution looks like a norm distribution but with very heavy tails?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple",
            "b) Discrete",
            "c) Continuous",
            "d) Cauchy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Cauchy distribution looks like a norm distribution but with very heavy tails. The mean (and variance) do not exist, that is, they are infinite."
    },
    {
        "id": 709,
        "Question": "The ________ is represented by the location parameter.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Median",
            "b) Mode",
            "c) Mean",
            "d) Variance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The median is represented by the location parameter, and the scale parameter influences the spread of the distribution about its median."
    },
    {
        "id": 710,
        "Question": "The ______ parameter influences the spread of the distribution about its median.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scale",
            "b) Mode",
            "c) Mean",
            "d) Variance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The scale parameter influences the spread of the distribution about its median. The median is represented by the location parameter."
    },
    {
        "id": 711,
        "Question": "Which distribution comes up a lot in Bayesian statistics because it is a good model for one’s prior beliefs about a population proportion?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bohr",
            "b) Discrete",
            "c) Alpha",
            "d) Beta"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Beta distribution comes up a lot in Bayesian statistics because it is a good model for one’s prior beliefs about a population proportion."
    },
    {
        "id": 712,
        "Question": "The associated R function is dlogis (x, location = 0, scale = 1) is for _________ distribution.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Logistic",
            "b) Linear",
            "c) Discrete",
            "d) Beta"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The associated R function is dlogis (x, location = 0, scale = 1). The logistic distribution comes up in differential equations as a model for population growth under certain assumptions."
    },
    {
        "id": 713,
        "Question": "The _________ distribution comes up in differential equations as a model for population growth under certain assumptions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Logistic",
            "b) Linear",
            "c) Discrete",
            "d) Beta"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The associated R function is dlogis(x, location = 0, scale = 1). The logistic distribution comes up in differential equations as a model for population growth under certain assumptions."
    },
    {
        "id": 714,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a distribution derived from the normal distribution?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Logistic",
            "b) Lognormal",
            "c) Normal",
            "d) Simple"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Lognormal distribution is a distribution derived from the normal distribution (hence the name). Its name also says that it is derived from the normal distribution."
    },
    {
        "id": 715,
        "Question": "The associated R function is dlnorm(x, meanlog = 0, sdlog = 1) is for ________ distribution.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Logistic",
            "b) Lognormal",
            "c) Normal",
            "d) Simple"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The associated R function is dlnorm(x, meanlog = 0, sdlog = 1). Lognormal distribution is a distribution derived from the normal distribution (hence the name). Its name also says that it is derived from the normal distribution."
    },
    {
        "id": 716,
        "Question": "The associated R function is dweibull(x, shape, scale = 1) is for _________ distribution.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Logistic",
            "b) Lognormal",
            "c) Weibull",
            "d) Simple"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The associated R function is dweibull(x, shape, scale = 1). There are exact results for ordinary transformations of the standard distributions, and distr takes advantage of these in many cases."
    },
    {
        "id": 717,
        "Question": "Which level plotting commands generate figures?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Low",
            "b) High",
            "c) Both high and low",
            "d) No levels"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: High level plotting commands generate figures. A figure consists of a plot region surrounded by margins."
    },
    {
        "id": 718,
        "Question": "The size of the margins is controlled by the argument _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mai",
            "b) Sai",
            "c) Lai",
            "d) Jai"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The size of the margins is controlled by the argument mai. The value of mai is a vector c(bottom, left, top, right) of length 4 whose values are the widths."
    },
    {
        "id": 719,
        "Question": "______ will be called inside par() to set margins.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mai",
            "b) Smai",
            "c) May",
            "d) Jay"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The value of mai is vector c(bottom, left, top, right) of length 4 whose values are the widths.  Mai will be called inside par() to set margins."
    },
    {
        "id": 720,
        "Question": "Axes, axis labels and titles all appear in the ________ of the figure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Directions",
            "b) Margin labels",
            "c) Margins",
            "d) Widths"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Axes, axis labels and titles all appear in the margins of the figure. Mai will be called inside par() to set margins."
    },
    {
        "id": 721,
        "Question": "Each margin is considered to have a number of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Test",
            "b) Text lines",
            "c) Line segment",
            "d) Margins"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Axes, axis labels and titles all appear in the margins of the figure. Each margin is considered to have a number of text lines (not necessarily a whole number)."
    },
    {
        "id": 722,
        "Question": "Which line numbers are further away from the plot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lower",
            "b) Higher",
            "c) Medium",
            "d) Simple"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Higher line numbers are further away from the plot. Axes, axis labels and titles all appear in the margins of the figure."
    },
    {
        "id": 723,
        "Question": "The graphical parameter __________ defines how many lines appear in each of the four margins.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Par",
            "b) Mar",
            "c) Char",
            "d) Ian"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The graphical parameter mar defines how many lines appear in each of the four margins. So mar is an alternative way of defining margins."
    },
    {
        "id": 724,
        "Question": "Which is the alternative way of defining margins?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mar",
            "b) Par",
            "c) Char",
            "d) Nar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The graphical parameter mar defines how many lines appear in each of the four margins. So mar is an alternative way of defining margins."
    },
    {
        "id": 725,
        "Question": "The standard font determines the width of the text lines in the __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Function",
            "b) Package",
            "c) Library",
            "d) Margin"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: For any open graphics device there is a standard font which will be used for any characters if no other font is specified (font). The standard font determines the width of the text lines in the margins."
    },
    {
        "id": 726,
        "Question": "Which function draws an axis on the current plot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) axis()",
            "b) par()",
            "c) mar()",
            "d) jar()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The axis() function draws an axis on the current plot. The side argument determines on which side it is to appear."
    },
    {
        "id": 727,
        "Question": "______ gives the length and height of the current figure in inches.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Din",
            "b) Fin",
            "c) Sin",
            "d) Cin"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R has a variety of graphics functions. Each function has its own set of arguments. Fin gives the length and height of the current figure in inches."
    },
    {
        "id": 728,
        "Question": "__________ read only parameter that returns the width and height of the current device surface in inches.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Din",
            "b) Fin",
            "c) Gin",
            "d) Kin"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: R has a variety of graphics functions. Din will read only parameter that returns the length and height of the current device surface in inches."
    },
    {
        "id": 729,
        "Question": "ask=T is a parameter that R asks before producing the _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) function",
            "b) package",
            "c) interface",
            "d) graphics"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Each function has its own set of arguments. ask=T in R language asks before producing the graphic. This is useful if you need to view multiple plots, one at a time."
    },
    {
        "id": 730,
        "Question": "Which of the following declares the current plot undeclared?",
        "Options": [
            "a) New = H",
            "b) New = T",
            "c) New = J",
            "d) New = L"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: New=T will declare the current plot is unused (even if it is not). This means that R will not erase it before moving in through the next plot. "
    },
    {
        "id": 731,
        "Question": "Which of the following will be used in fancy plots?",
        "Options": [
            "a) New = T",
            "b) New = J",
            "c) New = K",
            "d) New = L"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: New=T will declare the current plot is unused (even if it is not). This is useful for more fancy plots, where you may be producing a number of plots on the one figure."
    },
    {
        "id": 732,
        "Question": "________ level plotting functions that start a new plot.",
        "Options": [
            "a) High",
            "b) Low",
            "c) Medium",
            "d) Simple"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: R has a variety of graphics functions. High-level plotting functions will start a new plot. Low-level plotting functions that add elements to an existing plot."
    },
    {
        "id": 733,
        "Question": "________ level plotting functions that add elements to an existing plot.",
        "Options": [
            "a) High",
            "b) Low",
            "c) Medium",
            "d) Simple"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R has many varieties of graphics functions. High-level plotting functions will start a new plot. Low-level plotting functions that add elements to an existing plot."
    },
    {
        "id": 734,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the plotting character?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sch",
            "b) Pch",
            "c) Grd",
            "d) Pck"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: R has a variety of graphics functions. Each function has its own set of arguments. Pch gives the plotting character of the graph."
    },
    {
        "id": 735,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the colour argument?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Col",
            "b) Dol",
            "c) Cul",
            "d) Acol"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Col is the colouring argument in R and R has a variety of graphics functions. Each function has its own set of arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 736,
        "Question": "________ is used for main title in graph.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Title",
            "b) Main",
            "c) Title Main",
            "d) Main Title"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Main is used for the main title in the graphics.R has a variety of graphics functions. Each function has its own set of arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 737,
        "Question": "_________ are mostly used for statistical analysis.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nervous",
            "b) Neural Networks",
            "c) Blood Pressure",
            "d) Diabetes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Neural networks are used for statistical analysis and data modelling, in which their role is perceived as an alternative to standard nonlinear regression or cluster analysis techniques."
    },
    {
        "id": 738,
        "Question": "In which year Haykin gave a comprehensive survey of neural network techniques from an engineering perspective?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1995",
            "b) 1996",
            "c) 1966",
            "d) 1994"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Haykin (1994) gives a comprehensive survey of many neural network techniques from an engineering perspective."
    },
    {
        "id": 739,
        "Question": "Artificial neural networks may be thought of as simplified models of the networks of neurons that occur naturally in the ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Animal brain",
            "b) Human brain",
            "c) Bird brain",
            "d) Monkey brain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Artificial neural networks may be thought as the simplified logical models of the networks of neurons that occur in the animal brain."
    },
    {
        "id": 740,
        "Question": "The simplest artificial neuron is the _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) TGU",
            "b) THU",
            "c) JUH",
            "d) TLU"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The simplest artificial neuron is the threshold logic unit or TLU. The TLU is supposed to model the basic “integrate-and-fire” mechanism of real neurons."
    },
    {
        "id": 741,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the short form of Threshold logical unit?",
        "Options": [
            "a) THL",
            "b) THU",
            "c) TLU",
            "d) TLO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The simplest artificial neuron is the threshold logic unit or TLU. Its basic operation is to perform a weighted sum of its inputs and then output a “1” if this sum exceeds a threshold, and a “0” otherwise."
    },
    {
        "id": 742,
        "Question": "The building blocks of artificial neural networks are artificial _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Blocks",
            "b) Neurons",
            "c) Functions",
            "d) Packages"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The building blocks of artificial neural nets are artificial neurons. Artificial neural networks may be thought of as simplified models of the networks of neurons that occur naturally in the animal brain."
    },
    {
        "id": 743,
        "Question": "The membrane potential of the neuron has a negative resting or equilibrium value is called ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hyperpolarization",
            "b) polarization",
            "c) Hypolarization",
            "d) Hypopolarization"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The membrane potential of the neuron has a negative resting or equilibrium value. Making this more negative leads to a hyperpolarization which are trying to depolarize the membrane."
    },
    {
        "id": 744,
        "Question": "_________ are commonly introduced as representations of quantities that have magnitude and direction.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lists",
            "b) Data sets",
            "c) Data frames",
            "d) Vectors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Vectors are commonly introduced as representations of quantities that have magnitude and direction."
    },
    {
        "id": 745,
        "Question": "_______ is discovering unseen patterns from data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data Milling",
            "b) Data Mining",
            "c) Niching",
            "d) Machine learning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Data mining is the aim of discovering unseen patterns from data. Neural Networks are known to be universal function approximators."
    },
    {
        "id": 746,
        "Question": "The method that the optimized weight values are attained is called as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Leaning",
            "b) Lost",
            "c) Catching",
            "d) Learning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The method by which the optimized weight values are attained is called learning. Artificial neural networks work through optimized weight values.\n"
    }
]